<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://openbazaar.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://openbazaar.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-17T20:27:57+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">OpenBazaar</title><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar Developer Call - September 13, 2018</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-September-30-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar Developer Call - September 13, 2018" /><published>2018-09-14T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-14T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-September-30-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-September-30-2018/">&lt;p&gt;This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on September 13, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to join the call in real time? Sign up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/developers&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our ongoing conversations on Slack at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse OpenBazaar now at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lt_3RdS30uk&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chat log:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:57] Sameep: how many mikes are there??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:58] mg (OB1): Not enough!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:04] chris.troutner: The mobile app has not been release yet, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:05] mg (OB1): No it hasn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:07] chris.troutner: Who has been leading the charge on understanding the code that makes up an Insight server? I’d like to pick their brain offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:12] chris.troutner: That’s exciting. Thanks for the clarification, Josh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:15] Moonshot: Did you consider having a server work for multiple users? Something that would allow the full server functionality to read the user data stored locally. Is that what the relay node is meant to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:16] Moonshot: Ok thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:20] chris.troutner: @mg please keep me in the loop with that Insight testing stuff. Bitcoin.com might be able to help pool resources with OB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:21] mg (OB1): I’m not sure what pooled resources you had in mind, but we’re open to any ideas you had on that. I imagine the blog post that gets produced will have a lot of details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:24] Rod: Speaking of Bitcoin Cash, what are some of the main barriers to getting the multi-currency support setup right now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:26] mg (OB1): Do you mean multiple currencies simultaneously?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:27] Rod: I am talking about being able to accept multiple currencies through an individual listing right now instead of setting up separate listings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:29] chris.troutner: Do you guys know if there will be any blowback from Shapeshifts recent announcement about accounts? Will it impact the ability to pay using Shapeshift in OB?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:31] Moonshot: Does that mean the wallets for each coin need to be trusted, since you are not going to be running SPV for each one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:34] Moonshot: If performance is the obstacle to SPV, did you consider running SPV for all coins and limiting the # of wallets a user can run simultaneously?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:35] chris.troutner: Running for SPV for all coins is not an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:38] chris.troutner: Thanks for the clarification, Sam. I hadn’t really used it. Was just curious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:39] art: Any news on Monero integration?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:41] art: Cool, thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:41] art: If one wanted to use OB for services, is there a tutorial?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:42] chris.troutner: Tutorials:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:43] art: Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:44] chris.troutner: Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:44] roka: thanks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11:44] Jenn_OB1: Thanks everyone!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on September 13, 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Decentralized Application Development Nearly Destroyed My World</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-decentralized-application-development-nearly-destroyed-my-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Decentralized Application Development&lt;/span&gt; Nearly &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Destroyed My World&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-09-13T11:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-13T11:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-decentralized-application-development-nearly-destroyed-my-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-decentralized-application-development-nearly-destroyed-my-world/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Rob Misiorowski, OpenBazaar Front End Developer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, that title is a little hyperbolic, but decentralized applications with modern user experiences are few and far between and present some unique challenges for front-end developers. In this post I’ll describe some of these challenges and give examples of how we addressed them when developing the OpenBazaar desktop client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fundamentally-different-paradigms&quot;&gt;Fundamentally Different Paradigms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In a &lt;strong&gt;centralized application&lt;/strong&gt;, the data is primarily stored in and retrieved from one central source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, an app has 10,000 thing-a-magoos and they are all stored on a central server that’s administered by professional engineers and has professional quality hardware and software behind it. It’s optimized to process large numbers of client requests for data in a highly streamlined way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is useful when you need to retrieve and organize many pieces of data, like on a webpage that displays the top 50 thing-a-magoos on the network. With a centralized server, a client can efficiently retrieve the data it needs for all 50 thing-a-magoos in one single call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now, let’s consider a similar app, but one that is &lt;strong&gt;decentralized&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data doesn’t live in one central location. Each user stores their own data and distributes it to other peers on the network as those peers view the data. Instead of highly optimized hardware, this is a blend of computers ranging from Joe’s 8 year old desktop PC to Jennie’s brand new macbook pro. While some of these may be high end, it’s doubtful that most of these users will have production server level hardware or software. Now, instead of retrieving data from one central location, you likely have to go through all types of home routers and firewalls to get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to our landing page example from above, instead of making a &lt;em&gt;single&lt;/em&gt; call to retrieve data for 50 thing-a-magoos, now we need to make &lt;em&gt;50 calls&lt;/em&gt; (one to each user) to retrieve the data. Actually, it will almost certainly be many multiple multiples of 50, since P2P libraries like &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; will retrieve the same pieces of data from multiple nodes to compare for authenticity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-challenges-does-this-cause&quot;&gt;What Challenges Does This Cause?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hopefully getting clearer why there is much more leg-work involved in retrieving data in a decentralized way, but what challenges does this pose for clients?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Latency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed difference is significant between retrieving a single piece of data from a highly optimized production server verses from the home computer of the average person. For example, in the centralized world, if the average server request takes more than a fraction of a second to return—let’s say 250ms—it would often be considered slow and teams of engineers would be having meetings on how to reduce this. In our desktop client, we routinely have requests taking upwards of a minute before possibly timing out. And that’s just for a single request. I’m sure you can imagine the difference between retrieving a list of 50 thing-a-magoos in one request from a central server versus having to make a call for each one across a network of distributed nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequent data retrieval errors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider a popular centralized app like Facebook. How often do you enter a legitimate url and have some type of error return? I would venture to say hardly ever. In a decentralized app this world is destroyed because quite regularly calls for data fail. Perhaps the user isn’t online, nor are any seeders of the data? Perhaps some are online, but are unreachable? Perhaps you’re even making a call for a piece of data that no longer exists (e.g. a deleted listing)? Further complicating the issue is that we often don’t know the root cause of the failure. The error message could basically just be a large “shrug” emoji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Shrug_Emoji.png&quot; alt=&quot;Shrug Emoji&quot; title=&quot;Shrug Emoji&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Browsers live in a centralized world&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OpenBazaar front end is developed with Electron, which uses Chromium, the tech behind the Google Chrome browser. As such, it’s subject to many of the browser’s restrictions. One of those is that you are limited to 6 concurrent requests to the same domain. Even though we’re ultimately getting the data from many nodes, the requests are proxied through each node’s server. In other words, from the browser’s point of view, a fetch of 20 different user profiles are all coming from the same domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If latency weren’t an issue this wouldn’t be so bad. Even if a request took a less than ideal 250ms, you would be able to fully display a grid of 24 users in one second. But when requests routinely take 30 seconds, 45 seconds or 1 minute plus, suddenly it takes a whole lot of time to fully display a page. Even more problematic is that your request queue can clog up. Let’s say one profile comes back in a lightning fast 100ms and we display a user box for that user with a Follow button. If there are still 23 pending requests, even if the user clicks that Follow button, it will be put at the end of the queue and not even be called until all but 5 requests remain, which may easily be a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-example-of-how-we-addressed-these-challenges&quot;&gt;An Example of How We Addressed These Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar has an integrated chat section that’s really an app within an app. The chat app is present from the time your server starts and remains perpetually in the sidebar. Initially, this was a world destroyer because the little &lt;strong&gt;chat heads&lt;/strong&gt; (the user icons you click to open a conversation with a user) require some profile data from the party you’re conversing with (e.g. avatar, name). If a user is even slightly chatty and has engaged in at least 6 conversations, then those 6 profile calls would be enough to clog up the request queue and potentially prevent critical app functionality from being available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Chat Heads in OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chat Heads in OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Chat Heads in OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;heres-how-we-handled-some-of-the-challenges-decentralization-presented-us-in-openbazaar-chat&quot;&gt;Here’s how we handled some of the challenges decentralization presented us in OpenBazaar chat:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Latency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The server stores a list of your conversations. Within that data set is the peer ID of each person you are chatting with and the last message in the conversation. This allows us to create a chat head with a default avatar and use the peer ID as the name. The peer ID is also enough to make a link to the user’s page. While it may take up to a minute for the user’s avatar and name show up, at least you’ll have something showing in the client and you won’t be prevented from starting the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we implement multiple layers of caching. We can’t do this for all requests because for some it’s important you have fresh data. In this case, however, the user’s name and avatar will likely not change that often and if you do see data that is a few minutes (or occasionally a few days) old, it doesn’t degrade your experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One level of caching is done on the server where it will store the user’s profile on disk. Then, when you make a call and indicate a cached response is acceptable, the server will immediately send back the cached version and behind-the-scenes make an IPFS query to update the cache. In theory, the cached version will never be more than one revision behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other layer of cache is an in-memory client cache. The next time you request a profile where a cached version is ok, it won’t even go to the server, it would use what the client has in-memory. Since this is in-memory, it will only be available until you shut down the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequent data retrieval errors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our approach here is exactly the same as our approach to latency: The user will initially see a default avatar and a peer ID but still have everything they need to start a conversation. The fact that the profile fetch may not succeed is really just a visual shortcoming. This is a form of progressive enhancement where we are starting with the bare minimum functionality and attempting to augment the experience along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Browsers live in a centralized world&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This challenge was almost literally a world destroyer. If my memory serves me well, in OpenBazaar version 1.0 we had the chat app initialize before other important start-up functionality. For instance, while the chat app would be waiting on it’s multiple profiles to come back, the Notifications mini-app would be showing you a spinner. Even worse, if you wanted to actually navigate to a page in the app, the data needed to show the page would be queued until all those profile calls finished…which, lest we forget, could be minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a user experience deal breaker for those requests to be clogging up the queue and preventing critical functionality. But our hands were tied. If the browser imposes such a restriction, what could we do? Eventually, we stumbled upon the fact that the restriction is limited to HTTP requests. Incoming socket messages (which use TCP) have no such restriction. We added an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;async&lt;/code&gt; flag to most of our APIs so that the HTTP request would immediately return with a unique &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;requestId&lt;/code&gt;. Subsequently, the profiles would come individually via socket messages. They would each include the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;requestId&lt;/code&gt; so we could map the profile to the initial request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boom! We could kick off as many profile calls as we wanted and have virtually no impact on the HTTP request queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-summary&quot;&gt;In Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While “world destroying” is a bit dramatic, these challenges were indeed &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; challenging! Decentralized applications with an intended user base of non-engineers (i.e. a client not meant to be used from the shell of your favorite exotic Unix distribution), are still rare and there just aren’t that many best practices in place yet. Existing best practices for front end development are for centralized apps and a lot of them go right out the window when you introduce the challenges of decentralized data retrieval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralization is important though and, in my humble opinion, is here to stay. Over time, we’ll get there. Client developers will continue to come up with clever solutions and P2P libraries and browsers will iterate and improve. Similar to how email clients have come from being limited to the engineering labs of universities to now being used by your Grandma on her iPad, decentralized computing is coming soon to a grandma near you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">By Rob Misiorowski, OpenBazaar Front End Developer</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Get More Buyers on OpenBazaar with Categories and Tags</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-get-more-buyers-on-openbazaar-with-categories-and-tags/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Get &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;More Buyers&lt;/span&gt; on OpenBazaar with &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Categories and Tags&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-09-12T03:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-12T03:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-get-more-buyers-on-openbazaar-with-categories-and-tags</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-get-more-buyers-on-openbazaar-with-categories-and-tags/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by Jason Hotelling, OpenBazaar Front End Developer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello! We hope you’re having a great time selling and sharing on the OpenBazaar platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar stores boast the fastest setup time of any ecommerce platform. With very little effort, you can set up your store and add listings in minutes. Then, a little extra work can give buyers an exceptional experience to make them want to visit again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are going to talk about how to use tags and categories to help users find and browse your store with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;before-we-get-started&quot;&gt;Before We Get Started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t already, please follow our guides to getting started with OpenBazaar. They contain instructions and tutorials that span from &lt;em&gt;Download&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;em&gt;Browsing&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Selling&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/The-Beginners-Guide-to-Buying-Goods-Services-and-Cryptocurrency-on-OpenBazaar/&quot;&gt;The Beginner’s Guide to Buying Goods, Services and Cryptocurrency on Openbazaar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you are new to OpenBazaar, we also recommend watching our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VzlerMJMOu8&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar 2.0 Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VzlerMJMOu8&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-tags-are-for-search&quot;&gt;Step 1: Tags Are for Search&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tags&lt;/strong&gt; are one of the things search engines use to determine which listings to show to a potential buyer. Most users will discover your store through a listing that they find in search. For example, if a user is looking for t-shirts, they first navigate to the &lt;strong&gt;Discover&lt;/strong&gt; tab in OpenBazaar. Then they will select a search provider and enter a search term such as “t-shirt” or “t shirt”. In order for potential buyers to find &lt;em&gt;your shirts&lt;/em&gt;, you must enter any relevant tags on your listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, we have entered tags that may match what users enter in Search in the OpenBazaar Discover view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Add tags to your OpenBazaar listing.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Add tags to your OpenBazaar listing&quot; title=&quot;Add tags to your OpenBazaar listing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tip: Make sure to add your store name as a tag too so when people search for your store name, your listings will show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-categories-and-filters-in-your-store&quot;&gt;Step 2: Categories and Filters in Your Store&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once users click on your listing, they have the opportunity to visit your store by clicking “Go To Store” in the top left corner. This is where you have an opportunity to hook them and encourage them to shop around more. Your &lt;strong&gt;Store View&lt;/strong&gt; will show potential customers all your available listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OpenBazaar demo store - How To Get More Buyers on OpenBazar with Categories and Tags.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar demo store - How to get more buyers on OpenBazaar with categories and tags&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar demo store - How to get more buyers on OpenBazaar with categories and tags&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will make it easier for buyers to shop if you classify your listings. You should take time to become familiar with the Store View browsing experience. It will aid you later in planning and creating your store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;classify-your-listings-for-easy-store-browsing&quot;&gt;Classify Your Listings for Easy Store Browsing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Category radio buttons on OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Category radio buttons on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Category radio buttons on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little planning and foresight can make listing creation much easier. Determine which &lt;strong&gt;categories&lt;/strong&gt; and possible subcategories you’ll support in the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our example store, Variety Bazaar, we have a wide variety of listings. We ensure a potential buyer can find what they want through useful categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Add categories to your OpenBazaar listing.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Add categories to your OpenBazaar listing&quot; title=&quot;Add categories to your OpenBazaar listing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter clear, concise and unique category names for your listings. For our example store, we sell clothing, antiques, comic books and fidget spinners. We decided to represent subcategories within clothing by applying more than one category. We also sell retro items within separate categories. These items are all given the extra category ‘retro’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important not to confuse tags with categories. Categories are for organizing your store and providing a simple store browsing experience. They are only used for filtering on the store view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;browsing-using-listing-filters&quot;&gt;Browsing Using Listing Filters&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When potential buyers browse your store, they will see a few useful filters to aid them. Understanding these filters will help you plan your store well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;store-search&quot;&gt;Store Search&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Store search bar on OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Store search bar on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Store search bar on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Text entered into this &lt;strong&gt;store search&lt;/strong&gt; filters your listings based only on their titles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;shipping&quot;&gt;Shipping&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Shipping to country and free shipping filter on OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Shipping to country and free shipping filter on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Shipping to country and free shipping filter on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Ships to&lt;/strong&gt; filter limits listings based on countries to which your listings ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Free Shipping&lt;/strong&gt; filter will toggle display of listings based on this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Note: This filter displays even if no listings offer free shipping. We encourage you to use it where you can! It makes a purchase more compelling for a buyer if they know they won’t also have to deal with extra shipping costs at checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;category&quot;&gt;Category&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Clothing category selected on OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Clothing category selected on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Clothing category selected on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;category&lt;/strong&gt; filter is the primary method for which buyers will hone in on specific types of 
items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;type&quot;&gt;Type&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Listing type radio buttons on OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Listing type radio buttons on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Listing type radio buttons on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;em&gt;New Feature in OpenBazaar Desktop 2.2.5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;type&lt;/strong&gt; filter allows buyers to view store listings based on the current supported types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Physical Good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digital Good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cryptocurrency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;toggle-view&quot;&gt;Toggle View&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over on the right side of your store users can toggle between list or grid view. &lt;strong&gt;Grid view&lt;/strong&gt; shows a much larger image providing a better visual shopping experience. This is the default view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Grid view of an OpenBazaar store.png&quot; alt=&quot;Grid view of an OpenBazaar store&quot; title=&quot;Grid view of an OpenBazaar store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;List view&lt;/strong&gt; your listings are condensed so you can see more of them at one time. Each listing shows a small thumbnail of your product to the left and their prices on the right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;List view of an OpenBazaar store.png&quot; alt=&quot;List view of an OpenBazaar store&quot; title=&quot;List view of an OpenBazaar store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Note: It’s important for your listings to have &lt;strong&gt;descriptive titles&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;great photos&lt;/strong&gt; to draw in buyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sort-by&quot;&gt;Sort By&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dropdown menu allows users to sort your store listings based on price or title. Sorting can be by highest to lowest price or vice-versa; alphabetical or reverse-alphabetical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend time browsing other stores and take notes on your experience. Once you’re comfortable, its time to ensure your listings reflect a positive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tip: Once you have a listing or two up, you can &lt;strong&gt;clone&lt;/strong&gt; them to spare yourself from duplicating redundant listing information. Remember to make sure you don’t leave any incorrect fields from the original listing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a bit of extra time to plan and set up your store with care is important to drive its success. Achieving discoverability and browse-ability gets buyers in and keeps them around. Relevant tags added to your listings will increase discovery in search. Providing proper categories helps browsing users see what you offer. Finally, being familiar with your buyers’ experience will inform the best listing setup for your store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a series focused on getting the most out of your OpenBazaar store experience. Check back soon for the next installments!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Jason Hotelling, OpenBazaar Front End Developer</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Beginner’s Guide to Decentralization</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/the-beginners-guide-to-decentralization/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Beginner's Guide to &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Decentralization&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-09-10T03:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-10T03:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/the-beginners-guide-to-decentralization</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/the-beginners-guide-to-decentralization/">&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is a decentralized marketplace. What does &lt;em&gt;decentralized&lt;/em&gt; mean, and why does it matter? This article will explain the concept of decentralization without any technical jargon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralization is a way to describe how a system works. These systems can be nearly anything:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A political system, such as a government&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A technical system, such as a computer network&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A corporate system, such as the structure of a company&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A legal system, such as the laws of a particular nation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick definition: &lt;em&gt;decentralized&lt;/em&gt; means that no single person or organization has control over everyone else in a given system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better understand the concept I’ll give you some examples, but first, you need to understand decentralization’s opposite: &lt;em&gt;centralization&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;defining-centralized-systems&quot;&gt;Defining Centralized Systems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a system is “centralized,” that means one person or organization has control over everyone else. This means that the person or organization in control is able to make decisions on behalf of other people within the system, whether they like it or not. Let’s look at two examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A centralized political system&lt;/strong&gt; is one where one person or organization has control over everyone else and can make decisions for them. Monarchies and dictatorships are examples of highly centralized political systems where the leader of the nation is in control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A centralized marketplace&lt;/strong&gt; is one where the owner of the marketplace has control over all their users and can make decisions for them. Amazon, eBay, Etsy, Alibaba and all the popular ecommerce platforms are centralized. These companies get to make and enforce the rules for all the users on their platform, such as taking a cut of every transaction, monitoring all their data, and censoring trade whenever they choose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Centralized systems are &lt;em&gt;permissioned&lt;/em&gt;. You need the permission of the person or organization in control in order to participate. In a country with a highly centralized political system, permission must be granted for things like printing newspapers or even traveling. If you try to use a centralized payment system such as PayPal you need their permission. Most social media platforms are centralized and require the permission of the company to use them. Permission can be granted or revoked at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This image shows what a centralized system looks like. The participants in the system are on the outside, and there is one person or organization in the middle that everyone else is dependent upon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Centralized-network.png&quot; alt=&quot;Visual model of a centralized network&quot; title=&quot;Visual model of a centralized network&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Centralized network with a central point of control&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Centralization has its benefits. It removes ambiguity about who is in control and allows for swift action to remedy problems. For computer networks, it’s much easier to build and maintain centralized systems than decentralized ones. Having a strong leader controlling a company can help keep everyone focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Centralization also has drawbacks. There may not be ambiguity about who is in control, but that doesn’t mean those in control are actually competent, or moral. Centralized systems are easier to build technically, but they are also more fragile, since they have a single point of failure (if the person / organization in charge is gone, so is the system). Being permissioned means that those in power might exclude people they don’t like or agree with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Centralized systems can change based on who is in control. Even if the system is run well by competent and moral people today, it could be run poorly by different people tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an alternative to having systems so tightly controlled: Decentralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-decentralized-systems&quot;&gt;What Are Decentralized Systems?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve said, &lt;em&gt;decentralized&lt;/em&gt; means that there is no single person or organization that has control over everyone else in a given system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants in decentralized systems have the ability to make decisions themselves and aren’t forced to rely on anyone who controls the system. Let’s look at two examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A decentralized political system&lt;/strong&gt; is one where no person or organization has the ability to govern everyone else. A completely decentralized political system would be an anarchy (absence of a governing structure). Modern democratic systems have some elements of decentralization, where participants in the system do have some control over the decision-making process and there are multiple organizations which exist to ensure power doesn’t become centralized within one portion of the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A decentralized computer network&lt;/strong&gt; is a system where the computers talk directly to each other and there is no central point of control. Most online platforms today work by having a lot of computers called servers that their users are forced to connect to if they want to use the service. They are centralized and completely control the system. A decentralized computer network has no central servers that control access to the network: each users’ computer connects directly to other users’ computers, making a network of computers that no one controls. OpenBazaar is such a network, as are networks like Bitcoin and Bittorrent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This image shows what a decentralized system looks like. The participants in the system are equal and connect with each other instead of depending on a central party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Decentralized-network.png&quot; alt=&quot;Visual model of a decentralized network&quot; title=&quot;Visual model of a decentralized network&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Decentralized network with no center&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralized systems are &lt;em&gt;permissionless&lt;/em&gt;. Since no one controls the system, there’s no one who can stop people from joining it nor force them to leave. You can join or leave the OpenBazaar or Bitcoin networks anytime you want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralization has its benefits. There are no gatekeepers preventing you from doing what you want to do. Decentralized systems offer more freedom than centralized systems. There is no single point of failure which makes decentralized systems more resilient. Since there’s no one in charge there is no one that everyone depends on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralization also has drawbacks. Designing systems that have no one in control is difficult to do, and if not done properly will mean the system won’t work. Being permissionless does prevent gatekeepers from excluding people, but it’s also difficult (or even impossible) to remove bad actors from the system. Decentralized networks also tend to be more difficult to use than their centralized counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-spectrum-of-decentralization&quot;&gt;The Spectrum of Decentralization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Centralization and decentralization aren’t black and white. It’s not one or the other. Most systems have a mix of centralized and decentralized attributes that fall on a spectrum. When I say “centralized systems” I mean systems that have a clear central point of control. When I say “decentralized systems” I mean systems with no clear central point of control. In practice, there are gray areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a monarchy is a highly centralized form of governance.  However, there are historical examples of monarchs’ power being constrained by other groups, such as aristocracy or religious groups, so even the most centralized form of governance imaginable isn’t fully centralized in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true with decentralized systems. One criticism of “flat hierarchies” within companies (an attempt at eliminating management) is that they remain flat in name only, while some people effectively become managers again over time. Or when computers in decentralized networks communicate peer-to-peer for most communications but are forced to connect to a specific server the first time they start up (called a “bootstrap node”). Maintaining perfect decentralization within a given system is nearly impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also true that the same system can have strong decentralized elements and strong centralized elements at the same time. This can happen in open source software projects. The software itself might be built to communicate in a fully decentralized manner, but the development process itself is completely centralized within a small group or even an individual. There are some companies who offer a platform for users which they fully control and is completely centralized, but their corporate structure itself is decentralized. In these cases, you can’t label the entire system centralized or decentralized, but only certain attributes such as governance or technical architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-importance-of-decentralization-on-openbazaar&quot;&gt;The Importance of Decentralization on OpenBazaar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is unique because of its decentralization, but that alone though isn’t what makes it compelling. What’s important about OpenBazaar being decentralized is &lt;em&gt;what it enables users to do&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no company or organization that runs the OpenBazaar network. It’s a collection of people around the world connecting directly to each other to engage in free trade using cryptocurrencies. This lack of gatekeepers means OpenBazaar is permissionless, has no fees, is private, and has no censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It wouldn’t be possible to have these attributes without being decentralized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a company controlled the OpenBazaar network then…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It wouldn’t be &lt;strong&gt;permissionless&lt;/strong&gt;, since they could deny access.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It wouldn’t be &lt;strong&gt;private&lt;/strong&gt;, since they could watch users’ actions on their servers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It wouldn’t be &lt;strong&gt;free to use&lt;/strong&gt;, since they would own the infrastructure and need to take a cut to pay for it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It wouldn’t be &lt;strong&gt;censorship-resistant&lt;/strong&gt;, since the company would need to control the network based on business and market pressures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centralized&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;decentralized&lt;/strong&gt; systems exist on a spectrum and each have pros and cons. No current human system is completely one or the other. One thing they share though is that neither structure is an end goal in itself. What’s important is &lt;em&gt;how these structures enable the participation of all involved parties&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is not compelling &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; because it’s decentralized. OpenBazaar is excellent because the decentralization of the network gives users incredible freedom, privacy and autonomy in how they buy and sell online.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OpenBazaar is a decentralized marketplace. What does decentralized mean, and why does it matter? This article will explain the concept of decentralization without any technical jargon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Troubleshooting and How to Help with The Development of OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/troubleshooting-and-how-to-help-with-development-on-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/span&gt; and How to Help with The &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Development&lt;/span&gt; of OpenBazaar" /><published>2018-09-05T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-05T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/troubleshooting-and-how-to-help-with-development-on-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/troubleshooting-and-how-to-help-with-development-on-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Mike Greenberg, OpenBazaar Backend Developer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we use any kind of software we are likely to encounter issues from time to time. With closed-source software, or software that we generally pay for, there’s usually an easy way to contact someone for support as needed. You pay them, they fix your issues and it’s a very closed, one-on-one discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s a tradeoff: if that company changes their policies, pumps up their prices, or shuts down, that will have some effect on your ability to get that help—or even &lt;em&gt;keep using the software at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://coincenter.org/entry/what-is-open-source-and-why-is-it-important-for-cryptocurrency-and-open-blockchain-projects&quot;&gt;Open source software&lt;/a&gt; is a different kind of animal. It’s the result of many people coming together, sometimes from all around the world, to build programs that are transparent and inclusive, where contribution to the code base is easy and collaborative. This decentralization of technology is a major part of what we love about cryptocurrencies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; because &lt;strong&gt;it’s all about giving power back to individual users and contributors&lt;/strong&gt;. It allows them to be in control and make decisions for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/download&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt; is an open source application that is designed to be the fabric of future ecommerce with no middlemen involved and sometimes it presents some unique challenges. As the development leaders of this marketplace, we at &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io&quot;&gt;OB1&lt;/a&gt; are focused on providing a quality user experience &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; the app but also want to ensure users are empowered &lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt; of it as well so they can troubleshoot issues and help the platform keep growing. Which brings us to today’s topic…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;troubleshooting-and-reporting-issues-with-openbazaar-cue-applause&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting and Reporting Issues with OpenBazaar! (Cue applause)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar not only has the benefit of a company like OB1 ensuring its team is available, transparent and engaged with the community when people need assistance, it also has the communal benefits of an open source project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to navigate the resources of an open source project efficiently could save you time and headaches but may be different than what you’re accustomed to. This post should help clear up the support options that are available when you need help and show you how to give back to the OpenBazaar community at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s dig in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-just-happened&quot;&gt;What Just Happened?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uh oh. Your screen is displaying a cryptic error or the thing you expected never happened. Now what? The next steps are important to follow specifically in order to get to the bottom of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do is record the specific error messages you see and/or take screenshots of the problem. &lt;strong&gt;This part is critical for the developers to properly identify the root cause&lt;/strong&gt;. You are an archeologist making an archive of this bizarre behavior and you need to ensure it is preserved perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Text errors should always be copied and pasted where possible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual anomalies should be screen captured.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Original file output relevant to the failure should be saved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capturing these artifacts up-front will make sure they don’t accidentally get lost by the application changing state automatically or losing power on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-solutions&quot;&gt;Finding Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have the details of the problem, we should make sure that someone else hasn’t already reported the problem or found a fix. Often a problem has already been discussed and it’s just a matter of using the right tools to find some answers. As a developer on the project, I usually spend 2-3 minutes searching for unique phrases in the error or picking search terms which are going to identify my problem uniquely from other problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, consider the following error message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;There was an error following.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar error message indicating error following&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar error message indicating error following&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unique parts of this error are &lt;strong&gt;error following&lt;/strong&gt; and the phrase &lt;strong&gt;cannot start a transaction within a transaction&lt;/strong&gt;. Pay extra attention for developer misspellings if you’re transcribing an error from a screengrab too. While misspellings are embarrassing, they may occur sometimes. Pasting these search phrases into your search engine of choice should reveal pretty quickly if anyone else has reported this issue yet. Making use of double-quotes around phrases which should match exactly is recommended to filter out unrelated results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Searching for OpenBazaar error following.png&quot; alt=&quot;Searching for OpenBazaar error message indicating error following&amp;quot;&quot; title=&quot;Searching for OpenBazaar error message indicating error following&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A search for &lt;strong&gt;OpenBazaar “error following”&lt;/strong&gt; produced a Github issue which was reporting the same error. However, when we open the issue we find that the cause of the error is due to something different and probably not related to our problem. I will leave a search for the other phrase as an exercise for you to try. Finding a discussion around an existing problem could lead to a solution that you might be able to apply yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;researching-resources&quot;&gt;Researching Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a solution doesn’t already exist, you will need to get your new problem report into the right hands. We have quite a few places across the internet where the OpenBazaar community offers help to each other. Take advantage of the open community by sharing your challenge in the appropriate channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s quickly walk through the &lt;strong&gt;common resources&lt;/strong&gt; available and how they may be useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.zendesk.com/&quot;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions and Knowledge Base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we keep instructions for common tasks such as software setup, establishing your store, and handling moderation tasks. There’s also information about features which are unique to OpenBazaar like our multi-signature escrow or how vacation mode is used. This is primarily a read-only site which will surface the most regular questions from our users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Active Updates on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter can be a good source of up-to-the-minute news as well as a way to reach out to our team for urgent requests. Here you can find dialogue with fans, critics, news, updates, and promotions from our marketing team. It is an open platform for discussion with a short-form approach to dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Community Discussion on &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reddit allows for topical, threaded discussions and lets users discuss all sorts of things. Some leading topics in the OpenBazaar subreddit include: new stores, decentralized ecommerce news, cryptocurrency mechanics and issues which are hard to track down. The discussion on Reddit shifts over time but its persistence gives a good archive of past issues and thought-provoking conversation. Participating in the OpenBazaar subreddit can be anonymous and has no barrier to posting a question or comment short of creating a Reddit account. Most anything even slightly related to OpenBazaar can be posted here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Real-time Discussion on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/OpenBazaarGroup&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For high-bandwidth conversation with other users and contributors, our team and community congregate in these 2 discussion forums that function a lot like real-time chatrooms. Some areas of these communities focus on 3rd party search providers, moderators and escrow, and new ideas being tested on OpenBazaar, as well as offering each other help and support on common issues. Slack, by far the more popular of the two, has the most regular activity, as the OB1 team and many other developers are engaged there. Telegram is not quite as active but is a nice addition to Slack were people can pop in to ask quick questions about OpenBazaar or determine their next steps troubleshooting an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Development on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github contains the technical discussions and objectives of our various projects. Each repository contains a history of commits from previous contributors, a list of issues that represent pending work, and in some cases further technical documentation which is coupled to the software. This is where the rubber meets road as far as where improvements are discussed and added. It’s safe to assume if a problem or issue is not being tracked in Github, it is not being worked on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reporting-the-problem&quot;&gt;Reporting The Problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so what happens when you have exhausted all avenues of personal research and are still stumped? OB1 funnels all code changes through &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-desktop/issues&quot;&gt;Github’s issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;. When providing a bug report, including enough information in order to reproduce–and then fix–the problem is the primary objective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is a brief checklist of useful information that should be included in the report:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mention your &lt;strong&gt;operating system (OS) and version&lt;/strong&gt;. If the OS type and version is unknown for your computer, you can visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://whatsmyos.com/&quot;&gt;http://whatsmyos.com&lt;/a&gt; to help. (ex: Windows 10, MacOS 10.12.16, Ubuntu 16.04)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mention your &lt;strong&gt;OpenBazar software version&lt;/strong&gt;. This is indicated in the top right corner of the About screen, which can be launched from the navigation menu in the upper right. (ex: client 2.2.4, server 0.12.3)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Share any &lt;strong&gt;specific error messages and screenshots&lt;/strong&gt; you have previously recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Describe any &lt;strong&gt;context or steps leading up to the error&lt;/strong&gt;. A bug may be unique to the original environment it was created in or it may only be triggered by following steps in a specific order. Developers will use this information to attempt to reproduce the error in a controlled environment. Only once the problem can be demonstrated can developers begin to isolate and repair the root cause.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Clearly indicate &lt;strong&gt;what you expected to happen&lt;/strong&gt;. The error you’re experiencing may not be completely obvious to the developer that is reading your report. You may consider including your reason for wanting the problem to be solved the way you described. A developer may value this insight for improving the user experience of the feature.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reporting a bug is as simple as opening an issue in the appropriate Github repository, which will most often be &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-go&quot;&gt;openbazaar-go&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-desktop&quot;&gt;openbazaar-desktop&lt;/a&gt;. OB1 separates the repositories for the frontend user interface and the backend server. If you are unsure which repository a report should be put into, take a good guess and we’ll fix it if necessary. Once you have the information prepared, you can visit the Issues tab and click “New Issue” and paste the prepared information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Submitting an OpenBazaar Issue on Github.png&quot; alt=&quot;Submitting an OpenBazaar Issue on Github&quot; title=&quot;Submitting an OpenBazaar Issue on Github&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you don’t have a Github account to report the issue? That’s okay. 
If you are unfamiliar with Github then you may also file a report using &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/requests/new&quot;&gt;Zendesk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posting your report in Github is likely to get a faster solution, but you can also share your issue in any of the other official channels mentioned to begin a discussion. Who knows, you might even find another user is having the same issue later and puts both of your reports into Github. Our community IS pretty helpful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;following-up-and-fixing&quot;&gt;Following Up and Fixing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There may be some additional questions the team has. Please be sure to check back on your report from time to time to see if progress on your fix is being made and if more information about your problem may be needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reporting an issue to the OpenBazar community can be a bit of work but you can be an active part of finding or even building the solution. Since OpenBazaar is open source software, this is a huge part of how the marketplace grows. By taking the time to share your experiences with OB1 and other community developers you can contribute to making this software better for everyone—and maybe make some friends along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t already, please make sure you come join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, our most active community forum, and say hello!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">By Mike Greenberg, OpenBazaar Backend Developer</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar Developer Call - August 30, 2018</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-August-30-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar Developer Call - August 30, 2018" /><published>2018-08-30T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-30T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-August-30-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-August-30-2018/">&lt;p&gt;This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on August 30, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to join the call in real time? Sign up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/developers&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our ongoing conversations on Slack at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p-lmdS07mxc&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chat log:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:12] &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.github.io/wns/&quot;&gt;https://openbazaar.github.io/wns/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:12] chris.troutner: Very excited about a naming system!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:13] chris.troutner: Is this ready to use?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:13] chris.troutner: Ok. Might clarify that it’s using the Ethereum test network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:14] chris.troutner: Can you provide a link to the mobile wallet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:17] Sameep: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/smart-contracts&quot;&gt;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/smart-contracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:19] chris.troutner: &lt;a href=&quot;https://p2pvps.org/august-2018-project-update/&quot;&gt;https://p2pvps.org/august-2018-project-update/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:20] Yeshe: I think you guys are doing great.  Im setting up a web hosting vps business. Wish to help you guys out. But dont know how to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:21] Yeshe: Dont like how some of the big boys overcharge ppl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:21] chris.troutner: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.bitcoin.com/learn.html&quot;&gt;https://developer.bitcoin.com/learn.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:23] chris.troutner: &lt;a href=&quot;https://lbry.io/&quot;&gt;https://lbry.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:26] chris.troutner: I’d love to see someone offer OB store hosting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:27] Sameep: I like that idea&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:29] Yeshe: Yes i will be glad to help out …i will join the slack.  Will chat with chris …    Thanks guys&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:29] chris.troutner: My handle on different platforms is usually @chris.troutner or @christroutner&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:30] Yeshe: Thanks all&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on August 30, 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Decentralized Search and Content Discovery on OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/decentralized-search-and-content-discovery-on-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Decentralized &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Search and Content Discovery&lt;/span&gt; on OpenBazaar" /><published>2018-08-21T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-21T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/decentralized-search-and-content-discovery-on-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/decentralized-search-and-content-discovery-on-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by OpenBazaar Developer Tyler Smith&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content discovery&lt;/strong&gt; is a crucial component to any ecommerce system, especially 2-sided marketplaces where users are both the buyers and the sellers. Even if vendors have listed a number of great products, if users can’t find things they want then they won’t become buyers. &lt;strong&gt;Centralized&lt;/strong&gt; 2-sided marketplaces like Amazon and Etsy have been able to build robust discovery tools because they control the platform and are able to collect every bit of user data generated there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;decentralized&lt;/strong&gt; marketplace like OpenBazaar removes the opportunity for a single organization to own and control all data which creates advantages for users in giving them more freedom and privacy but it also presents some challenges for creating a good content discovery system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A truly decentralized answer to easy and elegant content discovery does not yet exist but we have developed an approach to help buyers find things they want and need in this growing marketplace while still honoring a valuable principle that decentralization provides: &lt;strong&gt;choice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Search Providers in OpenBazaar.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Search Providers in OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Search Providers in OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;federation-a-stop-between-centralization-and-full-decentralization&quot;&gt;Federation: A stop between centralization and full decentralization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In version 1.0 of OpenBazaar we tried our hand at a truly decentralized search index but the results were less than ideal. The technology is just not there yet. In response to the search deficiencies then, the market acted in the form of DuoSearch, which was a company that decided to build a crawler for the network and maintain their own centralized index. Users had to leave the OpenBazaar app and go to the DuoSearch website to easily browse items. Once they discovered items they wanted to by, they had to return to the app to make the purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For version 2.0 we knew we wanted a system that could be as nice to use as DuoSearch, from inside the app, and without requiring all users to use a single, centralized search engine. The solution is &lt;strong&gt;a federated search system&lt;/strong&gt; that anybody can participate in. In version 2.0, each search provider can build and maintain their own view of the network but conform with a common interface that allows them to be used interchangably in systems. Nobody has an upper hand and everybody can compete on quality and features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;basics-of-building-a-search-api-for-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Basics of building a search API for OpenBazaar&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anybody can build a search provider that can be added to the client by ensuring their API is compliant with &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/tyler-smith/44b5cc8065042f221630cb5c8be505bf&quot;&gt;OBIP2&lt;/a&gt; which defines a spec for how the OpenBazaar client and search providers interact. Any API following the spec can be consumed by OBIP2 clients which means anybody can build their own search engine any way they’d like to. They show any listings they want, any filters they want, and score results any way they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to serve search results a, search developer needs to crawl the network using the OpenBazaar server API and index the results into a system like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elastic.co/&quot;&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algolia.com/&quot;&gt;Algolia&lt;/a&gt;. They also need to frequently re-check their data to ensure the content is still available on the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After indexing all the data they need to build an API satisfying the OBIP2 interface so that OpenBazaar users can add the root URL to their client and begin using the search engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;customizing-your-search-experience&quot;&gt;Customizing your search experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A search provider could be completely free for use, monetize their search by selling paid promotion slots, or sell premium search endpoints. It’s entirely up to them how they’d like to run it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every provider decides what results to show for any given query and they define their own filtering and sorting options. This allows them do things like experiment with new features or specialize in only certain types of listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone could create a food-oriented search where users can filter by types of food or ingredients and sort by nutritional value. Or a search engine for clothing with options related sizes and styles. The OpenBazaar protocol and applications have no concern for what data is being served, as long as it’s being served in the proper format for users to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;common-issues-and-future-improvements&quot;&gt;Common issues and future improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crawling the network and keeping the data fresh is the most challenging part of building a search provider. Search providers want to make sure everything they serve is still available on the network. They also don’t want to serve listings whose names have expired on the network which can be tricky to track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future we plan to make this much easier and more reliable by utilizing &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io/blog/25-pubsub/&quot;&gt;PubSub in IPFS&lt;/a&gt; to broadcast updates that anybody can listen for. Providers will only need to listen on the update channel to get all the information necessary to update their index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re aware that the tooling and documentation around the lower level details on how to build a working crawler could stand to be improved. We are working on a future post that goes into more technical details and explanations and are considering how we can create open tooling to make it as easy as possible for anybody to participate in the OpenBazaar content provider ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by OpenBazaar Developer Tyler Smith</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Build a Search Engine for OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-build-a-search-engine-for-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Build a &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Search Engine&lt;/span&gt; for OpenBazaar" /><published>2018-08-21T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-21T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-build-a-search-engine-for-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-build-a-search-engine-for-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by OpenBazaar Lead Backend Developer Chris Pacia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we were designing &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/download&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;, now the world’s largest decentralized marketplace, we knew the general approach to creating a &lt;strong&gt;search engine&lt;/strong&gt; that delivered high quality results was to use a centralized server to index listings and run search queries. A centralized search experience, however, was completely out of line with the &lt;strong&gt;freedom&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;flexibility&lt;/strong&gt; this open-source marketplace represents. We knew there had to be some intermediate step we could take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-federated-approach&quot;&gt;A Federated Approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to do what few other platforms have done and open it up so that &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/decentralized-search-and-content-discovery-on-openbazaar/&quot;&gt;anyone can create a search engine that is compatible with the OpenBazaar app&lt;/a&gt;. This would allow us to start by building our own search engine to help users navigate the network but would relieve their total reliance on it. All the data that needs to be indexed is &lt;strong&gt;public&lt;/strong&gt; and anyone can create and run a search engine of their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-a-search-engine-for-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Building a Search Engine for OpenBazaar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have written a brief overview of how to build a search engine for OpenBazaar and described some of the outstanding issues we are still working on. It does take some technical skill to build a search engine, but developers with previous experience building and maintaining online infrastructure should be able to create a simple version without too much difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1---finding-peers&quot;&gt;Step 1 - Finding Peers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step one is to build a database of all the peers you want index. There are several ways you can do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Actively crawl the network&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The openbazaar-go API provides a couple of APIs to make this easy. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/ob/peers&lt;/code&gt; returns a list of peers you’re connected to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;ob peers.png&quot; alt=&quot;ob peers - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;ob peers - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/ob/closestpeers/&amp;lt;peerID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; returns a list of “closer” peers from the DHT. One can crawl the network for more nodes just by iterating over your current peer database and fetching closer peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;ob closest peers.png&quot; alt=&quot;ob closest peers - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;ob closest peers - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/ob/peerinfo/&amp;lt;peerID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; endpoint to look at their IP address if you wanted to index only Tor stores, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Passively listen for new peers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this you’d likely want several nodes running at the same time. From there you could stream
peerIDs to your database every time one of your nodes receives a new connection. You might not get all peers this way but you should find most. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;openbazaar-go&lt;/code&gt; nodes do not expose an API which streams new peer connections so you’d have to patch a node to get this data. Creating such an API should be relatively easy and it’s something we are considering doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Subscribe to pubsub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are just now starting to make use of the libp2p’s pubsub capabilities. Currently only IPNS data is broadcast to pubsub channels but hopefully relatively soon we will have all nodes announce new publishes over a pubsub channel. Normal users will not be subscribed to this data–as it is a lot of data–but for people who are building search engines this would be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on what data we include in the publish, you should be able to subscribe to the appropriate channel and receive streaming updates from every peer. We’ll be sure to announce and document this functionality when it is available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Manual curation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also just manually enter the peerIDs of stores you find interesting in your database. This isn’t actually a bad strategy if you want your search engine to target specific types of products. Complex machine learning algorithms would likely also work for this if you are particularly adventurous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2---indexing-stores&quot;&gt;Step 2 - Indexing Stores&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a list of stores it’s time to index them. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/ob/listings/&amp;lt;peerID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; will give you a list of all the store’s listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;indexing stores on openbazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Indexing Stores on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Indexing Stores on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you grab the hash from a listing you can get the full details by using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/ob/listing/&amp;lt;peerID&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;hash&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;ob listing peerid hash.png&quot; alt=&quot;ob listing peerid hash - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;ob listing peerid hash - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will also need the user’s profile which you can get from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/ob/profile/&amp;lt;peerID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;ob profile peerid.png&quot; alt=&quot;ob profile peerid - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;ob profile peerid - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you can put the listings in whatever database you please to index and search them. Your API just needs to conform to the specification in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/obips/blob/master/obip-0002.md&quot;&gt;OBIP2&lt;/a&gt; and it will be compatible with the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see your search engine when your stores are indexed, enter the URL here in the OpenBazaar client:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;add your search engine to openbazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Add your search engine to OpenBazaar - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Add your search engine to OpenBazaar - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3---keeping-content-fresh&quot;&gt;Step 3 - Keeping Content Fresh&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge with running a search engine is avoiding serving stale content. Given that OpenBazaar is still fairly new, users may come and go frequently. You want to avoid serving listings for stores where the owner has not been online in a long time to make sure to give potential buyers a fresh discovery experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, listings are not guaranteed to persist on the network longer than a week after a vendor has gone offline. It still &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; be visible to some users due to caching, but not everyone may be able to see the listing. If you serve old listings, a potential buyer might click on it only to get a Not Found error. We recommend not serving listings from vendors which have not been identified as being online at least once within the past week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you determine that? Admittedly this is an area where we are still working to improve but there are a few ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, make sure your database of peerIDs also tracks the last seen or last good timestamp for the peer. Next, you have several ways you could update the timestamp:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Ping each peer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/ob/status/&amp;lt;peerID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; endpoint will attempt to ping them and tell you if they are online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;ob status peerid endpoint.png&quot; alt=&quot;ob status peerid endpoint - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;ob status peerid endpoint - How To Build a Search Engine on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem, however, is that about 60% of nodes on the network are unreachable due to NAT traversal issues. Tor nodes tend to have even worse issues as many users run on operating systems like Tails and Whonix which lock down the control port and make it difficult to accept incoming connections. So this only gets you part of the way there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Passively listen for incoming connections&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is similar to 2) above in Finding Peers. You could update the timestamp for a peer every time they connect to you but again this will either require patching your node or for us to provide an API to get the data. This also will not cover every peer you’re interested in unless you run many nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Disable caching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you set &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;UsePersistentCache&quot;: false&lt;/code&gt; in your node’s config file it will stop returning from cache and will do a new DHT crawl each time you request user data. If the data has dropped out of the network, you will know about it as the data will return not found. If it’s not found, you should generally not serve up that peer’s data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you’ll likely also want to set &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;BackUpAPI&quot;: &quot;&quot;&lt;/code&gt; in the config as by default it will try to get the record from our gateway’s cache if the record cannot be found in the DHT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Use IPNS record validity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time a user publishes new content they publish an IPNS record containing an expiration date in the DHT. That expiration date is the time at which the user’s listings will drop out of the network absent them re-publishing which happens automatically when their node starts up and once a day thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you query for a user’s listings or profile or anything else, your node looks up the IPNS record. You could theoretically use this expiration date as a proxy for the last good timestamp for the peer and beyond that stop serving their listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data is not yet exposed in our API and it’s something that we have on our list to develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Use pubsub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, whenever you query for a peer’s data, it subscribes to streaming updates for that peer. This means you’ll be notified immediately whenever they publish a new IPNS record. Not only does this tell you when they have signed online, but you could also get the latest IPNS record validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, disabling cache–3) above–also disables pubsub and would make this method ineffective. This is another issue that we are working on improving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4---making-money&quot;&gt;Step 4 - Making Money!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s entirely possible for you to monetize your work on an OpenBazaar search engine by adding paid ads in your search results. In fact, you could pretty easy sell ad space for your search engine through your own OpenBazaar store!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;issues-and-improvements&quot;&gt;Issues and Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a general overview of the technical work required for building an OpenBazaar search engine. We’re aware of some areas we would like to improve upon such as creating an API that allows us to stream newly found peerIDs and also have APIs that allow us to inspect IPNS records or pubsub publishes to update our timestamp associated with each peer. We could likely combine all of this into one streaming API that pulls data from all these sources and streams not only new peerIDs that it finds, but also the most up-to-date timestamp for that peer that it is able to decipher. This way search engines only need a single API to update their peers database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are constantly working to make it easier for anyone to jump right in and start building on the OpenBazaar platform. If you have any questions or comments about any of this, please join our conversation in &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; and tell us what you think.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by OpenBazaar Lead Backend Developer Chris Pacia</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar Developer Call - August 16, 2018</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-August-16-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar Developer Call - August 16, 2018" /><published>2018-08-16T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-16T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-August-16-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-August-16-2018/">&lt;p&gt;This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on August 16, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to join the call in real time? Sign up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/developers&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our ongoing conversations on Slack at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tB0wCl4Hsik&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chat log:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:09] chris.troutner: There have been some new hires and a lot of changes. Could we get a brief run-down of an org chart. Like who is kind of overseeing what subcomponents of OB?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:13] chris.troutner: I’d love to hear some details/preview of the API wallet vs Etherium. Technical difficulties/gotchas, etc. Other than the OB token, what is the goals of the Ethereum wallet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:17] Gustavo Frederico: Hi - is there any known project for integration between OB and other traditional e-commerce platforms? (SAP Hybris, Oracle ATG commerce, Elastic Path, Magento, Sitecore, etc )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:21] Gustavo Frederico: Excellent!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:22] chris.troutner: Can you guys remind me on the difference between hitting the ‘Reload Transactions’ button vs deleting the header.bin file?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:23] mg (OB): Reload button is a soft reset. Deleting the headers.bin is the hard reset. Let me know if you want more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:23] chris.troutner: Thats good&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:24] chris.troutner: Since we’re on the topic of APIs and integrations, I’ll put this link here to the node.js library for interfacing with the OB API:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:25] mg (OB): Gustavo, it sounds like you may have a use case in mind. If there is, I’d be curious what so we can make sure to improve those docs to that end.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on August 16, 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer Stats and How To Get $10 in BTC for Your First Purchase on OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Summer-Stats-and-How-To-Get-10-in-BTC-for-Your-First-Purchase/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer Stats and How To Get &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;$10 in BTC&lt;/span&gt; for Your First Purchase on OpenBazaar" /><published>2018-08-15T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-15T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/Summer-Stats-and-How-To-Get-10-in-BTC-for-Your-First-Purchase</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Summer-Stats-and-How-To-Get-10-in-BTC-for-Your-First-Purchase/">&lt;p&gt;For those of us in the northern hemisphere, summer is waning - and we miss it already. We’ve had an excellent season so far with the release of some new features and seeing a pop of new users come in. We want to keep the fun going just a little bit longer by &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/bitcoin-promotion&quot;&gt;giving away some bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;here-are-a-few-things-we-are-proud-of-accomplishing-this-summer&quot;&gt;Here are a few things we are proud of accomplishing this summer:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Launched&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/New-OpenBazaar-Release-Enables-Trading-1500-Cryptocurrencies/&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer trading over 1,500 cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt; with seller’s choice of adding a markup or discount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Built&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;a whole new website&lt;/a&gt; just for browsing OpenBazaar on the web&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcomed&lt;/strong&gt; thousands of new users from over 125 different countries into the OpenBazaar network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to see people trading cryptocurrencies and easily sharing their stores and listings on social media. Very soon they will also be able to make and take payments in &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; wallet with their choice of &lt;strong&gt;five&lt;/strong&gt; different coins!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are constantly working to make decentralized ecommerce extremely beautiful and accessible for everyone, everywhere on earth. And we couldn’t do it without people from so many different places developing, trading and participating right alongside us, telling us what they think and helping us make this thing better every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want you to try it and tell us about it, too. To sweeten the already awesome deal of checking out the future of ecommerce, we want to give you &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/bitcoin-promotion&quot;&gt;$10 BTC toward your first purchase on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/bitcoin-promotion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Get $10 Bitcoin for OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;How To Get $10 in BTC for Your First Purchase on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;How To Get $10 in BTC for Your First Purchase on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yeah, we’re just &lt;em&gt;giving away $10 in bitcoin&lt;/em&gt; so you can try OpenBazaar for yourself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we aren’t even being creepy about it. You don’t need to already have or send bitcoin to anybody else nor spam everyone you’ve ever met. You just need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/bitcoin-promotion&quot;&gt;follow these short instructions&lt;/a&gt; and we will send $10 BTC to your OpenBazaar wallet so you can shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all we have for now. Grab your &lt;strong&gt;free bitcoin&lt;/strong&gt; and we’ll see you in the marketplace!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For those of us in the northern hemisphere, summer is waning - and we miss it already. We’ve had an excellent season so far with the release of some new features and seeing a pop of new users come in. We want to keep the fun going just a little bit longer by giving away some bitcoin!</summary></entry></feed>