<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-29T18:24:38+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/</id><title type="html">OpenBazaar</title><entry><title type="html">The Difference Between Cryptocurrency Payments and Cryptocurrency Trading in OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/the-difference-between-cryptocurrency-payments-and-cryptocurrency-trading-in-openbazaar" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Difference Between &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Cryptocurrency Payments&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Cryptocurrency Trading&lt;/span&gt; in OpenBazaar" /><published>2018-06-23T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-23T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/the-difference-between-cryptocurrency-payments-and-cryptocurrency-trading-in-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/the-difference-between-cryptocurrency-payments-and-cryptocurrency-trading-in-openbazaar">&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrencies are very exciting to us, which we think we’ve made pretty apparent. We did, after all, build the &lt;strong&gt;world’s first fully decentralized marketplace&lt;/strong&gt; to help cryptocurrency users find each other and buy and sell goods and services anywhere in the world using this groundbreaking new kind of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While the “currency” part of cryptocurrency is particularly important to us, there are quite a few things other you can do with this technology, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important attribute they have is how they store and move value even when not measured against things like physical items or government-controlled currencies. With OpenBazaar we’ve been working hard to help users to do more things with the cryptocurrencies they love which now includes &lt;strong&gt;trading coins&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;buying things&lt;/strong&gt;, both completely peer-to-peer. These two particular features are distinct though and we wanted to tell you a bit more about how they work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Setting-Up-a-New-Server-Node-Wallet-on-OpenBazaar-1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Setting Up a New Server Node Wallet on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Setting Up a New Server Node Wallet on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cryptocurrency-payments-in-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency Payments in OpenBazaar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, sending and receiving payments for listings in OpenBazaar can be done with &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash/&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt; (this integration is in Beta). These payments require that both the buyer and seller have wallets running the same coin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can &lt;strong&gt;choose which of these 3 coins&lt;/strong&gt; they would like to run when they first set up their profile and/or store. If they would like to add additional coins they can easily set up additional profiles/stores to do so that are easy to switch between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-up-a-new-server-node-wallet-on-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Setting Up a New Server Node Wallet on OpenBazaar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can also choose to add funds to their OpenBazaar wallets using any other coin they may have in an external wallet as enabled by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://shapeshift.io/&quot;&gt;Shapeshift&lt;/a&gt; Shifty Button integration. The coins will change and resolve to whichever of the 3 integrated coins the wallet is set to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the development side, integrating additional coins for payments like these 3 coins are is complicated to add and maintain with the current infrastructure. OpenBazaar requires that coins have certain technical attributes to be compatible with the checkout flow, they must have their own separate wallets within OpenBazaar, and users must run separate OpenBazaar nodes in order to support them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While we’ve made it easy to set up &amp;amp; toggle between different nodes running these different coins, we know this setup is far from ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-is-it-set-up-this-way&quot;&gt;Why is it set up this way?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This setup is the result of a choice we made to bridge a gap that opened up with Bitcoin when network transaction fees jumped very high at the end of 2017. We integrated Bitcoin Cash and Zcash quickly because of their technical similarity to Bitcoin, their supportive community and the ease of their implementation just to give users a couple more payment options that could allow them to circumvent these high fees if they wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plans now are to phase the network into a more inclusive structure starting with first &lt;strong&gt;combining these 3 payment coins into just one wallet&lt;/strong&gt;. This &lt;strong&gt;multicoin wallet&lt;/strong&gt; will allow users to easily use multiple coins at once rather than in separate nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long term goal is to expand the interface allow for any individual user to easily decide and set up whatever payment coins they would like to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cryptocurrency-trading-in-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency Trading in OpenBazaar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency trading is a completely separate feature from the payment coins available in OpenBazaar. It’s enabled by a custom listing type that makes it easy for users to list and search for they coins they want to sell and buy. Users can buy and sell a variety of other coins but again, right now, they must use Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash or Zcash for the actual payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Setting-up-a-cryptocurrency-listing-on-OpenBazaar.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Setting Up a Cryptocurrency Listing for Sale on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Setting Up a Cryptocurrency Listing for Sale on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now OpenBazaar uses third parties to pull in token information for our cryptocurrency trading. We started with &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoinaverage.com/&quot;&gt;BitcoinAverage&lt;/a&gt; which provides 44 different coins users can list. Soon we will also be adding &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/&quot;&gt;CoinMarketCap&lt;/a&gt;’s index which will shoot the available coins up to over 1,500. All coins available on these two platforms will also be available in OpenBazaar for trading. In the future we will also be able to add individual coins and we will soon be sharing a process for getting your coin listed if it is not already available through these providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Cryptocurrency-Trading-on-OpenBazaar-Home-Page.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cryptocurrency Trading on The OpenBazaar.com Home Page&quot; title=&quot;Cryptocurrency Trading on The OpenBazaar.com Home Page&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;See how it works on OpenBazaar.com!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’re an expert in the existing structure of payment coins vs. trading coins, perhaps you’d be interested in what our development team is doing next with &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2tynK31&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ready put your cryptocurrencies to work, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/download&quot;&gt;download OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt; now!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Cryptocurrencies are very exciting to us, which we think we’ve made pretty apparent. We did, after all, build the world’s first fully decentralized marketplace to help cryptocurrency users find each other and buy and sell goods and services anywhere in the world using this groundbreaking new kind of money.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Does Toronto Have a Great Crypto Community – or The GREATEST Crypto Community?</title><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/does-toronto-have-a-great-crypto-community-or-the-greatest-crypto-community" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Does Toronto Have a Great Crypto Community – or &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;The GREATEST &lt;/span&gt; Crypto Community?" /><published>2018-06-15T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-15T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/does-toronto-have-a-great-crypto-community-or-the-greatest-crypto-community</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/does-toronto-have-a-great-crypto-community-or-the-greatest-crypto-community">&lt;p&gt;OB1 CEO and OpenBazaar Project Lead Brian Hoffman and I (OB1/OpenBazaar Marketing and Community Manager, Jenn Cloud), were pleased to spend some time last week with the excellent crypto community in Toronto, Ontario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a great idea from our Series A leading investor, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omersventures.com/&quot;&gt;OMERS Ventures&lt;/a&gt;, we hosted an OpenBazaar meetup on Wednesday night at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.art-square.ca/&quot;&gt;Art Square Gallery&lt;/a&gt; across from the Art Gallery of Ontario in the heart of downtown Toronto. We had almost 130 people register for the event and over 70 showed up and packed the space to standing room only!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OB1 CEO Brian Hoffman and Toronto Crypto Community.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar Meetup - June 6 2018 - Toronto&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian presented a brief history of OpenBazaar (did you know that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbazaar.org/about/&quot;&gt;original codebase&lt;/a&gt; that was forked to become OpenBazaar was produced in Toronto?), shared the latest feature releases which are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/blog/cryptocurrency-trading-now-available-on-openbazaar/&quot;&gt;cryptocurrency trading&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://openbazaar.com/&quot;&gt;web browsing&lt;/a&gt;, and discussed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2018-roadmap/&quot;&gt;future plans&lt;/a&gt; for the network. There was a great question and answer session at the end, people were very interested in the governance structures of the network and our upcoming token release, about which we know we’ve been quiet, but we will have more to share very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a pro tip for when there is an OpenBazaar event near you: we gave out 3 deluxe swag bags to 3 attendees who had either bought or sold something on the marketplace so make sure you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/download/&quot;&gt;check it out for yourself&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Fab Toronto event w/ &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brianchoffman?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@brianchoffman&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@openbazaar&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wmougayar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@wmougayar&lt;/a&gt;, diving into the case for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/decentralized?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#decentralized&lt;/a&gt; marketplaces&lt;br /&gt;- Censorship resistant p2p network&lt;br /&gt;- Marketplace &amp;amp; rules controlled by users&lt;br /&gt;- Privacy &amp;amp; no middlemen&lt;br /&gt;- Community driven innovation &amp;amp; network growth&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/crypto?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#crypto&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/7YhQIAI1D7&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/7YhQIAI1D7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mags (@Crypto_Mags) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Crypto_Mags/status/1004558004581122048?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 7, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Mags for this great tweet! I had the opportunity to meet her and so many great, SMART people including but not at all limited to Ibrahim, Ana, Mike, Brad, John, OpenBazaar vendor Sanda and a couple from Brazil, Michael and Samara, who helped with the Portuguese translation of OpenBazaar. They even had a photo of the postcard I hand wrote and sent to them with their thank you t-shirts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event wouldn’t have been possible without the help of Lukas Royal and his team who located and secured an event space in record time near the OMERS office, set up the event on Meetup and established a Telegram group for community discussion. Special thanks also goes to one of our investors, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wmougayar&quot;&gt;William Mougayar&lt;/a&gt;, who shared this event with his network and created a spike of RSVPs. You all are wonderful and we thank you so much for your support and really making this event a success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in hosting an OpenBazaar event near you? Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/meet&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OB1 CEO and OpenBazaar Project Lead Brian Hoffman and I (OB1/OpenBazaar Marketing and Community Manager, Jenn Cloud), were pleased to spend some time last week with the excellent crypto community in Toronto, Ontario.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Valuing Privacy &amp;amp; still Getting Data from a Decentralized Network</title><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/gathering-stats-how-to-value-privacy-and-still-get-data-from-a-decentralized-network" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Valuing Privacy &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;&amp; still Getting Data&lt;/span&gt; from a Decentralized Network" /><published>2018-05-30T03:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T03:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/gathering-stats-how-to-value-privacy-and-still-get-data-from-a-decentralized-network</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/gathering-stats-how-to-value-privacy-and-still-get-data-from-a-decentralized-network">&lt;p&gt;Facebook knows exactly how many users are on their platform. Amazon knows exactly how many products are sold. Instagram knows exactly how many photos are shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, no one knows how many people use Bitcoin. No one knows how many files have been shared over Bittorrent. No one knows how many trades happen on OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why can some networks give precise statistics about how they’re being used, while others can only give estimations or have no data at all? It comes down to the architecture of the networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centralized Networks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you build a centralized network – and you control the center of the network – you then have access to information about everything that is happening. Centralized systems require all users to connect to a central point of control, and whoever sits at point of control is able to monitor and collect as much data as they please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Centralized-network.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Centralized network with central point of control&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most platforms on the internet today are centralized, and the central point of control is managed by a company. This is how Facebook, Amazon, and most platforms operate. Those companies sit in the center and collect as much information as they can about their users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the positive side, this allows them to have precise statistics and answer specific questions about how their platform is being used, which makes it easier for them to improve and satisfy users’ needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the negative side, it means the users on centralized platforms have no privacy from whoever manages the central point of control, and they don’t always use the data they gather just to improve their platform. They sometimes sell the data to others, or even lose the data if someone breaks into the databases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributed networks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed networks are fundamentally different from centralized networks. There is no central point of control in a distributed network. All users in the network are equal to other users, and users connect directly to each other. Each user is running software on their computer which connects them to the network, and that computer is called a “node” in the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few platforms on the internet today are distributed, but they are growing in number. Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies are distributed networks. OpenBazaar is distributed, as is Bittorrent. No one can sit in the center and collect information about users on these networks; there is no center at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Decentralized-network.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Distributed network with no center&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the positive side, this means that users have much more privacy on distributed networks. They aren’t required to connect and share information with a central point of control. They connect directly to other peers and exchange information directly, without necessarily informing others on the network about what they’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the negative side, this makes collecting statistics very difficult, which makes development more difficult. Those building the platform cannot see how users are using their product, and must seek other methods to know how best to improve the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Do Nodes Work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individual users set up and control their own nodes, generally from their own personal computers. They have to allow incoming and outgoing connections to participate in the network and connecting to other nodes takes some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the difficulties in collecting stats from distributed networks is the fact that most nodes on the network will only connect to a handful of peers at a time. If the network has 1,500 nodes running, each individual node might only be connected to eight or ten other nodes, meaning they only see a small fraction of the overall network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that getting an overview of the entire network is difficult, and requires lots of nodes that are connected to different peers. Or it requires a method to “crawl” through the network and look at the state over time and not as a single snapshot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;conectivity.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazar is a Peer to Peer Decentralized Network that Connects Individuals to Each Other across a Network&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed networks also present another difficulty in stats gathering: churn. Nodes can join and leave the network at any time because users can set up or delete their stores at any time. In centralized systems people joining and leaving is simple to notice, since they are either communicating with the central point of control or they aren’t. In distributed networks you don’t see all other nodes simultaneously and won’t know what’s happening on another part of the network. Even if you were able to perfectly capture the state of the network at one moment, it will likely change in the next moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is further complicated by distributed networks that don’t require nodes to be running 24/7, such as OpenBazaar (built on IPFS). This is a good thing and was a major feature built into the version 2.0 release  so that sellers’ stores are still accessible and buyers’ orders can still be processed even if the seller is technically offline, but it complicates the stats. Any attempt at gathering information about the state of the network by looking at &lt;em&gt;online nodes&lt;/em&gt; only will be missing the fact that these offline users are still a part of the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenBazaar Usage &amp;amp; Stats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can partially answer some questions about the OpenBazaar network with indirect data. For example, while we don’t know how many trades occur, we can see when a user leaves a review on a completed purchase. This gives us a very broad range to make estimations from, but is imprecise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We try to ascertain node count (the number of computers running the OpenBazaar software), but for the reasons noted above this is difficult. We can only see the number of nodes online and accepting incoming connections (users who have port forwarded), which is a small subset of overall OpenBazaar users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a limitation from the developer’s perspective, but it’s a feature from the user’s perspective. We built OpenBazaar to be private and it should remain so for people who value their privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opt-in Stats Gathering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe we’ve figured out a way to retain the privacy of OpenBazaar users while still allowing for relevant stats gathering to aid development. In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/blog/cryptocurrency-trading-now-available-on-openbazaar/&quot;&gt;2.2.0 release&lt;/a&gt; we introduced an opt-in stats gathering feature. Users are asked when they start the app if they’d like to share anonymous statistics with the OpenBazaar development team, and a list of the data shared is displayed. If users decline then no information is shared. If they accept then only the data that’s displayed will be shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Screenshot-from-2018-05-29-12-14-24.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data has already been helpful to the developers and over time will help us answer many questions that would have been impossible otherwise, due to OpenBazaar’s distributed design. Here are a few numbers we have been able to see over the last couple of weeks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Over 1,600 opt-ins since launch – Roughly 15% of users running version 2.2.0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Of this segment who opted in, visitors from 103 countries have driven over 4,500 sessions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;English is the language chosen by 68% of users who opted in; Russian, German and Spanish are all at 6% each&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is a network that exists for its users and is run by its users. In this marketplace, buyers &amp;amp; sellers have greater control over their experience than in any other marketplace on the planet. We want to know how to make it the best it can be for you–without stepping on your toes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Help us all make OpenBazaar better and drive forward the capabilities of decentralized platforms by opting into sharing anonymized usage stats.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download it now by clicking &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/download&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Facebook knows exactly how many users are on their platform. Amazon knows exactly how many products are sold. Instagram knows exactly how many photos are shared.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Do Moderators &amp;amp; Moderated Payments Do on OpenBazaar?</title><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/what-do-moderators-&-moderated-payments-do-on-openbazaar" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Do Moderators &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;&amp; Moderated Payments&lt;/span&gt; Do on OpenBazaar?" /><published>2018-05-17T03:49:16+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-17T03:49:16+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/what-do-moderators-&amp;-moderated-payments-do-on-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/what-do-moderators-&amp;-moderated-payments-do-on-openbazaar">&lt;p&gt;Decentralizing ecommerce is an important part of the future we believe in. We are working to build a world with greater access to global commerce and more opportunities for people everywhere to build the lives they want. We believe this is made possible with decentralized money like Bitcoin and decentralized marketplaces like OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a big vision. Much of the work we are doing right now is largely untangling some of the technological and psychological knots the infrastructure and assumptions of the last 20 years have made for us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first and biggest knots we knew had to be untangled for a decentralized marketplace like OpenBazaar to be feasible was a pretty basic service other marketplaces and storefronts have historically provided: &lt;strong&gt;dispute resolution&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Think about it: in a decentralized network that’s made only of the individual people that participate in it, and transactions exist only between the people engaged in them, what happens when something goes wrong with an order?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payments in OpenBazaar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a bit of background, OpenBazaar currently uses 3 different cryptocurrency payment types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Direct&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moderated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, if a buyer trusts a seller they can just send their coins directly to them in a direct payment. If the seller is offline at the time of payment, that creates a slightly different payment type where they just have to claim their coins when they return to their store. (You can read more details about each of these payment types &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360000303371-What-are-the-different-payment-types-in-OpenBazaar-&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there are moderated payments, which is what a buyer can use to send coins to a vendor they do not yet know or trust or to provide an extra layer of security for higher cost transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a moderated payment?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderated payments are an important part of the OpenBazaar checkout experience and something that we believe is a valuable application of a unique feature that Bitcoin and related cryptocurrencies have: multisignature (multisig) addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multisig addresses work like an escrow account between a buyer and a seller by pulling an objective third party into the checkout process, called a moderator. These addresses require 2 of these 3 parties to agree in order to release the coins at the end of a transaction. Typically transactions just go smoothly between buyers and sellers and a moderator’s help isn’t ever needed, but it sure is nice to know they are there just in case! If something does go wrong, moderators will help figure out who gets the payment coins when the buyer or seller opens a dispute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;moderated.png&quot; alt=&quot;Moderated payment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a moderator?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, a decentralized marketplace means that the entire platform is made up only of people connecting to other people with no large organizations sitting in the middle to dictate how anyone uses the platform–nor step in to provide things like dispute resolution. In a decentralized network, the individual users are each responsible for their own experiences which includes contributing positively to the community by building their business and reputation as well as protecting themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a buyer or a seller, a moderator is also just another type of user on the OpenBazaar network. Anyone can choose to become one and make their services as a moderator available on the network. And as you may know, since it’s pretty easy to get started on the OpenBazaar network, figuring out which users are more likely to be trustworthy requires a little scrutiny, first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I pick a good moderator?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer or seller, it’s important to choose a trustworthy moderator to add to your transactions if you are choosing a moderated payment. Here are some tips for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-choose-a-good-moderator-on-openbazaar/&quot;&gt;choosing a good moderator&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io/&quot;&gt;OB1&lt;/a&gt;, the company leading the development of OpenBazaar, now has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io/verified-moderators.html&quot;&gt;Verified Moderators program&lt;/a&gt; that is integrated into OpenBazaar to help users find someone that OB1 has reviewed who has shown themselves more likely to be trustworthy when helping settle disputes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vLn9dQu9Zp0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it’s always good to check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbazaar.org/scam-prevention/&quot;&gt;these scam prevention tips&lt;/a&gt; to help you stay safe and smart when buying and selling on OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose your own adventure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of choices involved in using OpenBazaar, and that’s on purpose. We know it is different from what you may be used to but we are building a marketplace where each user gets to be in control of their own experience with more features and opportunities being built all the time. To see some of the other things the OB1 team is working on to make OpenBazaar the most accessible and expandable ecommerce marketplace on the planet, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2018-roadmap/&quot;&gt;2018 Roadmap&lt;/a&gt; and make sure to sign up for the &lt;a href=&quot;/official_site/newsletter/&quot;&gt;email newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to get the latest updates!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Decentralizing ecommerce is an important part of the future we believe in. We are working to build a world with greater access to global commerce and more opportunities for people everywhere to build the lives they want. We believe this is made possible with decentralized money like Bitcoin and decentralized marketplaces like OpenBazaar.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cryptocurrency Trading Now Available on OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/cryptocurrency-trading-now-available-on-openbazaar" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cryptocurrency Trading &lt;span class='post-title-extra-alternative'&gt;Now Available on OpenBazaar&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-05-13T03:49:16+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-13T03:49:16+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/cryptocurrency-trading-now-available-on-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/cryptocurrency-trading-now-available-on-openbazaar">&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar &lt;strong&gt;version 2.2.0&lt;/strong&gt; was released today. For the full list of new features and improvements in this release, check out the release notes at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest new feature is the ability to ** buy and sell cryptocurrencies**.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cryptocurrency-trading-on-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency Trading on OpenBazaar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/q6ki3_1Io-U&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vendors are now able to use a special new listing type to &lt;strong&gt;sell cryptocurrencies on OpenBazaar&lt;/strong&gt;. They can choose from 44 different cryptocurrencies right now and more will be added over time. Payment must be settled in whichever coin they have chosen for their OpenBazaar store, either Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, or Zcash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;cryptolistings.gif&quot; alt=&quot;crypto listings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because OpenBazaar is completely peer-to-peer, &lt;strong&gt;this is not an exchange&lt;/strong&gt;. This new feature doesn’t include an order book with the ability to choose a target price for buying or selling. This new feature only allows people to trade cryptocurrencies directly with each other at market prices. It benefits from OpenBazaar’s main advantages; users trading cryptocurrencies on the platform &lt;strong&gt;won’t need to pay any fees&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;they aren’t forced to reveal any identifying information&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve released this new feature with the goal of listening to the community about how they believe cryptocurrency trading on OpenBazaar can be improved. We plan to rapidly iterate as we receive feedback from users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to give us your thoughts on this new feature!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opt-in-analytics&quot;&gt;Opt-in Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because OpenBazaar has been built with privacy in mind, the development team isn’t able to gain much information about how people use the software. This is good for privacy, but can sometimes hinder development. In order to gain more insight on how OpenBazaar is being used – and how to improve it – we’re introducing an &lt;strong&gt;opt-in analytics package&lt;/strong&gt;. Users who choose to opt in will share non-identifying data with the development team. The list of data being shared is displayed when opening the new release for the first time. Users can start or stop sharing data at any time in their Settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;release-notes&quot;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a major release, which adds buying and selling cryptocurrencies, opt in analytics, and many optimizations and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features&quot;&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– The ability to buy and sell cryptocurrencies was added. The currencies can be sold at market rates. This feature is experimental, and is expected to be rapidly iterated on as we recieve feedback from users. #1308
– An opt-in analytics package was added. Users are able to choose to share non-identifying data with the development team. This will facilitate identifying bugs and improving the app. Users can start or stop sharing data at any time. #1277&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements&quot;&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Norweigan, Polish, and Ukranian translations reached the 80% translated requirement, and were added as options for the client. #1324&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When viewing your sales, unfunded orders will now be hidden by default, since you cannot take action on those orders, and they clutter up the list of orders. You can still chose to view those orders. #1310&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listing card image loads will now cancel when the image card is no longer on the screen. This primarily improves the experience when changing pages in the search results or navigating away from a page of search results that hasn’t finished loading. #1309&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verified moderators are now lazy-loaded. This will speed up startup, and notify the user if the list of verified moderators changes while they are looking at information that will be affected by that change. #1298&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verified moderators are loaded from a Tor endpoint if the user is in Tor mode. #1284&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot;&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blockdozer changed their URL for viewing BCH transactions, the URL used when viewing details of transactions has been updated. #1320&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An issue where the no valid moderators error would show on an error at the same time as the no verified moderators message, and with the wrong formatting, was corrected. #1307&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A problem where invalid mods would never stop loading was fixed. #1306&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Error messages meant for only the purchase flow no longer appear in the settings/store tab. #1306&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some layout issues with moderator cards were corrected. #1300&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the settings/store tab, if a moderator assigned to your store has become invalid, now the only option is to de-select them. #1300&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An unused memo parameter was removed from the purchase call. #1314&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A minor layout issue was corrected in the transactions list. #1285&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The bug where pages stats are changed to zero in the page tabs on the user page when the page settings are updated was fixed. #1287&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A layout issue with verified moderators was fixed. #1270&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store pages will now open if one of the listings in them has an unrecognized currency value. #1269&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;internationalization&quot;&gt;Internationalization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are actively translating the text in the OpenBazaar reference client. If you are interested in volunteering as a translator, you can sign up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.transifex.com/ob1/openbazaar&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special thank you goes out to the many volunteers that provide translations, and to our testers that discovered important issues.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OpenBazaar version 2.2.0 was released today. For the full list of new features and improvements in this release, check out the release notes at the end of the post.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar 2018 Roadmap Community Call Agenda</title><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/openbazaar-2018-roadmap-community-call-agenda" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar 2018 Roadmap Community Call Agenda" /><published>2018-04-25T03:49:16+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-25T03:49:16+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/openbazaar-2018-roadmap-community-call-agenda</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/openbazaar-2018-roadmap-community-call-agenda">&lt;p&gt;We are looking forward to seeing you this &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, April 26th at 11am EST&lt;/strong&gt; to discuss the 2018 development roadmap and determine some priorities together as a community! Since we are expecting quite a few attendees, we want to share a brief agenda so everyone knows what to expect and we can keep things sane(ish!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;agenda-for-the-openbazaar-2018-roadmap-community-call&quot;&gt;Agenda for The OpenBazaar 2018 Roadmap Community Call&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introductions&lt;/strong&gt; – Meet the OB1 development team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recent &amp;amp; Upcoming Releases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;2018 Roadmap&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt; – Check this out ahead of time so that you know what is up for discussion!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Community Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you have not yet gotten on the call list please do so here as we will be sending the call link a few minutes ahead of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See you on Thursday!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are looking forward to seeing you this Thursday, April 26th at 11am EST to discuss the 2018 development roadmap and determine some priorities together as a community! Since we are expecting quite a few attendees, we want to share a brief agenda so everyone knows what to expect and we can keep things sane(ish!)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Do I Have to Download OpenBazaar?</title><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/why-do-i-have-to-download-openbazaar" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Do I Have to &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Download&lt;/span&gt; OpenBazaar?" /><published>2018-04-23T03:49:16+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-23T03:49:16+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/why-do-i-have-to-download-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/why-do-i-have-to-download-openbazaar">&lt;p&gt;To use OpenBazaar right now you need to download and install a program on your computer. This is quite different from other marketplaces, which you access by visiting a website. Why the difference?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is a fundamentally different way to do ecommerce. It’s built to let you take control of your own store &amp;amp; profile and connect with other users without any middlemen involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-middlemen-are-involved-in-traditional-ecommerce&quot;&gt;What middlemen are involved in traditional ecommerce?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When shopping or selling online, users encounters layers of middlemen that provide some convenience, but also force fees on users and tightly control all transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first layer is the money itself, government currencies such as the Dollar, Pound or Euro. They are produced by individual governments around the world and require exchanges to be translated into another global currency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The second is banks and credit card companies. These institutions are designed to hold and move these currencies and are also regulated by governments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The third is payment processors. These are companies like Stripe or PayPal that link your bank account or credit card to others so that you can make payments and send money more easily.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then finally are marketplaces like Amazon, Ebay or Alibaba. These companies own websites and apps where users can shop. This means they own not only the servers on which all buyer and seller profile information and content lives but also the experience that you are having and all of the data any user generates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To break free of all of these middlemen you have to break free of a lot of infrastructure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that simply wasn’t possible 10 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real breakthrough came with development of cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin. These cryptographic coins open up the first two layers of money itself to allow people to exchange value in a currency that isn’t generated by any government and can easily be used internationally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With OpenBazaar, we wanted to harness this power of Bitcoin and take it a step further, removing layers 3 and 4. Instead of asking people to connect to each other &lt;em&gt;through a website or network that we owned&lt;/em&gt;, we wanted to just let users &lt;em&gt;connect directly to each other&lt;/em&gt;, exactly how they do with Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies, but with a nice interface that felt like the payment processors and marketplaces they were used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting rid of servers in general isn’t an option as the internet still requires machines that can store and serve information to users all around the world–but they don’t necessarily need to be collected in specific locations, or, more importantly, &lt;em&gt;centrally owned&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Servers can be broken down and divided up between the users that participate in a certain network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-openbazaar-download-bundle&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The OpenBazaar download bundle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is two programs in one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenBazaar server&lt;/strong&gt; – The server is the back end application which allows OpenBazaar to function. Each user runs a server to connect them to the network and allow them to participate. It can both store and share their own public and private data, and help store and share the public data of others. This is the primary reason you have to download OpenBazaar right now.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenBazaar client&lt;/strong&gt; – The client is the front end application and allows the user to communicate and control the server, similar to a remote control. The client is the visual interface; it’s what you’re looking at when you run OpenBazaar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, the OpenBazaar packages and installers will install both server and client locally on your machine. However, you can choose to run just the server elsewhere, such as on a Raspberry Pi or use a virtual private server (VPS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This creates a distributed peer-to-peer network with the power of big, centralized servers but that isn’t controlled by any one company or organization – just a community of people who want to engage in trade directly with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-30-in-action&quot;&gt;Web 3.0 in action&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next evolution of the web is underway now and this sort of restructuring is what that’s all about. The coming years are about building the technology that eliminates the necessity of existing infrastructures to give a high level of control back to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who are doing this work believe in a world where people are able to run their own internet experience for themselves, with a level of privacy and control that was not possible, before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloading OpenBazaar is a choice to discover a new way to buy and sell online. It represents a willingness to explore and understand more about how the internet will be structured in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This download represents choice and ownership and a step out from under the heavy hand of centralized power structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you want to help build this future where individuals are in control? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/official_site/download/&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">To use OpenBazaar right now you need to download and install a program on your computer. This is quite different from other marketplaces, which you access by visiting a website. Why the difference?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar 2018 Roadmap</title><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/openbazaar-2018-roadmap" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar 2018 &lt;span class='post-title-extra-alternative'&gt;Roadmap&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-04-05T03:49:16+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-05T03:49:16+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/openbazaar-2018-roadmap</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/openbazaar-2018-roadmap">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since we updated the roadmap for OpenBazaar development. The previous roadmap essentially stated: “Get 2.0 finished!” We did that last November, and since then we’ve also released one major update (2.1.1) which allowed people to use Bitcoin Cash and Zcash in addition to Bitcoin. Several smaller but important features have been added as well, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io/verified-moderators.html&quot;&gt;verified moderators&lt;/a&gt;, to help stop scammers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company driving development – OB1 – also raised a series A round of funding. Now that the development team has released 2.0 and has resources to continue building, we’re putting out a roadmap to explain where we think OpenBazaar should go next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, this is open source and OpenBazaar is nothing more than a collection of people around the world running this free software. We want input from the community on what you think of this roadmap, and we want your help in achieving these goals as well. More details about how you can give feedback or contribute are at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tc3_ieTz4QY&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-platforms&quot;&gt;New Platforms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar has always been a desktop-only experience. Building distributed applications is very difficult to do in a browser and on mobile devices, and it was important to get the protocol right first before we even began working on alternative clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our mission has always been to make trade free. No cost to engage in trade, and no restrictions on trade either. To do this we try to make the barriers to entry of the application as low as possible. On desktop, the installation process and store setup are quite simple – but not everyone has a modern computer, and not everyone is able to download, install, and run whatever applications they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to run OpenBazaar in a browser and on a smartphone is essential to further reduce the barriers to entry into the network. These new clients are going to be the primary areas we focus on over the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mobile&quot;&gt;Mobile&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our mobile journey initially positioned OB1 offering a hosted node service that the iOS and Android clients would connect to. While convenient for the user, it would require OB1 controlling infrastructure and acting as a gatekeeper for the decentralised marketplace for mobile users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, we approached the Go community in Q3 2017 for assistance in modifying the OpenBazaar server (written in Go) for mobile devices. This strategy was successful, and after some optimisation we are proud to report that the OpenBazaar mobile applications, which OB1 will release, will run a full OpenBazaar node on the device. The significance of this achievement cannot be understated as this enables billions of mobile devices to access a decentralised marketplace as a full node on the OpenBazaar network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time we achieved this milestone and were positioned to release the app, Bitcoin transaction fees escalated to the point where trade was only viable for expensive transactions. We decided we needed to integrate other cryptocurrencies, as we further explain in &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/H4yW20txnB0&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the OpenBazaar server now supports other cryptocurrencies such as Zcash and Bitcoin Cash, it does so in an exclusive manner, and a user cannot buy or sell in multiple currencies at the same time. To support this, the OpenBazaar wallet required a significant refactor that is still ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end result will be an iOS and Android mobile app that will run a full OpenBazaar node that can transact in Bitcoin, Litecoin, Bitcoin Cash, and Zcash as a start. This will truly empower people all of the world to start earning and using cryptocurrencies in a global decentralised marketplace with zero fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Looking for a lightly used Aventador on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@openbazaar&lt;/a&gt; with this Android phone... &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/c7pk5WSGBZ&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/c7pk5WSGBZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Brian Hoffman (@brianchoffman) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brianchoffman/status/975115453893894144?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 17, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web&quot;&gt;Web&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running OpenBazaar in a browser is more difficult. The network is built on top of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt;. Running an OpenBazaar node is essentially running a custom IPFS node. There is an effort underway to have an IPFS node run in browser called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ipfs/js-ipfs&quot;&gt;IPFS-JS&lt;/a&gt;, and we believe this will allow us to build a web-based OpenBazaar version. Building the web-based version is a significant task, and we believe it will take us into early 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect the payoff to be worth the wait. The initial web-based client will allow buyers to make purchases without needing to download anything. Users can share links to stores or listings that will be viewable from the web. These improvements won’t compromise the completely distributed architecture of the network; all the necessary code is run client-side in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;developer-support&quot;&gt;Developer support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software development can be messy, especially in an innovative space where things change quickly. We made our own 1.0 version of OpenBazaar obsolete with 2.0 in only a year and a half. In order to get 2.0 out the door we didn’t focus much effort on supporting external developers, and as a result the project isn’t nearly as approachable to new contributors as we’d like. To fix this we’re now taking a few steps to make the project more friendly to external contributors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improving documentation for existing repositories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organizing / supporting software other than the main client / server repositories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Formalizing the protocol separately from the reference implementation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offering bounties for bugs or new features / apps on top of OpenBazaar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;token&quot;&gt;Token&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content discovery in a completely decentralized network can be difficult. Custom curation is a new feature we’ll be adding (see “Improved Content Discovery” below), but it’s not immediately clear why a user would take the time to offer curation services. It’s also unclear how a vendor advertises their listings in a network that nobody controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to create incentives for curators, and to give vendors the ability to advertise, we’re introducing the OpenBazaar Token.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The token whitepaper draft is complete and will be published in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbazaar.org/token/&quot;&gt;read more about the token&lt;/a&gt; and sign up to receive updates as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features&quot;&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New clients and the new token infrastructure are huge improvements for the ecosystem and will take a substantial part of development effort, but that’s not all we’re going to be doing this year. There are plenty of new features we want to add into the software as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cryptocurrency-listings&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency listings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar has always had three listing types available: physical goods, digital goods, and services. We’re now adding a fourth: cryptocurrency. Users will now be able to buy and sell cryptocurrencies directly with each other on the platform. No fees, no need to register with any service, and no threat of an exchange getting hacked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can walk through a prototype of this feature &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.invisionapp.com/share/FXGHLQ0QPEM#/screens/286861241&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We’re building this right now and it should be included in the next OpenBazaar release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;listings.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;requests&quot;&gt;Requests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrencies aren’t the only new listing type we’ll be introducing. We’ll also be adding requests, allowing buyers to make offers to purchase something if someone provides it to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The marketplace is currently one-sided with only vendors telling buyers what they have available. But with the requests feature it now becomes two-sided. Buyers tell vendors what they want, and then vendors can compete with each other to fulfil the open orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feature will change OpenBazaar from a platform where content is solely dictated by vendors to one where vendors and buyers both have the ability to change what is being offered. This listing type won’t be limited to physical goods either; users will be able to request digital goods, services, and cryptocurrencies as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;automated-digital-downloads&quot;&gt;Automated digital downloads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital goods are a great use case for cryptocurrency, but the current method of fulfilling orders placed for digital goods requires manual effort from the vendor. This new feature will automate the process so that it’s as simple as “send money, get file.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;automated-downloads.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;improved-content-discovery&quot;&gt;Improved Content Discovery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having search providers directly in the application has been a huge improvement for product discovery over the old 1.0 version, but users still don’t have a good way to browse listings, or to curate groups of listings themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be adding a feature that allows buyers to browse groups of listings that have been curated by other users on the network. These curated lists can be anything – goods sold only in a specific location, a niche style, goods based on popularity, the curator will be able to choose content lists based on any criteria they choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;content-discovery.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browsing experience in OpenBazaar. Designs may change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;better-reputation--identity&quot;&gt;Better Reputation &amp;amp; Identity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently buyers in OpenBazaar can leave reviews on transactions and those reviews are aggregated to show the vendor’s reputation. This is the only reputation metric we have in place, and we want to expand this moving forward. Decentralized reputation and identity is an incredibly difficult problem to solve, and there are no clear solutions that exist, but we know of a few ways to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One improvement is the addition of handles. This was a feature in the 1.0 version that hasn’t made it into 2.0 yet, the ability to tie your OpenBazaar ID (which is currently a random string of characters) into a human-readable name. For example, the store run by the development team has the following ID:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;ob://QmcUDmZK8PsPYWw5FRHKNZFjszm2K6e68BQSTpnJYUsML7/store&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t possible to memorize, but with the handles feature users could just type in a name such as “@OpenBazaar” to visit the store. It can also use DNS to resolve names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handles may also allow users to tie into existing identity systems, such as Blockstack. If the user has tied other accounts into the identity system, then this acts as a way to bootstrap reputation and increase trust among users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development of better reputation / identity hasn’t begun yet, so we welcome ideas and assistance in building this feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;openbazaar-foundation&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar Foundation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar has always been – and will always be – open source and free to use. The company OB1 has been the primary development team for most of OpenBazaar’s history, and have chosen not to directly monetize the protocol, but will be offering services to users on the network instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ensure the protocol will be maintained in the long-run, and to allow community members to play a larger role in guiding the development and maintenance of the protocol, network, and reference implementations, we’re considering the creation of an OpenBazaar Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specific mission of the organization is being decided now, but the overall goal would be to ensure that there always exists a place online where people can engage in free, private, permissionless trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new nonprofit would lead a transition away from OB1 being the primary maintainers of the protocol towards a community model of management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foundation creation process has only just begun, so if you have input or wish to help in the process, please let us know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-you-think&quot;&gt;What do you think?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love our roadmap? Think we’ve gotten something wrong, or missed an opportunity? We want to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hosted a community all on April 26, 2018 and you can check out the recording of that below if you’d like, but we would REALLY love for you to join us &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;on Slack&lt;/a&gt; to continue the conversation and give us your thoughts as we continue to set priorities together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/92AOVPrm6MA&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s been a while since we updated the roadmap for OpenBazaar development. The previous roadmap essentially stated: “Get 2.0 finished!” We did that last November, and since then we’ve also released one major update (2.1.1) which allowed people to use Bitcoin Cash and Zcash in addition to Bitcoin. Several smaller but important features have been added as well, including verified moderators, to help stop scammers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cryptocurrency Listing Type on OpenBazaar – What Do You Think?</title><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/cryptocurrency-listing-type-on-openbazaar-what-do-you-think" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cryptocurrency Listing Type on OpenBazaar – What Do You Think?" /><published>2018-03-22T03:49:16+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-22T03:49:16+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/cryptocurrency-listing-type-on-openbazaar-what-do-you-think</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/cryptocurrency-listing-type-on-openbazaar-what-do-you-think">&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency listing types on OpenBazaar would allow users to buy and sell coins directly with one another. What do you think? Could it work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through below to check out the short walkthrough demo of how you could post cryptocurrencies for sale. Please leave comments there or on the social media thread where you are seeing this post and tell us what you think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.invisionapp.com/share/FXGHLQ0QPEM#/screens/286861241&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;listing-demo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cryptocurrency Listing Type on OpenBazaar Demo Walkthrough&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.invisionapp.com/share/FXGHLQ0QPEM#/screens/286861241&quot;&gt;View Prototype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Still need to download OpenBazaar?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/download&quot;&gt;Get it now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Cryptocurrency listing types on OpenBazaar would allow users to buy and sell coins directly with one another. What do you think? Could it work?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Press Release: OB1 Raises $5 million Series A Financing to Grow World’s Largest Decentralized Marketplace</title><link href="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/press-release-ob1-raises-$5-million-series-a-financing-to-grow-world-s-largest-decentralized-marketplace" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Press Release: OB1 Raises $5 million Series A Financing to Grow World's Largest Decentralized Marketplace" /><published>2018-03-13T03:49:16+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-13T03:49:16+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/press-release:-ob1-raises-$5-million-series-a-financing-to-grow-world%E2%80%99s-largest-decentralized-marketplace</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.github.io/official_site/blog/press-release-ob1-raises-$5-million-series-a-financing-to-grow-world-s-largest-decentralized-marketplace">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Washington, D.C.&lt;/strong&gt; – March 13, 2018 – &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io&quot;&gt;OB1&lt;/a&gt;, the company building OpenBazaar, today announced a series A round of $5 million. The funds will help capitalize on the explosive growth that OpenBazaar has seen as blockchain and cryptocurrencies have become mainstream. OpenBazaar is the only e-commerce marketplace that offers secure, commission-free trade for both buyers and sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the launch of the updated 2.0 platform near the end of 2017, over 40,000 nodes globally have joined the OpenBazaar network. In early 2018 OpenBazaar enhanced its value to buyers and sellers by enabling purchases with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash/&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The round represents a strong validation of OB1’s stewardship of the OpenBazaar network and is led by &lt;a href=&quot;https://omersventures.com/&quot;&gt;OMERS Ventures&lt;/a&gt;, the venture capital arm of the OMERS pension fund. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitmain.com/&quot;&gt;Bitmain&lt;/a&gt; is also contributing to this round and joins existing investors &lt;a href=&quot;http://a16z.com/&quot;&gt;Andreessen Horowitz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usv.com/&quot;&gt;Union Square Ventures&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blueyard.com/&quot;&gt;BlueYard Capital&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dcg.co/&quot;&gt;Digital Currency Group&lt;/a&gt;, and angel investor &lt;a href=&quot;http://startupmanagement.org/&quot;&gt;William Mougayar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OB1 allows individuals, living anywhere, to buy and sell as part of a truly global marketplace” said Jim Orlando, Managing Partner, OMERS Ventures. “We are excited about the potential represented by OpenBazaar’s decentralized peer-to-peer protocol, and are thrilled about the various implementation paths that Brian and the rest of his team are pursuing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OB1 will continue to lead development of OpenBazaar to give users more flexibility and control over how they buy and sell goods and services online. Their plans for this year include releasing web and mobile versions of the application as well as giving users new ways to trade with each other, such as making requests and buying and selling cryptocurrencies. OB1 is also expanding the services it offers to users on OpenBazaar, such as the Verified Moderators program, released this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OB1 CEO Brian Hoffman said, “We are pleased to be partnering with both OMERS Ventures and Bitmain, adding them to a powerhouse international team of investors that are helping our team continue to build the future of free trade on the Internet worldwide. Our goal is to see the OpenBazaar protocol and software empower business owners and consumers alike to shift away from the corporate-controlled legacy systems and engage in ecommerce in a free, fair and independent way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users and fans can follow the progress of this open source project and join their community on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; and download the desktop application at &lt;a href=&quot;/official_site/download/&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Washington, D.C. – March 13, 2018 – OB1, the company building OpenBazaar, today announced a series A round of $5 million. The funds will help capitalize on the explosive growth that OpenBazaar has seen as blockchain and cryptocurrencies have become mainstream. OpenBazaar is the only e-commerce marketplace that offers secure, commission-free trade for both buyers and sellers.</summary></entry></feed>