<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://openbazaar.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://openbazaar.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-02T20:46:48+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/</id><title type="html">OpenBazaar</title><entry><title type="html">IPFS &amp;amp; Libp2p Developer Meetings - Growing The Decentralized Tech That Helps OpenBazaar Work</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/IPFS-Libp2p-Developer-Meetings-Growing-The-Decentralized-Tech-That-Helps-OpenBazaar-Work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IPFS &amp; Libp2p Developer Meetings - Growing The &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Decentralized Tech&lt;/span&gt; That Helps OpenBazaar Work" /><published>2018-07-30T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-30T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/IPFS-Libp2p-Developer-Meetings-Growing-The-Decentralized-Tech-That-Helps-OpenBazaar-Work</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/IPFS-Libp2p-Developer-Meetings-Growing-The-Decentralized-Tech-That-Helps-OpenBazaar-Work/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By OB1 Lead Backend Developer Chris Pacia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month I had the opportunity to attend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ipfs/conf&quot;&gt;IPFS/Libp2p Developer Meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Berlin. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io/&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; development is of great importance to us as OpenBazaar is built on top of it and relies heavily on it for most of its functionality. Overall the meeting was very productive. It was nice to meet the new members of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://protocol.ai/&quot;&gt;Protocol Labs&lt;/a&gt; team and see how they are growing. They have an enormous amount of talent on their team and in the IPFS community and they’re genuinely solving very hard problems in decentralized web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;IPFS and Libp2p Developer Meetings in Berlin 2018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IPFS and Libp2p Developer Meetings in Berlin 2018&quot; title=&quot;IPFS and Libp2p Developer Meetings in Berlin 2018&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are some of the key takeaways from this event as they relate directly to OpenBazaar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quic&quot;&gt;QUIC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ve been able to integrate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chromium.org/quic&quot;&gt;QUIC&lt;/a&gt; as a transport for IPFS. For those who don’t what QUIC is, it’s a new transport created by Google which offers all around better performance than TCP. Not only will QUIC make OpenBazaar faster, but it will help slightly with NAT traversal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ipns-pubsub&quot;&gt;IPNS Pubsub&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pubsub isn’t yet hooked up in the IPFS coreapi package but will be shortly. While we will still need to make a DHT crawl the first time an IPNS query is made as well as when coming back from absence, all subsequent queries will return the most up-to-date record instantly. We should see a nice speed boost in browsing as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;IPFS and Libp2p Developer Meetings in Berlin 2018-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IPFS and Libp2p Developer Meetings in Berlin 2018 - Presentation&quot; title=&quot;IPFS and Libp2p Developer Meetings in Berlin 2018 - Presentation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nat-traversal&quot;&gt;NAT Traversal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned that IPFS is already doing more for NAT traversal than I realized but more work is still needed. Currently a high percentage of nodes on the IPFS network are not reachable and I presume it’s probably a similar percentage of OpenBazaar nodes. We had some nice discussion about improving NAT traversal. The first action item is to wire up the libp2p-autonat package which will help detect if users are behind restricted NATs. Moving forward we’d like to develop some heuristics for deciding if and how to relay packets through other nodes using the libp2p-circuit-relay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-onion-transport&quot;&gt;New onion-transport&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ve done some preliminary work on a new onion transport for libp2p. Our current transport was written by me and will at minimum need to be changed to conform to planned changes to the transport interface. I believe the goal, however, will be to have the new transport ready by the time that new interface goes live so we can easily make the switch. There’s also a possibility we can use a library which statically compiles the Tor daemon and maybe resolve some issues running OpenBazaar on Tails and Whonix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was plenty more talked about and presented, some of which will likely be in OpenBazaar under the hood but also plenty of projects that are genuinely interesting in the own right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll look forward to seeing everyone again for IPFS conference in Lisbon in November.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">By OB1 Lead Backend Developer Chris Pacia</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New OpenBazaar Release Enables Trading 1500+ Cryptocurrencies</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/New-OpenBazaar-Release-Enables-Trading-1500-Cryptocurrencies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New OpenBazaar Release Enables &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Trading 1500+ Cryptocurrencies&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-07-27T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-27T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/New-OpenBazaar-Release-Enables-Trading-1500-Cryptocurrencies</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/New-OpenBazaar-Release-Enables-Trading-1500-Cryptocurrencies/">&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-desktop/releases/tag/v2.2.2&quot;&gt;version 2.2.2&lt;/a&gt; was just released, and this update gives users several new improvements to the cryptocurrency trading feature. This release also includes other improvements and bug fixes; for full details read the release notes posted below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cryptocurrency-trading&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency trading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release includes two major improvements to the cryptocurrency trading feature within OpenBazaar.
The first is the ability for users offering to trade coins to mark up or discount their price. Instead of only being able to offer a trade at market price, they can choose to add a markup, which will automatically increase the price to the buyer based on the percentage they choose. They can also choose to offer a discount from market price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software constantly is updating the market price of the cryptocurrencies involved in the trade, and will add the markup or discount at the moment the trade happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Cryptocurrency Listing Type Price Modifier.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Setting a markup or discount on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Setting a markup or discount on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second improvement to cryptocurrency listings is a major expansion of how many coins can be bought and sold on the platform. Previously there were about 60 available. Now we’re integrated price data from &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/&quot;&gt;CoinMarketCap&lt;/a&gt; and there are more than 1,500 coins you can trade on OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to see if a specific coin is available, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/download&quot;&gt;download OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt; and start the process of creating a cryptocurrency listing. You’ll see the full list of coins in this dropdown menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Cryptocurrency Listing Type Chose from Over 1500 Coins.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Choosing from over 1500 cryptocurrencies&quot; title=&quot;Choosing from over 1,500 cryptocurrencies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, there are no fees to pay and no accounts to sign up for. It’s a direct swap of cryptocurrencies between you and the other party, and if you choose a moderated payment (highly recommended) then there’s a third party available in case of dispute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to buy or sell coins without fees or without signing up for an account, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/download/&quot;&gt;give OpenBazaar a try&lt;/a&gt; and let us know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;release-notes&quot;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a minor release, focused on adding improvements to cryptocurrency listings, such as the ability to set their price above or below the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features&quot;&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ability to adjust the price of a cryptocurrency listing by a percentage relative to the market is now available. #1416, #1438&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A view on web feature was added to several screens. This provides a link to the same data on openbazaar.com. #1403, #1413, #1430, #1441&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements&quot;&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The name of each address in the settings modal is now bold. #1459&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The order of the items in the nav menu was adjusted, and your name is now clickable. #1459&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New details were added to the opt-in metrics. #1440, #1446&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The trumbowyg text editor will now be translated if it has the required language files. #1436&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moderators that don’t use the same cryptocurrency as the user cannot be added as a moderator. If they were already added, they will be marked as invalid so they can be removed. #1420&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non-translated text is now translated. #1392, #1382, #1435&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When a cryptocurrency order is fulfilled, the tx sent by the seller can be clicked if it is a URL. If HTML is included in the data, the HTML is removed. The data is validated to not be more than 512 characters. #1386, #1396, #1397&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A script to download and implement new cryptocurrency data for cryptocurrency listings was implemented. This is run manually before each release. #1384, #1422, #1423, #1429, #1479&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot;&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A rare problem where the debug log can have an error has been corrected. #1480&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new node will now have a default value of 0 for their reviews instead of showing an error. #1477&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A bug preventing a user from looking at their own moderator details modal has been fixed. #1473&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The memo in a purchase will no longer be cleared on a screen rerender. #1467&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When an order times out, but has not been fulfilled, when the seller claims the payment the buyer will no longer be told they can complete the order. #1463&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A potential race condition in the order details screen was corrected. #1452&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some minor issues with disputes when only one party’s contract has been received by the moderator were cleaned up. #1448&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BCH QR codes will not always have the proper prefix. #1418&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A problem with the shipping option selection resetting when interacting with the purchase page was corrected. #1402, #1442, #1447&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An issue with the free shipping tag not being horizontally aligned in the store screen was fixed. #1385&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;internationalization&quot;&gt;Internationalization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are actively translating the text in the OpenBazaar reference client. If you are interested in volunteering as a translator, you can sign up at https://www.transifex.com/ob1/openbazaar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A special thank you goes out to the many volunteers that provide translations, contributor rhcastilhos, and to our testers that discovered important issues.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OpenBazaar version 2.2.2 was just released, and this update gives users several new improvements to the cryptocurrency trading feature. This release also includes other improvements and bug fixes; for full details read the release notes posted below.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Freedom To Trade Means Freedom To Choose Currencies: The OpenBazaar Multiwallet</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Freedom-To-Trade-Means-Freedom-To-Choose-Currencies-The-OpenBazaar-Multiwallet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Freedom To &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Trade&lt;/span&gt; Means Freedom To &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Choose Currencies:&lt;/span&gt; The OpenBazaar Multiwallet" /><published>2018-07-25T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-25T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/Freedom-To-Trade-Means-Freedom-To-Choose-Currencies-The-OpenBazaar-Multiwallet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Freedom-To-Trade-Means-Freedom-To-Choose-Currencies-The-OpenBazaar-Multiwallet/">&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is the most free marketplace available on the planet. That freedom implies choice: the right to choose who to trade with, to choose how to protect your purchase, or to choose the visibility of your listings. That freedom should also extend to your choice of currency. And more than that! For your choice to be independent of any one developer’s motives, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io&quot;&gt;OB1&lt;/a&gt;. This is the first of two posts which share the motivation and direction our team will take as we explore how to make OpenBazaar work with any currency users choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-the-wallet&quot;&gt;Why The Wallet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right around the time &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-20-is-live/&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar 2.0 launched&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; – the default payment option of OpenBazaar at the time – was experiencing high transaction volume lasting several months resulting in network congestion and a poor user experience. All of this created significant friction during a small window where many first impressions would be established. With the landscape of growing alternative cryptocurrencies simultaneously booming around Bitcoin’s shortcomings, it punctuated the need for a choice in payment inside OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;seeking-currency-nirvana&quot;&gt;Seeking Currency Nirvana&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making OpenBazaar capable of trading with multiple simultaneous currencies affects many aspects of the application: the &lt;strong&gt;Seller&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Moderator&lt;/strong&gt; both have concerns for the types of currencies they can accept on the network; the &lt;strong&gt;Buyer&lt;/strong&gt; has concerns in the refund scenarios; the &lt;strong&gt;Wallet&lt;/strong&gt; implementation manipulates the state of the ledger with the current currency’s representation in mind; there are concerns for the protocol in how certain listings shall be validated; and many screens of interface which need to be reconsidered. With lot of ground to cover, we needed a solution in user’s hands with the least development effort required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solution was devised that many wallet implementations (along with their respective currency’s representations) would be provided along with the application and the user would be able to select one on startup. The additional options for currency usage would include &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt; and would make the application’s active currency interchangeable while touching very few of the related details. A seamless experience for the user with just a restart between each currency in use. Only a few screens in the interface would need a change to represent the currently active currency. The server would allow each configuration to be maintained side-by-side facilitating the simple switching from one currency to another without needing to break any of the previously made design decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January 2018, OB1 released &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-21-released-bitcoin-cash-and-zcash-integrated/&quot;&gt;version 2.1&lt;/a&gt;. This release was a half-step which allowed our team to quickly respond to the unexpected market conditions, but it also created many new challenges. The release proved that the option of other currencies were welcome and being requested on the network. At the time of publishing this article, 12% of crawlable listings have selected Bitcoin Cash as the accepted currency. But it also educated us on the limitations of adopting third-party wallets as we attempted to support multiple contributions; each presenting their own technical and social challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Setting-Up-a-New-Server-Node-Wallet-on-OpenBazaar-1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Setting Up a New Server Node Wallet on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Setting Up a New Server Node Wallet on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the OpenBazaar wallet was designed, we assumed quite a few time-saving details. The biggest of these assumptions was that Bitcoin would be the only currency in use. This, of course, had side-effects in our design such as a ledger which only tracks UTXO-based currencies as well as displaying values in other currencies from values represented in Bitcoin. We also made the assumption that users would prefer wallets which could independently verify their own transactions as a matter of ensuring the user need not trust the protocol or even the UI. As such, our wallet implementations default to using &lt;strong&gt;Simple Payment Verification (SPV)&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure the user’s own transactions are highly unlikely to be invalid with the option for users to operate full Bitcoin or Bitcoin Cash nodes if they preferred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these design decisions needed reconsideration. The maturing mobile experience which the OB1 team was exploring in the background needed a better solution and the existing 2.0 desktop experience was certainly ready to see a simpler interface when using multiple currencies. The existing answer would have lead toward running an SPV wallet (or full node) for each currency simultaneously, but would not scale in resource-constrained environments such as mobile and older-generation computers. OB1 is also integrating Ethereum as a currency for trade on the network and this has highlighted limitations in our UTXO-based ledger and wallet interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;formalizing-the-multiwallet&quot;&gt;Formalizing the Multiwallet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needing to make a decision with some urgency, internal discussion landed us on a solution in pursuit of an API backend driving interactions on the blockchain. Each API would handle the concerns for handling their respective currency’s blockchain which would reduce the responsibility of the OB1 team in maintaining currency-specific logic. Users would no longer need to provide the computing resources for transacting on the currency’s blockchain at the expense of the API operator (currently OB1, but more on this later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The APIs of the existing currencies that we already support abstract nicely into our existing wallet-interface with a minor change of adding an additional dimension to a few of the requests (so the wallet knows to which currency’s blockchain a transaction should be applied). With only very minor technical concerns that seemed solvable, the biggest obstacle was that we were sacrificing the user’s default expectation that they can trustlessly engage with their built-in wallet without any other alternatives. Still an imperfect solution for the security-conscious, but a good next step toward supporting multiple simultaneous currencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;openbazaar-multiwallet-design.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar Multi Wallet Design&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar Multi Wallet Design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&quot;want-to-see-more-click-here-for-an-interactive-demo&quot;&gt;Want to see more? Click &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.invisionapp.com/share/5XMZC8DT8HM#/screens/308962050_Openbazaar-2-0-Wallet&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for an interactive demo!&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect that different use cases will change the user’s expectations of the wallet. For example, a vendor might care more about the verifiability of their transactions than a buyer, and a mobile user may prefer to utilize an API-based wallet to save on limited device resources. It would be difficult to build the ideal wallet for all of our users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, the OB1 team is committed to seeing OpenBazaar as a protocol of trade which is agnostic of the currency it uses for trade. Any time invested into wallet maintenance is only distracting us from our goals. This was made painfully obvious by the questions raised when the third-party wallet contributions began rolling in. It was unclear who would provide a fix when a bug compromises funds in a user’s wallet. Or decide when a wallet implementation was valuable enough to offer as an option. Nor did we want to be the ones conjuring arbitrary rules for approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the obvious question was asked: How could we offer the choice of currency and wallet directly to the user? More on that in an upcoming post!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OpenBazaar is the most free marketplace available on the planet. That freedom implies choice: the right to choose who to trade with, to choose how to protect your purchase, or to choose the visibility of your listings. That freedom should also extend to your choice of currency. And more than that! For your choice to be independent of any one developer’s motives, including OB1. This is the first of two posts which share the motivation and direction our team will take as we explore how to make OpenBazaar work with any currency users choose.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar Developer Call - July 19, 2018</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-July-19-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar Developer Call - July 19, 2018" /><published>2018-07-19T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-19T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-July-19-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-July-19-2018/">&lt;p&gt;This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on July 19, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to join the call in real time? Sign up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/developers&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yuYRcmdPoDI&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on July 19, 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zcon0 Recap - A 3-Day Look at the Zcash Community and the Future of OpenBazaar Governance</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/zcon0-recap-a-3-day-look-at-the-zcash-community-and-the-future-of-openbazaar-governance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zcon0 Recap - A 3-Day Look at the &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Zcash Community&lt;/span&gt; and the Future of OpenBazaar Governance" /><published>2018-07-13T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-13T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/zcon0-recap-a-3-day-look-at-the-zcash-community-and-the-future-of-openbazaar-governance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/zcon0-recap-a-3-day-look-at-the-zcash-community-and-the-future-of-openbazaar-governance/">&lt;p&gt;The Zcash Foundation held their first major conference since inception, called Zcon0, in Montreal at the end of June. I was able to attend and wanted to briefly give my own recap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zcash is one of the three cryptocurrencies that are currently accepted inside OpenBazaar. Their focus on financial privacy aligns with the goals of OpenBazaar as a platform where people can choose how private they want their transactions to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zcash Foundation is a relatively young organization, formed to take a leadership role in the Zcash community which has primarily been guided by the Zcash Company. OpenBazaar and OB1 are in a similar situation, where the OB1 company has been leading development on OpenBazaar for years, and we’re now looking to create an OpenBazaar Foundation to move stewardship of the project into a more community-focused nonprofit organization. Part of my interest in attending Zcon0 was to see a community going through an organizational change and see what issues presented themselves and what I could learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first trip to Montreal. Everyone says it’s a beautiful city, and they’re right. I arrived the day before the conference and visited Mont Royal, a large hill with a park and a stunning view of the city. My phone’s camera doesn’t quite do it justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;montroyal.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mont Royal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The director of the Foundation, Josh Cincinnati, was unable to attend for family reasons, but he kicked off the conference with a humorous and thoughtful pre-recorded message (and several of these were presented throughout the conference) welcoming us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zooko spoke next, discussing the general state of Zcash and the company, as well as diving into financial details. I was surprised at how open he was with these details. It set the tone of being honest and open with each other about how things really stood in the Zcash community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other speakers gave a history of how Zcash came to exist, and then discussed where it was going, with special emphasis on the next big update (named Sapling) coming in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most valuable presentation that morning was “Using Zcash” by Linda Naeun Lee. She was tasked with trying to buy things with Zcash and reporting on her experience. Though she has a computer science background, she wasn’t familiar with the world of cryptocurrency, and she found it a very confusing experience. Zcash simply doesn’t have good wallets, nor does it have good places to spend the coins either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Linda did take some time to explain one positive experience she had spending Zcash: on OpenBazaar! She explained how she used OpenBazaar to buy a tshirt for someone in Venezuela with Zcash. I was glad to see OpenBazaar working for its intended purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon was workshops. We got to choose which workshops we attended, and I chose ones on improving user experience and how to achieve wallet scalability. I was able to contribute some thoughts on the UX discussion based on my experience with OpenBazaar, but mostly listened to much more technically knowledgeable people in the wallet scalability discussion. The workshops were intended for the leaders of the sessions to come away from them with new ideas or poll the groups for their opinions on specific issues; I’m not sure they achieved those goals in such a relatively short period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second day was focused on the technical side of Zcash development. I’m not a developer, and while I’m fairly knowledgeable about how Bitcoin is designed, how distributed networks work, and with the rudimentary basics of cryptography, the majority of these presentations were beyond my grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ZK-SNARKS are interesting - as best I can understand them! - and I appreciated that they also had presentations from other similar efforts, such as the Coda Protocol and Bulletproofs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This day was mostly me following presentations for the first ten minutes and then losing the speakers entirely when they started discussing the math or code. Still, I got a general sense for who was working on what, and why they were doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night there was a “Gala Dinner” for attendees. Zooko and Matthew Green had an informal chat with each other on stage while the audience tossed out some conversation ideas. It was a nice idea, but the conversation was unfocused and largely consisted of off-the-cuff personal opinions instead of well-considered thoughts on issues people wanted to hear discussed. But with good food and good company everyone seemed to be having a good time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3&quot;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This day was devoted to governance, the issue I was most interested in, and I’m glad they took the time to focus on it. They were looking to fill two board seats in the foundation and they explained the voting process they used and their rationale for their approach. The results of the voting were revealed, and it wasn’t only for the board seats, they also asked community members questions about direction of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few members of the group questioned whether or not this voting system was truly representative of the Zcash community as a whole. It was acknowledged that the system wasn’t ideal, but that it was better than the known alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eric Meltzer briefly spoke and proposed creating an investment fund from the founder’s reward. The presentation itself wasn’t particularly notable, but his idea was proposed in the Zcash forums as well, and the thread was soon locked by a Zcash company employee, creating some drama in the community over the past few weeks. It seems like most people are against changing the founder’s reward, but they also are against the Zcash Company controlling the platforms where people discuss these ideas. I believe efforts are underway to transition these forums’ moderation to the Zcash Foundation now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A speaker gave an illuminating overview of where the foundation had given out grants the year before, and where it was looking to give out grants in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning session ended with a panel on governance with Peter Van Valkenburgh, Jill Carlson, Zooko Wilcox, Jameson Lopp, and Vitalik Buterin. There were some disagreements on what proper governance entailed, with Jameson favoring a more anarchic position like Bitcoin. Zooko spoke of his concept of consent, which wasn’t perfectly clear to me; it sounded essentially like “take it or leave it” and everyone voting with their feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference wrapped up, and I Ieft Montreal with a better understanding of Zcash from several perspectives: historical, technical,  and communal, as well as a better idea of what they hope it can become moving forward. I was encouraged to see people thinking deeply about the differences between the company and nonprofit organizations and what roles they should be playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to watch some of the presentations from Zcon0, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL40dyJ0UYTLK507afWUMgzUYeh-i4qQWS&quot;&gt;this playlist&lt;/a&gt; on Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciate the opportunity to attend and I plan on attending next year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Zcash Foundation held their first major conference since inception, called Zcon0, in Montreal at the end of June. I was able to attend and wanted to briefly give my own recap.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Difference Between Cryptocurrency Payments and Cryptocurrency Trading in OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/the-difference-between-cryptocurrency-payments-and-cryptocurrency-trading-in-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Difference Between &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Cryptocurrency Payments&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Cryptocurrency Trading&lt;/span&gt; in OpenBazaar" /><published>2018-06-23T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-23T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/the-difference-between-cryptocurrency-payments-and-cryptocurrency-trading-in-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/the-difference-between-cryptocurrency-payments-and-cryptocurrency-trading-in-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrencies are very exciting to us, which we think we’ve made pretty apparent. We did, after all, build the &lt;strong&gt;world’s first fully decentralized marketplace&lt;/strong&gt; to help cryptocurrency users find each other and buy and sell goods and services anywhere in the world using this groundbreaking new kind of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While the “currency” part of cryptocurrency is particularly important to us, there are quite a few things other you can do with this technology, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important attribute they have is how they store and move value even when not measured against things like physical items or government-controlled currencies. With OpenBazaar we’ve been working hard to help users to do more things with the cryptocurrencies they love which now includes &lt;strong&gt;trading coins&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;buying things&lt;/strong&gt;, both completely peer-to-peer. These two particular features are distinct though and we wanted to tell you a bit more about how they work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Setting-Up-a-New-Server-Node-Wallet-on-OpenBazaar-1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Setting Up a New Server Node Wallet on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Setting Up a New Server Node Wallet on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cryptocurrency-payments-in-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency Payments in OpenBazaar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, sending and receiving payments for listings in OpenBazaar can be done with &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash/&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt; (this integration is in Beta). These payments require that both the buyer and seller have wallets running the same coin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can &lt;strong&gt;choose which of these 3 coins&lt;/strong&gt; they would like to run when they first set up their profile and/or store. If they would like to add additional coins they can easily set up additional profiles/stores to do so that are easy to switch between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-up-a-new-server-node-wallet-on-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Setting Up a New Server Node Wallet on OpenBazaar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can also choose to add funds to their OpenBazaar wallets using any other coin they may have in an external wallet as enabled by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://shapeshift.io/&quot;&gt;Shapeshift&lt;/a&gt; Shifty Button integration. The coins will change and resolve to whichever of the 3 integrated coins the wallet is set to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the development side, integrating additional coins for payments like these 3 coins are is complicated to add and maintain with the current infrastructure. OpenBazaar requires that coins have certain technical attributes to be compatible with the checkout flow, they must have their own separate wallets within OpenBazaar, and users must run separate OpenBazaar nodes in order to support them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While we’ve made it easy to set up &amp;amp; toggle between different nodes running these different coins, we know this setup is far from ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-is-it-set-up-this-way&quot;&gt;Why is it set up this way?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This setup is the result of a choice we made to bridge a gap that opened up with Bitcoin when network transaction fees jumped very high at the end of 2017. We integrated Bitcoin Cash and Zcash quickly because of their technical similarity to Bitcoin, their supportive community and the ease of their implementation just to give users a couple more payment options that could allow them to circumvent these high fees if they wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plans now are to phase the network into a more inclusive structure starting with first &lt;strong&gt;combining these 3 payment coins into just one wallet&lt;/strong&gt;. This &lt;strong&gt;multicoin wallet&lt;/strong&gt; will allow users to easily use multiple coins at once rather than in separate nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long term goal is to expand the interface allow for any individual user to easily decide and set up whatever payment coins they would like to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cryptocurrency-trading-in-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency Trading in OpenBazaar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency trading is a completely separate feature from the payment coins available in OpenBazaar. It’s enabled by a custom listing type that makes it easy for users to list and search for they coins they want to sell and buy. Users can buy and sell a variety of other coins but again, right now, they must use Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash or Zcash for the actual payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Setting-up-a-cryptocurrency-listing-on-OpenBazaar.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Setting Up a Cryptocurrency Listing for Sale on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Setting Up a Cryptocurrency Listing for Sale on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now OpenBazaar uses third parties to pull in token information for our cryptocurrency trading. We started with &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoinaverage.com/&quot;&gt;BitcoinAverage&lt;/a&gt; which provides 44 different coins users can list. Soon we will also be adding &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/&quot;&gt;CoinMarketCap&lt;/a&gt;’s index which will shoot the available coins up to over 1,500. All coins available on these two platforms will also be available in OpenBazaar for trading. In the future we will also be able to add individual coins and we will soon be sharing a process for getting your coin listed if it is not already available through these providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Cryptocurrency-Trading-on-OpenBazaar-Home-Page.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cryptocurrency Trading on The OpenBazaar.com Home Page&quot; title=&quot;Cryptocurrency Trading on The OpenBazaar.com Home Page&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;See how it works on OpenBazaar.com!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’re an expert in the existing structure of payment coins vs. trading coins, perhaps you’d be interested in what our development team is doing next with &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2tynK31&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ready put your cryptocurrencies to work, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/download&quot;&gt;download OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt; now!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Cryptocurrencies are very exciting to us, which we think we’ve made pretty apparent. We did, after all, build the world’s first fully decentralized marketplace to help cryptocurrency users find each other and buy and sell goods and services anywhere in the world using this groundbreaking new kind of money.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Does Toronto Have a Great Crypto Community – or The GREATEST Crypto Community?</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/does-toronto-have-a-great-crypto-community-or-the-greatest-crypto-community/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Does Toronto Have a Great Crypto Community – or &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;The GREATEST &lt;/span&gt; Crypto Community?" /><published>2018-06-15T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-15T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/does-toronto-have-a-great-crypto-community-or-the-greatest-crypto-community</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/does-toronto-have-a-great-crypto-community-or-the-greatest-crypto-community/">&lt;p&gt;OB1 CEO and OpenBazaar Project Lead Brian Hoffman and I (OB1/OpenBazaar Marketing and Community Manager, Jenn Cloud), were pleased to spend some time last week with the excellent crypto community in Toronto, Ontario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a great idea from our Series A leading investor, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omersventures.com/&quot;&gt;OMERS Ventures&lt;/a&gt;, we hosted an OpenBazaar meetup on Wednesday night at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.art-square.ca/&quot;&gt;Art Square Gallery&lt;/a&gt; across from the Art Gallery of Ontario in the heart of downtown Toronto. We had almost 130 people register for the event and over 70 showed up and packed the space to standing room only!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OB1 CEO Brian Hoffman and Toronto Crypto Community.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar Meetup - June 6 2018 - Toronto&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian presented a brief history of OpenBazaar (did you know that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbazaar.org/about/&quot;&gt;original codebase&lt;/a&gt; that was forked to become OpenBazaar was produced in Toronto?), shared the latest feature releases which are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/blog/cryptocurrency-trading-now-available-on-openbazaar/&quot;&gt;cryptocurrency trading&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://openbazaar.com/&quot;&gt;web browsing&lt;/a&gt;, and discussed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2018-roadmap/&quot;&gt;future plans&lt;/a&gt; for the network. There was a great question and answer session at the end, people were very interested in the governance structures of the network and our upcoming token release, about which we know we’ve been quiet, but we will have more to share very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a pro tip for when there is an OpenBazaar event near you: we gave out 3 deluxe swag bags to 3 attendees who had either bought or sold something on the marketplace so make sure you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/download/&quot;&gt;check it out for yourself&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Fab Toronto event w/ &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brianchoffman?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@brianchoffman&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@openbazaar&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wmougayar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@wmougayar&lt;/a&gt;, diving into the case for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/decentralized?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#decentralized&lt;/a&gt; marketplaces&lt;br /&gt;- Censorship resistant p2p network&lt;br /&gt;- Marketplace &amp;amp; rules controlled by users&lt;br /&gt;- Privacy &amp;amp; no middlemen&lt;br /&gt;- Community driven innovation &amp;amp; network growth&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/crypto?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#crypto&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/7YhQIAI1D7&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/7YhQIAI1D7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mags (@Crypto_Mags) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Crypto_Mags/status/1004558004581122048?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 7, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Mags for this great tweet! I had the opportunity to meet her and so many great, SMART people including but not at all limited to Ibrahim, Ana, Mike, Brad, John, OpenBazaar vendor Sanda and a couple from Brazil, Michael and Samara, who helped with the Portuguese translation of OpenBazaar. They even had a photo of the postcard I hand wrote and sent to them with their thank you t-shirts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event wouldn’t have been possible without the help of Lukas Royal and his team who located and secured an event space in record time near the OMERS office, set up the event on Meetup and established a Telegram group for community discussion. Special thanks also goes to one of our investors, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wmougayar&quot;&gt;William Mougayar&lt;/a&gt;, who shared this event with his network and created a spike of RSVPs. You all are wonderful and we thank you so much for your support and really making this event a success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in hosting an OpenBazaar event near you? Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/meet&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OB1 CEO and OpenBazaar Project Lead Brian Hoffman and I (OB1/OpenBazaar Marketing and Community Manager, Jenn Cloud), were pleased to spend some time last week with the excellent crypto community in Toronto, Ontario.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Valuing Privacy &amp;amp; still Getting Data from a Decentralized Network</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/gathering-stats-how-to-value-privacy-and-still-get-data-from-a-decentralized-network/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Valuing Privacy &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;&amp; still Getting Data&lt;/span&gt; from a Decentralized Network" /><published>2018-05-30T03:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T03:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/gathering-stats-how-to-value-privacy-and-still-get-data-from-a-decentralized-network</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/gathering-stats-how-to-value-privacy-and-still-get-data-from-a-decentralized-network/">&lt;p&gt;Facebook knows exactly how many users are on their platform. Amazon knows exactly how many products are sold. Instagram knows exactly how many photos are shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, no one knows how many people use Bitcoin. No one knows how many files have been shared over Bittorrent. No one knows how many trades happen on OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why can some networks give precise statistics about how they’re being used, while others can only give estimations or have no data at all? It comes down to the architecture of the networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centralized Networks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you build a centralized network – and you control the center of the network – you then have access to information about everything that is happening. Centralized systems require all users to connect to a central point of control, and whoever sits at point of control is able to monitor and collect as much data as they please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Centralized-network.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Centralized network with central point of control&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most platforms on the internet today are centralized, and the central point of control is managed by a company. This is how Facebook, Amazon, and most platforms operate. Those companies sit in the center and collect as much information as they can about their users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the positive side, this allows them to have precise statistics and answer specific questions about how their platform is being used, which makes it easier for them to improve and satisfy users’ needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the negative side, it means the users on centralized platforms have no privacy from whoever manages the central point of control, and they don’t always use the data they gather just to improve their platform. They sometimes sell the data to others, or even lose the data if someone breaks into the databases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributed networks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed networks are fundamentally different from centralized networks. There is no central point of control in a distributed network. All users in the network are equal to other users, and users connect directly to each other. Each user is running software on their computer which connects them to the network, and that computer is called a “node” in the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few platforms on the internet today are distributed, but they are growing in number. Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies are distributed networks. OpenBazaar is distributed, as is Bittorrent. No one can sit in the center and collect information about users on these networks; there is no center at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Decentralized-network.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Distributed network with no center&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the positive side, this means that users have much more privacy on distributed networks. They aren’t required to connect and share information with a central point of control. They connect directly to other peers and exchange information directly, without necessarily informing others on the network about what they’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the negative side, this makes collecting statistics very difficult, which makes development more difficult. Those building the platform cannot see how users are using their product, and must seek other methods to know how best to improve the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Do Nodes Work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individual users set up and control their own nodes, generally from their own personal computers. They have to allow incoming and outgoing connections to participate in the network and connecting to other nodes takes some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the difficulties in collecting stats from distributed networks is the fact that most nodes on the network will only connect to a handful of peers at a time. If the network has 1,500 nodes running, each individual node might only be connected to eight or ten other nodes, meaning they only see a small fraction of the overall network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that getting an overview of the entire network is difficult, and requires lots of nodes that are connected to different peers. Or it requires a method to “crawl” through the network and look at the state over time and not as a single snapshot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;conectivity.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazar is a Peer to Peer Decentralized Network that Connects Individuals to Each Other across a Network&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed networks also present another difficulty in stats gathering: churn. Nodes can join and leave the network at any time because users can set up or delete their stores at any time. In centralized systems people joining and leaving is simple to notice, since they are either communicating with the central point of control or they aren’t. In distributed networks you don’t see all other nodes simultaneously and won’t know what’s happening on another part of the network. Even if you were able to perfectly capture the state of the network at one moment, it will likely change in the next moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is further complicated by distributed networks that don’t require nodes to be running 24/7, such as OpenBazaar (built on IPFS). This is a good thing and was a major feature built into the version 2.0 release  so that sellers’ stores are still accessible and buyers’ orders can still be processed even if the seller is technically offline, but it complicates the stats. Any attempt at gathering information about the state of the network by looking at &lt;em&gt;online nodes&lt;/em&gt; only will be missing the fact that these offline users are still a part of the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenBazaar Usage &amp;amp; Stats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can partially answer some questions about the OpenBazaar network with indirect data. For example, while we don’t know how many trades occur, we can see when a user leaves a review on a completed purchase. This gives us a very broad range to make estimations from, but is imprecise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We try to ascertain node count (the number of computers running the OpenBazaar software), but for the reasons noted above this is difficult. We can only see the number of nodes online and accepting incoming connections (users who have port forwarded), which is a small subset of overall OpenBazaar users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a limitation from the developer’s perspective, but it’s a feature from the user’s perspective. We built OpenBazaar to be private and it should remain so for people who value their privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opt-in Stats Gathering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe we’ve figured out a way to retain the privacy of OpenBazaar users while still allowing for relevant stats gathering to aid development. In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/blog/cryptocurrency-trading-now-available-on-openbazaar/&quot;&gt;2.2.0 release&lt;/a&gt; we introduced an opt-in stats gathering feature. Users are asked when they start the app if they’d like to share anonymous statistics with the OpenBazaar development team, and a list of the data shared is displayed. If users decline then no information is shared. If they accept then only the data that’s displayed will be shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Screenshot-from-2018-05-29-12-14-24.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data has already been helpful to the developers and over time will help us answer many questions that would have been impossible otherwise, due to OpenBazaar’s distributed design. Here are a few numbers we have been able to see over the last couple of weeks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Over 1,600 opt-ins since launch – Roughly 15% of users running version 2.2.0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Of this segment who opted in, visitors from 103 countries have driven over 4,500 sessions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;English is the language chosen by 68% of users who opted in; Russian, German and Spanish are all at 6% each&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is a network that exists for its users and is run by its users. In this marketplace, buyers &amp;amp; sellers have greater control over their experience than in any other marketplace on the planet. We want to know how to make it the best it can be for you–without stepping on your toes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Help us all make OpenBazaar better and drive forward the capabilities of decentralized platforms by opting into sharing anonymized usage stats.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download it now by clicking &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/download&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Facebook knows exactly how many users are on their platform. Amazon knows exactly how many products are sold. Instagram knows exactly how many photos are shared.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Do Moderators &amp;amp; Moderated Payments Do on OpenBazaar?</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/what-do-moderators-&-moderated-payments-do-on-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Do Moderators &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;&amp; Moderated Payments&lt;/span&gt; Do on OpenBazaar?" /><published>2018-05-17T03:49:16+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-17T03:49:16+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/what-do-moderators-&amp;-moderated-payments-do-on-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/what-do-moderators-&amp;-moderated-payments-do-on-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;Decentralizing ecommerce is an important part of the future we believe in. We are working to build a world with greater access to global commerce and more opportunities for people everywhere to build the lives they want. We believe this is made possible with decentralized money like Bitcoin and decentralized marketplaces like OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a big vision. Much of the work we are doing right now is largely untangling some of the technological and psychological knots the infrastructure and assumptions of the last 20 years have made for us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first and biggest knots we knew had to be untangled for a decentralized marketplace like OpenBazaar to be feasible was a pretty basic service other marketplaces and storefronts have historically provided: &lt;strong&gt;dispute resolution&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Think about it: in a decentralized network that’s made only of the individual people that participate in it, and transactions exist only between the people engaged in them, what happens when something goes wrong with an order?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payments in OpenBazaar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a bit of background, OpenBazaar currently uses 3 different cryptocurrency payment types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Direct&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moderated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, if a buyer trusts a seller they can just send their coins directly to them in a direct payment. If the seller is offline at the time of payment, that creates a slightly different payment type where they just have to claim their coins when they return to their store. (You can read more details about each of these payment types &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360000303371-What-are-the-different-payment-types-in-OpenBazaar-&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there are moderated payments, which is what a buyer can use to send coins to a vendor they do not yet know or trust or to provide an extra layer of security for higher cost transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a moderated payment?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderated payments are an important part of the OpenBazaar checkout experience and something that we believe is a valuable application of a unique feature that Bitcoin and related cryptocurrencies have: multisignature (multisig) addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multisig addresses work like an escrow account between a buyer and a seller by pulling an objective third party into the checkout process, called a moderator. These addresses require 2 of these 3 parties to agree in order to release the coins at the end of a transaction. Typically transactions just go smoothly between buyers and sellers and a moderator’s help isn’t ever needed, but it sure is nice to know they are there just in case! If something does go wrong, moderators will help figure out who gets the payment coins when the buyer or seller opens a dispute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;moderated.png&quot; alt=&quot;Moderated payment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a moderator?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, a decentralized marketplace means that the entire platform is made up only of people connecting to other people with no large organizations sitting in the middle to dictate how anyone uses the platform–nor step in to provide things like dispute resolution. In a decentralized network, the individual users are each responsible for their own experiences which includes contributing positively to the community by building their business and reputation as well as protecting themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a buyer or a seller, a moderator is also just another type of user on the OpenBazaar network. Anyone can choose to become one and make their services as a moderator available on the network. And as you may know, since it’s pretty easy to get started on the OpenBazaar network, figuring out which users are more likely to be trustworthy requires a little scrutiny, first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I pick a good moderator?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer or seller, it’s important to choose a trustworthy moderator to add to your transactions if you are choosing a moderated payment. Here are some tips for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-choose-a-good-moderator-on-openbazaar/&quot;&gt;choosing a good moderator&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io/&quot;&gt;OB1&lt;/a&gt;, the company leading the development of OpenBazaar, now has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io/verified-moderators.html&quot;&gt;Verified Moderators program&lt;/a&gt; that is integrated into OpenBazaar to help users find someone that OB1 has reviewed who has shown themselves more likely to be trustworthy when helping settle disputes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vLn9dQu9Zp0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it’s always good to check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbazaar.org/scam-prevention/&quot;&gt;these scam prevention tips&lt;/a&gt; to help you stay safe and smart when buying and selling on OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose your own adventure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of choices involved in using OpenBazaar, and that’s on purpose. We know it is different from what you may be used to but we are building a marketplace where each user gets to be in control of their own experience with more features and opportunities being built all the time. To see some of the other things the OB1 team is working on to make OpenBazaar the most accessible and expandable ecommerce marketplace on the planet, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2018-roadmap/&quot;&gt;2018 Roadmap&lt;/a&gt; and make sure to sign up for the &lt;a href=&quot;/newsletter/&quot;&gt;email newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to get the latest updates!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Decentralizing ecommerce is an important part of the future we believe in. We are working to build a world with greater access to global commerce and more opportunities for people everywhere to build the lives they want. We believe this is made possible with decentralized money like Bitcoin and decentralized marketplaces like OpenBazaar.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cryptocurrency Trading Now Available on OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/cryptocurrency-trading-now-available-on-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cryptocurrency Trading &lt;span class='post-title-extra-alternative'&gt;Now Available on OpenBazaar&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-05-13T03:49:16+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-13T03:49:16+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/cryptocurrency-trading-now-available-on-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/cryptocurrency-trading-now-available-on-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar &lt;strong&gt;version 2.2.0&lt;/strong&gt; was released today. For the full list of new features and improvements in this release, check out the release notes at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest new feature is the ability to ** buy and sell cryptocurrencies**.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cryptocurrency-trading-on-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrency Trading on OpenBazaar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/q6ki3_1Io-U&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vendors are now able to use a special new listing type to &lt;strong&gt;sell cryptocurrencies on OpenBazaar&lt;/strong&gt;. They can choose from 44 different cryptocurrencies right now and more will be added over time. Payment must be settled in whichever coin they have chosen for their OpenBazaar store, either Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, or Zcash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;cryptolistings.gif&quot; alt=&quot;crypto listings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because OpenBazaar is completely peer-to-peer, &lt;strong&gt;this is not an exchange&lt;/strong&gt;. This new feature doesn’t include an order book with the ability to choose a target price for buying or selling. This new feature only allows people to trade cryptocurrencies directly with each other at market prices. It benefits from OpenBazaar’s main advantages; users trading cryptocurrencies on the platform &lt;strong&gt;won’t need to pay any fees&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;they aren’t forced to reveal any identifying information&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve released this new feature with the goal of listening to the community about how they believe cryptocurrency trading on OpenBazaar can be improved. We plan to rapidly iterate as we receive feedback from users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to give us your thoughts on this new feature!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opt-in-analytics&quot;&gt;Opt-in Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because OpenBazaar has been built with privacy in mind, the development team isn’t able to gain much information about how people use the software. This is good for privacy, but can sometimes hinder development. In order to gain more insight on how OpenBazaar is being used – and how to improve it – we’re introducing an &lt;strong&gt;opt-in analytics package&lt;/strong&gt;. Users who choose to opt in will share non-identifying data with the development team. The list of data being shared is displayed when opening the new release for the first time. Users can start or stop sharing data at any time in their Settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;release-notes&quot;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a major release, which adds buying and selling cryptocurrencies, opt in analytics, and many optimizations and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features&quot;&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– The ability to buy and sell cryptocurrencies was added. The currencies can be sold at market rates. This feature is experimental, and is expected to be rapidly iterated on as we recieve feedback from users. #1308
– An opt-in analytics package was added. Users are able to choose to share non-identifying data with the development team. This will facilitate identifying bugs and improving the app. Users can start or stop sharing data at any time. #1277&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements&quot;&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Norweigan, Polish, and Ukranian translations reached the 80% translated requirement, and were added as options for the client. #1324&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When viewing your sales, unfunded orders will now be hidden by default, since you cannot take action on those orders, and they clutter up the list of orders. You can still chose to view those orders. #1310&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listing card image loads will now cancel when the image card is no longer on the screen. This primarily improves the experience when changing pages in the search results or navigating away from a page of search results that hasn’t finished loading. #1309&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verified moderators are now lazy-loaded. This will speed up startup, and notify the user if the list of verified moderators changes while they are looking at information that will be affected by that change. #1298&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verified moderators are loaded from a Tor endpoint if the user is in Tor mode. #1284&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot;&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blockdozer changed their URL for viewing BCH transactions, the URL used when viewing details of transactions has been updated. #1320&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An issue where the no valid moderators error would show on an error at the same time as the no verified moderators message, and with the wrong formatting, was corrected. #1307&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A problem where invalid mods would never stop loading was fixed. #1306&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Error messages meant for only the purchase flow no longer appear in the settings/store tab. #1306&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some layout issues with moderator cards were corrected. #1300&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the settings/store tab, if a moderator assigned to your store has become invalid, now the only option is to de-select them. #1300&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An unused memo parameter was removed from the purchase call. #1314&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A minor layout issue was corrected in the transactions list. #1285&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The bug where pages stats are changed to zero in the page tabs on the user page when the page settings are updated was fixed. #1287&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A layout issue with verified moderators was fixed. #1270&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store pages will now open if one of the listings in them has an unrecognized currency value. #1269&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;internationalization&quot;&gt;Internationalization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are actively translating the text in the OpenBazaar reference client. If you are interested in volunteering as a translator, you can sign up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.transifex.com/ob1/openbazaar&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special thank you goes out to the many volunteers that provide translations, and to our testers that discovered important issues.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OpenBazaar version 2.2.0 was released today. For the full list of new features and improvements in this release, check out the release notes at the end of the post.</summary></entry></feed>