<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://openbazaar.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://openbazaar.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-02T18:52:16+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">OpenBazaar</title><entry><title type="html">How to Sell Services for Cryptocurrency on OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-sell-services-for-cryptocurrency-on-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Sell Services for Cryptocurrency&lt;/span&gt; on OpenBazaar" /><published>2019-04-25T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-25T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-sell-services-for-cryptocurrency-on-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-sell-services-for-cryptocurrency-on-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;Making sales is about more than just moving physical products. People also make entire careers—and often very high level careers!—out of selling the services they perform. These can be things done from anywhere in the world like like web design, software development and copywriting, or very local things like medical assistance, legal representation and lawn care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.deloitte.com/insights/us/en/economy/issues-by-the-numbers/trade-in-services-economy-growth.html&quot;&gt;services make up almost 70% of value added to the world’s economy&lt;/a&gt;. This kind of market share shows an enormous opportunity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sell-your-services-online&quot;&gt;Sell Your Services Online&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar’s unique approach to an escrow account makes it easy for a provider to list and bill for their services. By setting up a moderated transaction a service seller can be sure that their client has the funds for contract they are agreeing to and upon successful completion of the work the funds can simply be released to the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On OpenBazaar you can easily sell services for cryptocurrency. Here’s how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-define-your-service&quot;&gt;1. Define your service&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What services do you sell? How do you usually price them? Many providers offer services by the hour or on a custom basis, but to list services for sale on OpenBazaar it’s easiest to start by “productizing” them, or structuring them to be constrained to a set cost. For example, if you provide language translation services you may create 3 different products with different prices. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100 - 200 words translated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;200 - 400 words translated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;400 - 600 words translated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-create-your-listings&quot;&gt;2. Create your listings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your services defined you can create listings for them on OpenBazaar. Create a &lt;strong&gt;new listing&lt;/strong&gt; and under &lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;, select “&lt;strong&gt;Service&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Sell_Services_for_Cryptocurrency_on_OpenBazaar.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Sell Services for Cryptocurrency on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Sell Services for Cryptocurrency on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a great &lt;strong&gt;title&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;description&lt;/strong&gt; that relates to keywords people may use in search that will help them find it easily. Make sure to describe exactly what a buyer will receive and consider adding more information such as examples of past work or testimonials to make the offer compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Include at least 1 great &lt;strong&gt;image&lt;/strong&gt; that describes your service such as a photo of you providing the service or an photo of the completed service with simple text overlaid, such as “500-700 Words Translated English to Chinese.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tags&lt;/strong&gt; can be added to boost the searchability of your item. Include obvious ones that relate to the item itself like “website design” or “manuscript editing,” then more as relates to broader categories it represents such as “business or “writing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;category&lt;/strong&gt; is to help keep your store organized. If you plan to sell both “software development” and “language translation,” you’d just type in the appropriate category for the appropriate listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variants&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;inventory&lt;/strong&gt; can likely be left blank. These are helpful for things like physical goods where you may offer the exact same shirt but in 3 different colors and you only have a certain number of each. If you have variations with your services it is generally a good approach to create separate listings for each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;strong&gt;return policy&lt;/strong&gt; you can set this up however you’d like. You may want to say no refunds or perhaps offer a 100% satisfaction guarantee with a full refund option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terms &amp;amp; conditions&lt;/strong&gt; can be added if you have any conditions or advisories you want to make people aware of when accessing or using your digital good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;coins&lt;/strong&gt; you’d like to receive as payment: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoincash.org&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://litecoin.org&quot;&gt;Litecoin&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt;. it can be just one of them or any combination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-share-your-services-from-openbazaarcom&quot;&gt;3. Share your services from OpenBazaar.com&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is a marketplace where people can browse and discover the items that you have for sale—but that’s not the only way they can find them! &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar.com&lt;/a&gt; exists to make it easy for you and others to share stores and listings to your social media and other communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your listing is live you can click “View on web” in the address bar at the top to see it and share it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;view_on_web_link_in_openbazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;View on Web Link in OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;View on Web Link in OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;more-than-a-marketplace&quot;&gt;More Than a Marketplace&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is still new and it is very niche because it exclusively uses cryptocurrency for payments. It needs every true believer’s help to grow into a phenomenon worldwide and that starts with our community. Make sure to connect with us to market your store and service listings and meet other like-minded people all around the world. Meet us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/OpenBazaarGroup&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;strong&gt;Want To Learn More about Selling Goods and Services on OpenBazaar?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
Check out these other posts that will help you get started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-seller-guide-what-to-expect-in-this-decentralized-marketplace/&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar Seller Guide - What To Expect in This Decentralized Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-market-your-store-and-listings-on-openbazaar/&quot;&gt;How To Market Your Store and Listings on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/5-tips-to-make-your-openbazaar-listings-pop/&quot;&gt;5 Tips To Make Your OpenBazaar Listings Pop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-sell-digital-goods-for-cryptocurrency-on-openbazaar/&quot;&gt;How to Sell Digital Goods for Cryptocurrency on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Making sales is about more than just moving physical products. People also make entire careers—and often very high level careers!—out of selling the services they perform. These can be things done from anywhere in the world like like web design, software development and copywriting, or very local things like medical assistance, legal representation and lawn care.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar Developer Call - April 11, 2019</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-April-11-2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar Developer Call - April 11, 2019" /><published>2019-04-12T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-April-11-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-April-11-2019/">&lt;p&gt;This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on April 11, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to join the call in real time? Sign up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/developers&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our ongoing conversations on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse OpenBazaar now at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2z1UZo5S7WU&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chat log:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:04]  mg (ob1): Good morning all, FYI we monitor and interact in the chat during the call. If you think of questions, feel free to post them here and we’ll get them answered. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:07] DiarioBitcoin.com: are the relay servers custom relay servers for the OB protocol, or are they generic protocol agnostic relay servers (TURN)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:10]  mg (ob1): The relay servers are specific to IPFS but are transport agnostic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:10]  mg (ob1): They were designed to ensure that if one transport were blocked, the IPFS relay could bridge across transports as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:11]  mg (ob1): More information: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ipfs/js-ipfs/tree/master/examples/circuit-relaying&quot;&gt;https://github.com/ipfs/js-ipfs/tree/master/examples/circuit-relaying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:11] DiarioBitcoin.com: thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:11] DiarioBitcoin.com: Q: when DAI support?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:12]  mg (ob1): We’ll get that one at the end. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:15]  mg (ob1): Thanks :) &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/samulator&quot;&gt;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/samulator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:20] Matt: what platform will tokens be based on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:20]  mg (ob1): ERC-20&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:20] Matt: you should consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Bitcoin-com/slp-sdk&quot;&gt;https://github.com/Bitcoin-com/slp-sdk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:21]  mg (ob1): We might depending on our initial token success. SLP was barely ready when we began work on the token development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:22] Rod: Has there been any news on the web buying/client side?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:22] DiarioBitcoin.com: thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:22] MatthewZipkin: Possible to start signing releases? And post dev public keys&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:24]  mg (ob1): Yes and on our radar in the near future. We do sign the commits but I don’t think those keys are public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:24]  mg (ob1): (but github.com verifies them, if you trust them)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:25] Rod: Thanks for the update 👍&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:25]  mg (ob1): I think we’d end up with something like signed checksums per release. If you have something specific in mind, LMK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:30]  mg (ob1): That’s a great update Rod! Thanks for sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:31] Matt: how will the import aliexpress thing prevent spoofing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:31] Rod: ^^ Appreciate it mg 😄&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:32] Matt: pretending to be a user on aliexpress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:32] Matt: yes thats what i mean&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:32] Matt: thanks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:33] John: Thank you for the updates&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on April 11, 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar 2.3.1 is Released with IPFS Rebase</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2-3-1-release-ipfs-rebase/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar 2.3.1 is Released &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;with IPFS Rebase&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2019-03-19T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-19T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2-3-1-release-ipfs-rebase</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2-3-1-release-ipfs-rebase/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;important-this-is-a-required-update&quot;&gt;IMPORTANT: This is a required update&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have tweaked how pricing is calculated to be better aware of currency conversions and changed how content is cached/retrieved as part of the IPFS update. Old nodes and new nodes will be unable to share content. We recommend that you &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/115002761312-How-do-I-backup-my-store-&quot;&gt;backup your OpenBazaar data&lt;/a&gt; before you update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar version 2.3.1 has &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-desktop/releases/tag/v2.3.1&quot;&gt;been released&lt;/a&gt; and was primarily focused on upgrading the underlying &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; library to 0.4.18. This release prepares the development team to enable some features which will improve message deliverability and discovery on the network. In addition to the IPFS update, we have several minor fixes and improvements which resolve some painful timing bugs and general code improvements and reorganizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;release-notes&quot;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a minor release, focused on an IPFS rebase in the go server. It is important to back up your store before running this update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release uses version 0.13.1 of the openbazaar-go server. You can view server changes at this link:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-go/releases/tag/v0.13.1&quot;&gt;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-go/releases/tag/v0.13.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A bulk coin accepted updater control was added in settings/store. This allows a seller to update all the coins accepted by all their listings at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blockbooth was removed from the list of default search providers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improvements were made in how moderators are loaded in the purchase screen, so the spinner doesn’t continue forever if one of them fails to load.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code was added to handle upcoming changes to the peerID format.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A few changes were made to the metrics collected.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some code clean up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When coping a contract in the order details screen, the JSON is now formatted nicely.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inputs are sanitized, to prevent any issues with a user entering invalid or harmful characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An adjustment was made to prevent security software from incorrectly flagging the OB update as malware.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A bug that caused the dispute resolve button to not appear in disputes using ZCash was fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the url is missing a protocol in the fulfillment of a digital order, it will now open correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An issue where the user page wouldn’t update the user’s name if it was changed was corrected.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A bug with the warning about external links showing when using Tor was fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minor fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internationalization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are actively translating the text in the OpenBazaar reference client. If you are interested in volunteering as a translator, you can sign up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.transifex.com/ob1/openbazaar&quot;&gt;https://www.transifex.com/ob1/openbazaar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Special Thanks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A special thank you goes out to the many volunteers that provide translations, and to our testers that discovered important issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more development details, please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-desktop/releases/tag/v2.3.1&quot;&gt;the release notes on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">IMPORTANT: This is a required update</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar Developer Call - March 14, 2019</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-March-14-2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar Developer Call - March 14, 2019" /><published>2019-03-18T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-18T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-March-14-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-March-14-2019/">&lt;p&gt;This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on March 14, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to join the call in real time? Sign up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/developers&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our ongoing conversations on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse OpenBazaar now at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mBPcpODsudk&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chat log:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:17] Rod: I would be 100% interested in the wallet-interface changes, which slack channel are you planning to give updates to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:18] mg (OB1): Sorry about audio… the public slack would either be #openbazaar-2_0 or a private payments channel that are invite only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:18] mg (OB1): We can hear your mic….random voice! :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:18] Sam - OB1: We can hear you cryptoshoppe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:18] Rod: Cryptoshoppe we can all hear you lol&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:18] Rod: :p&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:19] mg (OB1): Here is the wallet-interface pull requests: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/wallet-interface&quot;&gt;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/wallet-interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:19] CryptoShoppe: I can’t hear anyone else&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:19] mg (OB1): Here is a specific pull request in flight: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/wallet-interface/pull/13&quot;&gt;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/wallet-interface/pull/13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:19] mg (OB1): Cryptoshoppe, we do have your audio coming in. If you have a question, you can ask it and watch the stream later for your answer. :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:20] mg (OB1): Or ask it here?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:20] CryptoShoppe: what about resolved store url addresses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:20] mg (OB1): Like ob://customname?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:21] CryptoShoppe: instead of hashed addresses, which are hard to remember&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:21] CryptoShoppe: yeah like that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:21] mg (OB1): Can you hear audio yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:21] CryptoShoppe: no I can’t hear Sam speaking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:21] CryptoShoppe: fixed it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:22] mg (OB1): Okay great. We’ll get an answer for you in audio then. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:22] Rod: Thank you @mg for the links&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:23] mg (OB1): Of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:30] Rod: By chance has there been any work/research/talk on speeding up IPNS publishes ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:30] Tyler: Tiered routing should do that too&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:30] Tyler: it should speed up both reads and rights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:30] Tyler: writes*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:31] mg (OB1): Sam: CryptoShoppe asked “what about resolved store url addresses?” like ob://customname&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:37] mg (OB1): DID spec: &lt;a href=&quot;https://w3c-ccg.github.io/did-method-registry&quot;&gt;https://w3c-ccg.github.io/did-method-registry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:38] mg (OB1): I’m not certain what the IPFS team plans to do with this, but they are thinking about the problem, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:40] mg (OB1): Report from the Monero community about integration feasibility: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rbrunner7.github.io/openbazaar&quot;&gt;https://rbrunner7.github.io/openbazaar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:41] Rod: Are ERC-20 tokens going to be usable with the first ethereum wallet release w/OB?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:41] mg (OB1): ^^ the above report is completely independent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:42] Rod: Gotcha&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:43] Rod: Thanks for the clarification&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:46] BeautyBubble: Suggestion on the BBB meeting, can you please make certain that all links shared find a home here on SLACK.  Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:46] BeautyBubble: Yes.  This chat links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:47] John Tooker: Thank you all for the work you do&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:47] BeautyBubble: Thank you so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:47] Rod: Thanks Sam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:47] BeautyBubble: Assuming we just log out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:47] Sam - OB1: Yes :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:47] BeautyBubble: Okay, thank you guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:48] Sam - OB1: You’re welcome!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on March 14, 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Sell Digital Goods for Cryptocurrency on OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-sell-digital-goods-for-cryptocurrency-on-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Sell Digital Goods for Cryptocurrency&lt;/span&gt; on OpenBazaar" /><published>2019-03-14T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-14T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-sell-digital-goods-for-cryptocurrency-on-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-sell-digital-goods-for-cryptocurrency-on-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;When you think about the world’s largest internet marketplaces, what kind of products do you picture? Maybe you get your coffee or toilet paper or other daily sundries from Amazon or Alibaba. Maybe you buy secondhand or hard-to-find collectible items on Ebay. Maybe you visit Etsy for thoughtful handmade gifts. These sites do have a focus on physical goods but that’s not all they can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-may-blow-your-mind-so-proceed-with-caution&quot;&gt;This may blow your mind so proceed with caution.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do you buy your ebooks? Okay, maybe still Amazon or similar… What about music and movies? Oh, now we’re starting to get a little weird. What about online courses? Digital access codes? Video game codes? Data bundles like fonts or photo editing presets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online marketplaces aren’t all about physical goods. Digital goods are just as sellable as physical goods and there are many places where many people buy and sell them around the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On OpenBazaar you can easily sell digital goods for cryptocurrency. Here’s how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-file-hosting&quot;&gt;1. File Hosting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File hosting&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;automatic delivery&lt;/strong&gt; within OpenBazaar is a features we plan to build in the future but they are still on ice at the moment. In the meantime, if you are selling things like game codes or gift cards, you will have to send them manually to your buyers when you receive a payment. If you are selling a file that users will need to download, you will need to host it somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would love to recommend a decentralized file hosting solution but the most promising projects are still in an early release stage or pre-release. If you’d like to learn more about projects like &lt;a href=&quot;https://filecoin.io/&quot;&gt;Filecoin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://storj.io/&quot;&gt;Storj&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sia.tech/&quot;&gt;Sia&lt;/a&gt; you can do so &lt;a href=&quot;https://coingeek.com/p2p-decentralized-file-storage-dropbox-killer/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/bitfwd/what-is-decentralised-storage-ipfs-filecoin-sia-storj-swarm-5509e476995f&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can host files somewhere like your own external website or server, or by using a storage service like Dropbox or Google Drive. Dropbox Professional and Business plans are paid services but they allow you to set a password on files for an extra layer of security around who can access it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you receive a payment you can then share a link with your buyer that they can click to download their file. Or, if you want to keep it very simple and your file is small enough you can let buyers know that they need to provide an email address so you can email the file to them when their payment is confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-create-your-listing&quot;&gt;2. Create Your Listing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a plan for hosting and sharing your digital product you can create a listing for it on OpenBazaar. Create a &lt;strong&gt;new listing&lt;/strong&gt; and under &lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt; select &lt;strong&gt;“Digital Good.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;create_digital_listing_on_openbazaar_2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Create a Digital Listing on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Create a Digital Listing on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a great &lt;strong&gt;title&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;description&lt;/strong&gt; that relate to keywords people may use in search to find it easily. Make sure to also describe how you will send the file to users when they complete their purchase and let them if you need something from them such as an email address. It’s also helpful to include any instructions they may need for setting up or installing your file if it requires that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Include at least 1 great &lt;strong&gt;image&lt;/strong&gt; that describes your item such as a book jacket mockup for an ebook or the cover art for a music album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tags&lt;/strong&gt; can be added to boost the searchability of your item. Include obvious ones as relate to the item itself like “book” or “music” then more as relates to broader categories it represents such as “fiction” or “bluegrass.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;category&lt;/strong&gt; helps keep your store organized. If you plan to sell both ebooks AND music albums, you’d just type in the corresponding category for each of your listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variants&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;inventory&lt;/strong&gt; can likely be left blank. These are helpful for things like physical goods where you may offer the same hat but in 3 different colors with only a certian number of each available. If you have variations of your digital goods it may be worth creating separate listings for each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;strong&gt;return policy&lt;/strong&gt; you can set this up however you’d like. You may want to say no refunds if the price point is very low on the item or perhaps offer a 100% satisfaction guarantee with a full refund option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terms &amp;amp; conditions&lt;/strong&gt; can be added if you have any conditions or advisories you want to make people aware of when accessing or using your digital good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;coins&lt;/strong&gt; you’d like to receive as payment–it can be just one of them or any combination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-share-your-item-from-openbazaarcom&quot;&gt;3. Share your item from OpenBazaar.com&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is a marketplace where people can browse and discover the items that you have for sale—but that’s not the only way they can find them! &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar.com&lt;/a&gt; exists to make it easy for you and others to share stores and listings to your social media and other communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your listing is live you can click “View on web” in the address bar at the top to see it and share it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;view_on_web_link_in_openbazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;View on Web Link in OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;View on Web Link in OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;more-than-a-marketplace&quot;&gt;More Than a Marketplace&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software is still new and it is very niche because it exclusively uses cryptocurrency for payments. It needs every true believer’s help to grow into a phenomenon worldwide and that starts with our community. Make sure to connect with us to market your store and meet other like-minded people all around the world. Meet us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/OpenBazaarGroup&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want To Learn More about Selling on OpenBazaar?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Check out these other posts that will help you get started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-seller-guide-what-to-expect-in-this-decentralized-marketplace/&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar Seller Guide - What To Expect in This Decentralized Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-market-your-store-and-listings-on-openbazaar/&quot;&gt;How To Market Your Store and Listings on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/5-tips-to-make-your-openbazaar-listings-pop/&quot;&gt;5 Tips To Make Your OpenBazaar Listings Pop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When you think about the world’s largest internet marketplaces, what kind of products do you picture? Maybe you get your coffee or toilet paper or other daily sundries from Amazon or Alibaba. Maybe you buy secondhand or hard-to-find collectible items on Ebay. Maybe you visit Etsy for thoughtful handmade gifts. These sites do have a focus on physical goods but that’s not all they can do.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Spend Bitcoin and Other Cryptocurrencies on OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-spend-bitcoin-and-other-cryptocurrencies-on-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Spend Bitcoin and Other Cryptocurrencies&lt;/span&gt; on OpenBazaar" /><published>2019-02-28T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-28T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-spend-bitcoin-and-other-cryptocurrencies-on-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-spend-bitcoin-and-other-cryptocurrencies-on-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;Shopping online is pretty excellent, right? It’s really one of the most powerful features of the internet today. How great is it that we can connect to businesses around the world from just about anywhere we are and have things delivered right to us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we now know there are some big downsides, too. What about all those extra fees to cover things like platform costs and payment processing? All of your private data like your address and financial information is stored on these networks which is a big risk to you if it ever gets hacked. Everything you do on these networks is spied on. Then you get ads from the spies so they can try to take &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; of your money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar helps people shop online but with a couple of &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; important differences:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The OpenBazaar Network Is Made of People.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is decentralized which means the whole network is made up of just the computers that run the software and, of course, the people who own them. There are no big companies jacking up fees, taking a cut, pumping you full of ads, or deciding what you get to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenBazaar Uses Cryptocurrencies for Payments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means people anywhere in the world can buy and sell things with each other and not worry about added costs for platform use, crazy transaction fees or exchange rates for international currencies. If you want to buy something from someone in another country… you can! Cryptocurrencies work everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shopping with cryptocurrency works a little differently than with cash or credit cards but our mission with OpenBazaar is to make it easy. Here are four other features that you need to know about when you spend Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies on OpenBazaar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-multiwallet-for-bitcoin-bitcoin-cash-zcash-and-litecoin&quot;&gt;1. Multiwallet for Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, Zcash and Litecoin&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OpenBazaar_Multiwallet.gif&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar Multiwallet for Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, Zcash and Litecoin&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar Multiwallet for Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, Zcash and Litecoin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar now has a multiwallet built right into it. This means you can 
use your choice of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoincash.org&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://litecoin.org&quot;&gt;Litecoin&lt;/a&gt; (with Ether and others coming soon) right inside the application. Vendors can accept all of these coins by default as well and many of them choose to so you can shop with your favorites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-different-payment-types-to-help-protect-your-coins&quot;&gt;2. Different Payment Types to Help Protect your Coins&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OpenBazaar_Payment_Type.gif&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar Payment Types Direct or Moderated&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar Payment Types Direct or Moderated&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you keep your cryptocoins safe on a marketplace where there is no centralized company to insure your purchase and send you a refund in the event you’re unhappy? With futuristic innovation and good old fashioned people power, that’s how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar offers 2 major payment types: &lt;strong&gt;direct&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;moderated&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;direct payment&lt;/strong&gt; is when you send your coins directly to the seller to start your transaction. This is like handing someone cash but over the internet. Once you hand over the money there’s no way to get it back, unless the seller chooses to give you a refund. Be cautious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;moderated payment&lt;/strong&gt; is when you send your coins to a 2-of-3 multisignature account that includes you, the seller and a moderator. A moderator is just another user on the network who has offered their moderation services to help in the case of a dispute. This like using an escrow service because 2 of the 3 parties involved in the transaction must agree for the coins to be released. Generally the buyer and seller agree but in the case of trouble with the transaction, either one of them can reach out to the moderator for help. Learn more about the details of payment types &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/115002761052-How-does-a-moderated-payment-using-multisig-work-&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-moderator-types-to-make-choosing-a-moderator-easier&quot;&gt;3. Moderator Types to Make Choosing a Moderator Easier&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OB1_Verified_Moderator_Shield.gif&quot; alt=&quot;OB1 Verified Moderator Shield on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;OB1 Verified Moderator Shield on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone can become a moderator on OpenBazaar so it’s very important to choose someone who is trustworthy. You may notice that some listings have an orange shield on them which signals that the seller has one or more OB1 Verified Moderators to choose from. An OB1 Verified Moderator has submitted some reputation &amp;amp; identity information to OB1, the company leading the development of OpenBazaar, to demonstrate they are more likely to be trustworthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a seller does not have moderators or &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io/verified-moderators.html&quot;&gt;OB1 Verified Moderators&lt;/a&gt; listed on their item but you would like to use one on your transaction, just message the seller to request it. If they decline, proceed with caution unless you know and trust them and are willing to risk your coins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-different-listing-types-so-you-can-easily-search-for-items-services-digital-goods-and-cryptocurrencies&quot;&gt;4. Different Listing Types So You Can Easily Search for Items, Services, Digital Goods and Cryptocurrencies&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OpenBazaar_Listing_Type.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Listing Types on OpenBazaar for Services, Cryptocurrencies, Physical Goods or Digital Goods&quot; title=&quot;Listing Types on OpenBazaar for Services, Cryptocurrencies, Physical Goods or Digital Goods&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We often use the word “thing” to describe what’s for sale on OpenBazaar but did you know that people can also sell things that are not just &lt;em&gt;physical&lt;/em&gt; things? Since its inception OpenBazaar users have listed “things” you may think of right away like books, clothing and art, but also “things” like real estate, internet hosting space and temporary rentals…the last two of which start to blur the line between “thing” and “service.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services are also a distinct listing type available in OpenBazaar. People have listed translation, design, coding or other business services. Even ridesharing! (Wait, is that also on the blurry line of service/thing too?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another listing type available is digital goods like ebooks, music, stock photos, game codes, gift cards and more. These items are particularly popular because they don’t require anyone to wrestle with the sometimes complicated logistics of shipping physical items. Digital goods also don’t require you to share your identity with the other party. You can buy and sell as many digital items as you like without ever sharing your identity information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final listing type available right now is cryptocurrencies. Yes, they are digital goods too, but they’re distinct enough to merit a separate listing type. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-buy-cryptocurrencies-privately-with-no-fees/&quot;&gt;trade over 1,500 cryptocurrencies right in OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;. Just look around for the coins you want, select a listing, set your quantity from a seller’s available inventory, and pay for them with BTC, BCH, ZEC or LTC. The seller will then send them to your wallet and you can complete the transaction!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want To Learn More about Shopping with Cryptocurrencies on OpenBazaar?&lt;/strong&gt;\
Check out these other posts that will help you get started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/The-Beginners-Guide-to-Buying-Goods-Services-and-Cryptocurrency-on-OpenBazaar/&quot;&gt;The Beginner’s Guide to Buying Goods, Services and Cryptocurrency on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/3-things-that-make-it-really-easy-to-shop-on-openbazaar/&quot;&gt;3 Things That Make It Really Easy to Shop on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Shopping online is pretty excellent, right? It’s really one of the most powerful features of the internet today. How great is it that we can connect to businesses around the world from just about anywhere we are and have things delivered right to us?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar Developer Call - February 14, 2019</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-February-14-2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar Developer Call - February 14, 2019" /><published>2019-02-19T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-19T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-February-14-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-February-14-2019/">&lt;p&gt;This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on February 14, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to join the call in real time? Sign up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/developers&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our ongoing conversations on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse OpenBazaar now at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NjsqD1EO1Pg&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chat log:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:16] chris.troutner: I’ve been using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-desktop/releases/tag/v2.3.0&quot;&gt;v2.3 release&lt;/a&gt; to do cryptocurrency trades. Haven’t run into any issues, but my server is running on DO, so always ‘online’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:17] mg (OB1): Appreciation to all of you who came out to visit at the conference!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:18] chris.troutner: Can you guys also expand on the differences between &lt;a href=&quot;https://gethaven.app&quot;&gt;Haven&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org&quot;&gt;OB&lt;/a&gt;? I’m a little unclear on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:20] chris.troutner: Very cool. Love the explanation of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; vs IPNS calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:20] Rod: Have the recent IPFS updates helped at all with how long IPNS calls take?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:22] Rod: Got it, thanks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:25] chris.troutner: Makes sense. Thanks. Helps to define the scope between the two projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:27] chris.troutner: Thanks, Mike!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:28] Jlong: Talk about the purchase flow and whther OB is willing to change the default to verified mods&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:32] Jlong: Cannot the store provide obids?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:32] flavoraid: Plans for allowing geographic search?  For example, if I’m looking for a plumber, I’m probably only interested in plumbers located within in 20 miles of my residence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:34] ligi: what is the plan for the ethereum support public rollout?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:35] ligi: would so much love to use OB with DAI&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:35] Jlong: This can apply mainly to Haven&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:35] Jlong: Cool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:36] flavoraid: Also, I might only want someone who is licensed and bonded.  It would be handy if that were a checkbox, so that plumbers could display their license and bonding status on their profile, and select for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:37] mg (OB1): Someone was chasing this in the public chat semi-recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:37] mg (OB1): (location-association with a store)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:38] flavoraid: Thanks for the response re: location based search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:40] flavoraid: Maybe Google Plus codes could be used for internal location search (no api call): &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Location_Code&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Location_Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:40] ligi: thanks for the info regarding ethereum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:40] ligi: looking forward to it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:40] mg (OB1): If Google doesn’t discontinue the service from underneath us 2 years from now when they decide it’s not worth supporting anymore. (no thanks)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:41] flavoraid: “Locations close to each other have similar codes. They can be encoded or decoded offline.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:41] flavoraid: Plus codes are open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:41] mg (OB1): That’s a good point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:42] Rod: I’m making an announcement for my project I’ve been working on for a few months this week&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:42] flavoraid: News re: Monero integration?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:42] Rod: &lt;a href=&quot;https://zokos.com&quot;&gt;https://zokos.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:43] mg (OB1): flavoraid: Check out the latest MoneroTalk podcast. They interviewed Brian about that just this last weekend. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:44] flavoraid: Thanks for the pointer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:45] Rod: Thanks Sam :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:45] mg (OB1): MoneroTalk podcast w OpenBazaar Devs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:46] flavoraid: OB hosting services?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:46] flavoraid: That y’all would especially like to support?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:47] flavoraid: Thanks, y’all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:47] chris.troutner: Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:48] Anup: Cheers guys&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on February 14, 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Market Your Store and Listings on OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-market-your-store-and-listings-on-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Market Your Store and Listings&lt;/span&gt; on OpenBazaar" /><published>2019-02-15T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-15T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-market-your-store-and-listings-on-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-market-your-store-and-listings-on-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;The shift to peer-to-peer online commerce won’t happen overnight. Until this technology becomes widespread, we need tools that help the transition go more smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the earliest feedback we heard from ecommerce sellers who were interested in OpenBazaar was that they wanted a way to easily share their store and listings on their social networks. To answer this we built &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-regular-website-to-look-into-a-decentralized-network&quot;&gt;A regular website to look into a decentralized network&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/download&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt; is an application that users have to download and run on their own computers to connect to and participate in the network. It is built this way to make the decentralization of the network possible. While the tech isn’t available for a full OpenBazaar buying &amp;amp; selling experience in a browser yet, that doesn’t mean there can’t be just a simple website that looks into the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That solved the simplest part of the problem: sellers wanted to share their links easily and potential buyers—who may or may not know about OpenBazaar yet—wanted to view them in a predictable way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar.com&lt;/a&gt; in the middle of last year and it’s been a hit. Traffic to the site is growing &lt;strong&gt;around 40% month over month&lt;/strong&gt;. This shows us that users are interested in decentralized applications that uphold some core values, but that are also accessible wherever they may be in their technological adventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sharing-store--listings-from-within-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Sharing store &amp;amp; listings from within OpenBazaar&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who want to share stores and listings easily on the web can grab their links from OpenBazaar.com several ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By clicking the green “View on Web” link in the address bar within their OpenBazaar client:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;openbazaar_view_on_web_link.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar View on Web Link&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar View on Web Link&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By copying the store ID and pasting it on the end of https://openbazaar.com/store/ like this:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;openbazaar_peerid_selected.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar PeerID Selected&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar PeerID Selected&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmcUDmZK8PsPYWw5FRHKNZFjszm2K6e68BQSTpnJYUsML7&quot;&gt;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmcUDmZK8PsPYWw5FRHKNZFjszm2K6e68BQSTpnJYUsML7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sharing-store--listings-from-openbazaarcom&quot;&gt;Sharing store &amp;amp; listings from OpenBazaar.com&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On OpenBazaar.com there are additional features including these social share buttons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;openbazaar_store_widget_builder_link.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar Widget Builder Link and Social Share Buttons&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar Widget Builder Link and Social Share Buttons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/widget&quot;&gt;the widget&lt;/a&gt; for sellers who have websites where they want to showcase their OpenBazaar store. Simply copy the code and add it to your site wherever you can post an embed or add HTML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;openbazaar_store_widget_builder.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar Store Widget Builder&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar Store Widget Builder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working to build a fully decentralized marketplace and social experience to promote privacy and autonomy for users around the world. It’s clear to us, though, that the road to full decentralization is made up of multiple decentralized steps rather than a complete jump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving from centralized systems we are displeased with is a process that will take some time and the ability to make small advances through that process is imperative. Building decentralized apps that also interface with centralized apps that people are used to using right now is important to help them better match their desires for the future with their present reality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The shift to peer-to-peer online commerce won’t happen overnight. Until this technology becomes widespread, we need tools that help the transition go more smoothly.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Which Cryptocurrencies are used in OpenBazaar, and Why?</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/which-cryptocurrencies-are-used-in-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Which Cryptocurrencies are used in OpenBazaar, &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;and Why?&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2019-01-24T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-24T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/which-cryptocurrencies-are-used-in-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/which-cryptocurrencies-are-used-in-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;The decentralized marketplace OpenBazaar supports several different cryptocurrencies for buying and selling goods and services between users. This post explains which currencies, and why were they chosen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cryptocurrencies-supported-in-openbazaar&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrencies Supported in OpenBazaar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Litecoin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zcash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-we-support-these-cryptocurrencies&quot;&gt;Why we Support these Cryptocurrencies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar was originally developed with only Bitcoin in mind. At the beginning of 2018 we &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/H4yW20txnB0&quot;&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; a handful of new coins, and in early 2019 version 2.3 was released which added Litecoin and a new wallet which supports multiple coins per instance, which made it easier to integrate new coins moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the original reliance on Bitcoin, it’s always been a requirement for any supported cryptocurrency to be architecturally similar to Bitcoin for it to work properly. All the coins supported are forks of Bitcoin, unless otherwise noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another requirement is multisig. OpenBazaar uses multisig for moderated and offline payments (escrow), and coins must have this feature - or the ability to support escrow payments another way - to be supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bitcoin&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/en/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; is the original cryptocurrency. It is the most secure, with a large industry of miners devoting energy to securing the blockchain. It has the most users of any cryptocurrency, and is used for commerce more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin was the only currency used in OpenBazaar from the beginning of the project in 2014 until early 2018. It is the most used cryptocurrency within the platform by a wide margin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bitcoin-cash&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt; was forked from Bitcoin in August 2017. The creators of Bitcoin Cash disagreed with the development decisions of Bitcoin (particularly around scaling), and created new consensus rules. They focus on their cryptocurrency being usable for commerce on-chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar adopted Bitcoin Cash because adoption was technically simple due to its similarity to Bitcoin, and because community members were willing to offer support for the implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;litecoin&quot;&gt;Litecoin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://litecoin.org/&quot;&gt;Litecoin&lt;/a&gt; was one of the earliest altcoins. It is very similar to Bitcoin in design, with a few differences such as having a quicker block generation time and different hash algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one of the oldest altcoins it has well-established industry support, and a substantial community of users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like Bitcoin Cash, OpenBazaar adopted Litecoin because adoption was technically simple due to its similarity to Bitcoin, and because community members were willing to offer support for the implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zcash&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash/&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt; is a cryptocurrency that focuses on privacy. It was forked from Bitcoin, but adds the ability to do “shielded transactions” using zk-SNARKs, which aren’t traceable on the blockchain like typical Bitcoin transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within OpenBazaar at the moment, shielded transactions using Zcash aren’t possible, and only transparent transactions (which aren’t private) are possible. At some point we hope to change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the other currencies mentioned,  OpenBazaar adopted Zcash because adoption was technically simple due to its similarity to Bitcoin, and because community members were willing to offer support for the implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-cryptocurrencies&quot;&gt;Other cryptocurrencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethereum support is being actively developed now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some ERC-20 tokens will also be supported after Ethereum support is added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is discussion about Monero support, but because of Monero’s multisig design it might only allow direct transactions, not escrowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will be updated when new coins are supported, or when new development is occurring.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The decentralized marketplace OpenBazaar supports several different cryptocurrencies for buying and selling goods and services between users. This post explains which currencies, and why were they chosen.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar 2.3 is Released with New Multiwallet Feature</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2.3-release-with-multiwallet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar 2.3 is Released &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;with New Multiwallet Feature&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2019-01-17T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-17T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2.3-release-with-multiwallet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2.3-release-with-multiwallet/">&lt;p&gt;After several months of work OpenBazaar version 2.3 has &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-desktop/releases&quot;&gt;been released&lt;/a&gt;. This is a major release which contains significant changes to how the OpenBazaar wallet functions. Because of the major changes in this release, we highly recommend you &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/115002761312-How-do-I-backup-my-store-&quot;&gt;backup your OpenBazaar data&lt;/a&gt; before you update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, OpenBazaar users were forced to use one cryptocurrency at a time. At startup they choose between Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, and Zcash. From that moment they could only use the coin they chose for all sales or purchases. If they wanted to use another coin, they had to run an entirely separate node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the 2.3 release OpenBazaar users are no longer forced to use a single cryptocurrency, but can buy, sell, send and receive multiple coins with the same wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of release there are four supported cryptocurrencies: Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, Litecoin and Zcash. Ethereum support is nearing completion and will be added soon, and other coins will be added later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows you what the multiwallet looks like and how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U3N82PbhezM&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">After several months of work OpenBazaar version 2.3 has been released. This is a major release which contains significant changes to how the OpenBazaar wallet functions. Because of the major changes in this release, we highly recommend you backup your OpenBazaar data before you update.</summary></entry></feed>