<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://openbazaar.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://openbazaar.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-14T18:49:15+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">OpenBazaar</title><entry><title type="html">How OpenBazaar &amp;amp; Bitcoin Could Kill the American Pickers Economy</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-openbazaar-bitcoin-could-kill-the-american-pickers-economy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How OpenBazaar &amp; Bitcoin Could Kill the &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;American Pickers&lt;/span&gt; Economy" /><published>2018-12-13T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-13T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-openbazaar-bitcoin-could-kill-the-american-pickers-economy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-openbazaar-bitcoin-could-kill-the-american-pickers-economy/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Sam Patterson, OB1 Co-Founder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This post is a bit of speculation on creative use cases for OpenBazaar recently re-inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/OpenBazaar/comments/9x4p69/openbazaar_more_than_just_your_standard_storefront/&quot;&gt;this community post on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;. OpenBazaar is a simple cryptocurrency marketplace built on an open-source network that can be used, grown and changed by users around the world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let us know what your creative ideas for OpenBazaar are on &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, or on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the holiday season again. Like many people, I have been thinking a lot about the stuff we acquire and exchange as a demonstration of love this time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stuff.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Things.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posessions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of us in the western world often have a lot of &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt; already and this season encourages us to acquire more. It made me think about how many of us even really &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; how much stuff we already have and my fascination with the TV show American Pickers. If you haven’t watched it before, take 2 minutes to watch this clip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tKu-rCXkad4&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This clip demonstrates a few common themes in the show:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The owner of the item had lost track of where it was. Often in the show, the owners aren’t even aware of the item’s existence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The method to determine a price to sell the item was informal, and time consuming. There’s a good chance one of the parties in the trade was far away from a ‘market price’.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transactions are done in person, in cash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The setting of the show is somewhat unique; they typically find rural collectors who have barns full of old items. But some of the themes of the show are mirrored in the broader economy as well, at least in developed economies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-do-we-know-what-stuff-we-already-have&quot;&gt;How Do We Know What Stuff We Already Have?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping track of personal possessions depends largely on the individual, but it is usually done informally. Few people formally track all the objects they own. One popular method is simple: don’t keep track, and have periodic yard sales to deal with excess possessions. On a somewhat regular basis (typically each spring or summer), people will sort through their possessions and determine which items they want to keep, and which they are willing to sell. In this sense, a yard sale serves the following functions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Periodically &lt;strong&gt;updating your own knowledge&lt;/strong&gt; about your possessions and how much you value them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transmitting some of that information&lt;/strong&gt; to your local community by displaying those items publicly and pricing them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reducing the number of unwanted possessions&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;increasing cash&lt;/strong&gt; (or occasionally improve possessions through barter).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(As an aside, this might explain how ‘pickers’ can be successful; their physical presence and interest in your possessions is a simpler method for achieving these three functions.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method of keeping track of possessions has worked well enough for most people, but it’s far from ideal. The largest cost is &lt;strong&gt;time&lt;/strong&gt;. Preparation requires manually sorting goods and determining their price, physically sorting them (and putting back what wasn’t sold later), then waiting for others to take an interest in them. A yard sale typically takes at least a day’s worth of activity. The haggling itself - similar to the pickers - benefits those who have more information about the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advent of the Internet is already allowing better methods. Online platforms for buying and selling goods allow people to more effectively sell their unwanted possessions by opening up the information beyond the local community. However, these platforms have significant drawbacks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The platforms &lt;strong&gt;charge fees&lt;/strong&gt;, and the payment methods they use often charge fees as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The platforms &lt;strong&gt;monitor the data&lt;/strong&gt; of the people listing their possessions, which is &lt;strong&gt;typically tied to their real-world identity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The platforms have their own &lt;strong&gt;restrictions around listing possessions&lt;/strong&gt;, from type of goods they allow to the length of time they can be hosted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using these platforms is an incremental improvement over the yard sale. It still requires manually assessing and valuing your own possessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-openbazaar-and-bitcoin-can-manage-personal-possessions&quot;&gt;How OpenBazaar and Bitcoin can Manage Personal Possessions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;tracking_personal_inventory_on_openbazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tracking Personal Inventory on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Tracking Personal Inventory on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/download&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt; is a decentralized network for trade; users run the software locally and connect directly to other users to buy and sell goods and services. There is no central institution to take a cut, monitor data, or restrict trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; is a digital currency and payment network; users control their own money locally and aren’t reliant on banks or payment processors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together, these platforms could change the way we keep track of our personal possessions. Our own knowledge of our possessions - and their value - doesn’t need to be manually re-evaluated informally and periodically, but instead continually tracked and updated. Nor does this information need to be manually transmitted to the local or global community; it can be automatically (and anonymously) displayed to the world, continuously, at no cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be achieved by representing possessions as &lt;strong&gt;Ricardian contracts&lt;/strong&gt; (I’ll just refer them them as contracts), and publishing them to the OpenBazaar network. Ricardian contracts are a data structure that allows goods and services to be represented electronically; these contracts allow users to put in any information about a possession as well as the price they value the good at. When a user creates a contract, the OpenBazaar client publishes the information to the network, and other users can view that contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they choose, the user could put in a price for which they’d be willing to sell the item. If anyone in the world values that possession more than the current owner, they could instantly make an offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a user isn’t willing to sell a possession, they could simply create a contract and choose to keep the information about it stored locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-downside&quot;&gt;The Downside&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retroactively listing possessions as contracts would be time-consuming. However, if a user were to begin creating contracts for all new possessions they gain, eventually most or all of their possessions would be recorded as contracts in their OpenBazaar client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-present-and-the-future&quot;&gt;The Present and The Future&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, much of commerce is already moving to the Internet, and the process of recording information about possessions is moving from a manual task to one which could easily be automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you acquire an item via OpenBazaar, this could be done easily. Information about the contract purchased would simply change ownership to the new user. Using other major platforms could also be simple with importing tools, likely done via a browser plugin or something similar. Anything purchased via Amazon would automatically be represented as a contract. Apps using UPC scanners could automatically create contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This system would allow all possessions to have a continuous digital representation, and associated value, at no cost to the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? What other interesting use cases can you think of for a system like OpenBazaar? What would you like to see it do in the future? Tell us about it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, or on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">By Sam Patterson, OB1 Co-Founder</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar Shopping and Selling Survival Guide - Last Minute Holiday Edition</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-shopping-and-selling-survival-guide-last-minute-holiday-edition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar Shopping and Selling Survival Guide - &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Last Minute Holiday Edition&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-12-06T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-06T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-shopping-and-selling-survival-guide-last-minute-holiday-edition</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-shopping-and-selling-survival-guide-last-minute-holiday-edition/">&lt;p&gt;Staying ahead of the holiday season can be a challenge for shoppers and sellers alike. What’s an &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/download&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt; user to do when they find themselves already in December and they still need to buy some gifts and/or squeeze in a few more sales?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, disaster can still be avoided with a quick pause to regroup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OpenBazaar_Shopping_and_Selling_Survival_Guide_Gift.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar Shopping and Selling Survival Guide Gift&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar Shopping and Selling Survival Guide Gift&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buyers:&lt;/strong&gt; are you running a little behind and still need a great gift for the other cryptocurrency lovers in your life? Make a &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; statement by using your coins to buy their gifts on OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get shopping&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t already, start browsing now! &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar.com&lt;/a&gt; makes this incredibly easy for you to do anywhere you have an internet-connected device. When you are ready to buy your gifts, just open the same listings with your desktop app to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember production and shipping times&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most vendors on OpenBazaar are individuals or small businesses who run everything themselves. You may have just fallen in love with an item but if you need it by a specific time, make sure the vendor can deliver it by then. For custom or handmade goods, be sure to check with the vendor about what they have ready to ship and their current production &amp;amp; shipping times. Also note where in the world they are shipping from to estimate how long it will take to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look for deals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of OpenBazaar vendors are still offering promotions right now like this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;use coupon code &amp;quot;xmas&amp;quot; to get %15 off any shirts for your super normal presents for people this holiday season. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/bZImpRezxp&quot;&gt;https://t.co/bZImpRezxp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;if btc, use &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@openbazaar&lt;/a&gt; discount already included in price ob://QmTwutUrwXS3bh5rfSXriJCNayToD44VpWJbm6DwKuVc2U/store&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; YOUR HYDRA (@BraveTheWorld) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BraveTheWorld/status/1070474239826771968?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 6, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still some nice deals to be had out there so keep an eye out for them. We will be sharing any great deals we find on our social media, too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sellers:&lt;/strong&gt; Do you still want to earn a few more cryptocoins this month? Here are some tips to do so and not run yourself ragged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check in with yourself and your business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, a bit more Bitcoin is always great but make sure you are realistic about what it will take you to get through any additional orders this month so that you don’t overextend yourself. Account for how long it takes you to make, acquire, package and send your items and about how long it takes to arrive in different locations so that you can advise your buyers well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know your cutoff time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you know the last day you can accept orders in order to get them to buyers before the holiday they are celebrating. This is especially important if you do handmade or other custom work. Also, do you want to take some time off this month? Make sure you aren’t chasing orders into your own holiday and &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/115002765331-How-do-I-turn-my-store-off-or-go-on-vacation-mode-&quot;&gt;set your OpenBazaar store to “off”&lt;/a&gt; a few days prior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promote &amp;amp; offer incentives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great way to promote yourself and encourage a little sales push is to use social media to talk about special offers you have. Vendors are still offering incentives for buyers like discounts and bonus gifts right now. If your capacity allows for it, give your potential buyers some extra reasons to give their business to &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; over the hundreds of other vendors competing for their attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; You can easily add coupon codes to your items on OpenBazaar following &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360018728172-How-do-I-add-a-discount-or-coupon-code-to-my-items-&quot;&gt;these steps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all still have some work left to do if we celebrate holidays in December so while this may not &lt;em&gt;eliminate&lt;/em&gt; stress, hopefully thinking through these things can help you minimize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;happy-holidays&quot;&gt;Happy holidays!&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Staying ahead of the holiday season can be a challenge for shoppers and sellers alike. What’s an OpenBazaar user to do when they find themselves already in December and they still need to buy some gifts and/or squeeze in a few more sales? Thankfully, disaster can still be avoided with a quick pause to regroup.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1: Lessons Learned</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2-turns-1-lessons-learned/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1: &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-11-29T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-29T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2-turns-1-lessons-learned</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2-turns-1-lessons-learned/">&lt;p&gt;This month we’ve been celebrating &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/these-5-openbazaar-stats-are-really-exciting/&quot;&gt;the one year anniversary of OpenBazaar 2.0&lt;/a&gt;. To read a summary of the last year, read &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/big-change-hard-work-and-strong-growth-openbazaar-2-turns-1/&quot;&gt;Brian Hoffman’s piece&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar started more than four years ago, and for everyone involved it has been an incredible learning experience. Here are a few lessons we’ve learned over the years, with a particular emphasis on the past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-expect-politics&quot;&gt;1. Expect politics.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like Bitcoin, OpenBazaar is an open source piece of software and a network of people running the software. As such, it’s incapable of having a “position” on any given issue. However, the individuals and companies building OpenBazaar do have opinions about issues in the cryptocurrency space. When they promote these beliefs – particularly on controversial issues – others will often claim “OpenBazaar believes X” instead of correctly attributing the opinion to the individual or company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we started building OpenBazaar in mid-2014 the community of people using cryptocurrencies was smaller, primarily focused on Bitcoin, and the majority of people agreed that building infrastructure in order to use cryptocurrency was worthwhile and necessary for broader adoption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few years the community got larger and also began to disagree on the future of Bitcoin, such as how (or even if) it should scale. OpenBazaar itself played no role in this “scaling debate,” remaining neutral and following whichever chain the market decided upon. While the project itself was neutral, the individuals and companies working on OpenBazaar weren’t. In the new tribalist atmosphere created during the block size debate, this caused many to ascribe the individual positions of developers to the project itself, leading some to withdrawal their support and no longer use the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For better or worse, the cryptocurrency space has become politicized over the past few years, and we now recognize the importance of emphasizing the project’s neutrality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-plan-for-all-possible-future-scenariosincluding-unfavorable-ones&quot;&gt;2. Plan for all possible future scenarios—including unfavorable ones.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson learned is also related to the scaling debate mentioned above. We recognized the possibility that fees could get high enough to prevent people from using Bitcoin for commerce. As individuals and as a company we supported efforts to keep Bitcoin functioning and not get to that point. Unfortunately, it happened anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On the day OpenBazaar 2.0 launched the average Bitcoin fee was ~$5 per transaction and rising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though we already knew high fees were a possibility, this all happened in a very short timeframe and forced us to react as quickly as possible. Since Bitcoin &lt;strong&gt;wasn’t usable for commerce at that moment&lt;/strong&gt;, we decided to add support for new, usable cryptocurrencies into the client immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This put us in the situation of publishing a Bitcoin-only product in November of 2017 and then needing to put all our development efforts into making it a multi-coin product immediately afterwards, which was several months of work. Had we decided at the beginning to build OpenBazaar 2.0 with support for multiple coins it likely would have been simpler and the resulting UX would have been better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing about future scenarios and trying to make or prevent them from happening isn’t sufficient. You need to have plans in place for facing whatever reality meets your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-dont-get-overly-focused-on-a-single-product&quot;&gt;3. Don’t get overly focused on a single product.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is a desktop application. This is primarily for technical reasons; building a completely peer-to-peer application is tough for desktop only and even more so in a web browser or on a mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second reason is due to momentum. We started on desktop and have continued iterating on desktop because, while it has been a difficult undertaking, it was one we became very familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;Web&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ob1.io/&quot;&gt;mobile&lt;/a&gt; are implementations we are actively working on and have dreamed of realizing since the beginning, but they require very different engineering approaches and even philosophies. For them to begin development we had to deliberately choose to direct significant resources to them and many of the decisions made along these paths have not been easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web-connected technology is evolving quickly now and organizations working in a sector like cryptocurrencies need to demonstrate 2 extremes: &lt;strong&gt;focus&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;flexibility&lt;/strong&gt;. People are solving hard problems every day using this very new technology while also facing a growing market with changing desires. They need to be both steadfast &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; nimble to tackle each day that may change all of their grandest plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve learned a lot about developing open source software, managing a community and dealing with the changes and growth of cryptocurrencies over the past few years, and we certainly haven’t been perfect. We appreciate the knowledge we have gained, and are executing against it in our daily work. We look forward to learning much more as we continue building the largest and most free decentralized ecommerce platform on the internet with you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This month we’ve been celebrating the one year anniversary of OpenBazaar 2.0. To read a summary of the last year, read Brian Hoffman’s piece.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Discounts When You Shop OpenBazaar This Week</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/big-discounts-when-You-shop-openbazaar-this-week/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Big Discounts&lt;/span&gt; When You Shop OpenBazaar This Week" /><published>2018-11-20T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-20T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/big-discounts-when-You-shop-openbazaar-this-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/big-discounts-when-You-shop-openbazaar-this-week/">&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-20-is-live/&quot;&gt;one year anniversary of OpenBazaar 2&lt;/a&gt; we are sharing goodies and offers all month long with our users! Clustered loosely around Black Friday this week are some exciting deals that OpenBazaar vendors have set up just for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise specified, use coupon code &lt;strong&gt;OB2Turns1&lt;/strong&gt; to claim the discounts on the stores or items described!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;here-are-some-great-stores-and-listings-for-you-to-shop-this-week&quot;&gt;Here are some great stores and listings for you to shop this week:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;drapis&quot;&gt;DrApis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;75% off&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;DrApis_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;DrApis on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;DrApis on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmfUNUFM5B4PJh73Ht4Gd7qa1TAWV1BBUAhbrYRa2E9hXe&quot;&gt;DrApis on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
DrApis produces and sells premium raw apiculture products from Portugal. Their artisanal raw honey is produced and extracted using exclusively traditional methods, preserving all the natural vitamins, enzymes, phytonutrients and other nutritional elements produced by bees. Now you can enjoy their high-quality products at their lowest prices &lt;em&gt;ever.&lt;/em&gt; Don’t miss this!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;matthew-zipkin&quot;&gt;Matthew Zipkin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;75% off&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Matthew_Zipkin_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Matthew Zipkin Bitcoin Clocks on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Matthew Zipkin Bitcoin Clocks on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmeSyTRaNZMD8ajcfbhC8eYibWgnSZtSGUp3Vn59bCnPWC&quot;&gt;Matthew Zipkin on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Matthew Zipkin is offering this steep discount on his unique Bitcoin clocks. They are practical as well as beautiful pieces of art that any collector would love to have in their home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another fun fact, Matthew is also an &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io/verified-moderators.html&quot;&gt;OB1 Verified Moderator&lt;/a&gt; who is available for you to add to your transactions and provide assistance in case of a dispute. Send him a message and say hello!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;cryptocollectibles&quot;&gt;CryptoCollectibles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;75% off&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;CryptoCollectibles_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;CryptoCollectibles on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;CryptoCollectibles on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/&quot;&gt;CryptoCollectibles on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
CryptoCollectibles has curated several items that are available at this crazy discount. In honor of his recent passing they are all vintage Stan Lee comics. Some have art by Jack “The King” Kirby, Gene Colan, Gil Kane, and other forefathers of the comic book industry. Check out the full list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/journey-into-mystery-111-1964-comic-book&quot;&gt;Journey into Mystery #111&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$220&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$55&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/the-mighty-thor-137-1967-comic-book&quot;&gt;The Mighty Thor #137&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$240&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$60&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/tales-of-suspense-80-1966-comic-book&quot;&gt;Tales of Suspense #80&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$100&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$25&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/tales-of-suspense-82-featuring-iron-man-and-captain-america-196&quot;&gt;Tales of Suspense #82&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$70&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$17.50&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/tales-of-suspense-89-featuring-iron-man-and-captain-america-196&quot;&gt;Tales of Suspense #89&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$55&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$13.75&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/tales-of-suspense-95-featuring-iron-man-and-captain-america-196&quot;&gt;Tales of Suspense #95&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$90&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$22.50&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/tales-of-suspense-99-featuring-iron-man-and-captain-america-196&quot;&gt;Tales of Suspense #99&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$120&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$30&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/captain-america-106-1968-comic-book&quot;&gt;Captain America #106&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$80&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$20&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/tales-to-astonish-58-1964-comic-book&quot;&gt;Tales to Astonish #58&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$50&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$12.50&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/tales-to-astonish-98-featuring-sub-mariner-and-the-incredible-hu&quot;&gt;Tales to Astonish #98&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$80&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$20&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/daredevil-23-1967-comic-book&quot;&gt;Daredevil #23&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$60&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$15&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4/daredevil-25-1967-comic-book&quot;&gt;Daredevil #25&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;del&gt;$60&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;$15&lt;/strong&gt; with code OB2Turns1
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;kimchi-socks&quot;&gt;Kimchi Socks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;75% off&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;Kimchi_Socks_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kimchi Socks on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Kimchi Socks on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/Qma4rBjoQ6j2cusFGMrQjbA7mddPAr9gzPQPgatourZvGf&quot;&gt;Kimchi Socks on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Score some high quality socks to show off your love of your favorite crypto coins.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;penny-portrait&quot;&gt;Penny Portrait&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;25% off&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;Penny_Portrait_Kit_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Penny Portrait on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Penny Portrait on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmQE5wCGM91QLo5YL1aPMS7qYVBquectSm17AQDCSWH6jA&quot;&gt;Penny Portrait on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Put together your own unique art piece with this special kit from Penny Portrait.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;pascal-boyart&quot;&gt;Pascal Boyart&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;10% off&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;Pascal_Boyart_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pascal Boyart on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Pascal Boyart on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmYTXDyMNjdUSvqNc88T2VeVF3KdG7PMefnGQKrp9NZ5Tp&quot;&gt;Pascal Boyart on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Pascal Boyart is an accomplished fine artist based in Paris. He began as a graffiti artist but now produces a wide range of art styles. Many of the pieces he has featured on OpenBazaar focus on cryptocurrency and crypto-culture. Read more of his amazing story on his &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/home/QmYTXDyMNjdUSvqNc88T2VeVF3KdG7PMefnGQKrp9NZ5Tp&quot;&gt;About page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a limited time he’s offering &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/OpenBazaar/comments/9vm6ou/weekly_spotlight_share_your_openbazaar_stores/e9f00mz/&quot;&gt;10% off&lt;/a&gt; on the limited edition prints Crypto Anarchist Manifesto and WhitePaper French version. Use coupon code: BTCARTREVOLUTION
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;openbazaar-swag-bundle&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar Swag Bundle&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just $1!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OpenBazaar_Swag_Bundle_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar Swag Bundle on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar Swag Bundle on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmcUDmZK8PsPYWw5FRHKNZFjszm2K6e68BQSTpnJYUsML7/openbazaar-2-turns-1-swag-bundle-btc&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar Swag Bundle on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Celebrate 1 year of OpenBazaar 2 with this great swag pack. Priced crazy low at just $1 with &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt; shipping because we want to make sure you have the right gear to show off your support and get to see how easy shopping on OpenBazaar can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;like-what-you-see&quot;&gt;Like what you see?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shop these stores and so many more on the brand new browsing website, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">To celebrate the one year anniversary of OpenBazaar 2 we are sharing goodies and offers all month long with our users! Clustered loosely around Black Friday this week are some exciting deals that OpenBazaar vendors have set up just for you.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">These 5 OpenBazaar Stats Are Really Exciting</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/these-5-openbazaar-stats-are-really-exciting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="These &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;5 OpenBazaar Stats&lt;/span&gt; Are Really Exciting" /><published>2018-11-15T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-15T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/these-5-openbazaar-stats-are-really-exciting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/these-5-openbazaar-stats-are-really-exciting/">&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar 2 has had a powerful year since its launch in November 2017. We are proud of the growth and activity we have seen during this tumultuous time in crypto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are &lt;strong&gt;5 exciting stats&lt;/strong&gt; that show network usage and the growth of our contributing community all around the world:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OpenBazaar_2_Stats_Infographic.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar 2 Stats Infographic&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar 2 Stats Infographic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;100000-nodes&quot;&gt;100,000+ Nodes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OpenBazaar 2 network has seen over 100k nodes since launch. “Nodes” means the installation of the app and creation of a profile or store that can connect to others on the network and be discovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;150-countries&quot;&gt;150+ Countries&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is truly international. Users from all around the world are represented as both buyers and sellers. There have also been &lt;strong&gt;291 contributors&lt;/strong&gt; to the OpenBazaar language translation project on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.transifex.com/ob1/openbazaar/languages/&quot;&gt;Transifex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1300000-searches&quot;&gt;1,300,000+ Searches&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just since May 2, 2018 when basic tracking was configured. These have returned over &lt;strong&gt;3,000,000,000 results&lt;/strong&gt;. Yeah, that’s 3 &lt;em&gt;billion&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;20000-sellers&quot;&gt;20,000+ Sellers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20k nodes with at least one listing have been seen on the network. Sellers on OpenBazaar get to experience the &lt;strong&gt;easiest e-commerce store setup on the planet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;60-contributors&quot;&gt;60+ Contributors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dozens of users have contributed to the OpenBazaar codebase on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; resulting in &lt;strong&gt;2,258 commits&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;471 closed issues&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t had a chance to check it out yet, now is a great time to do so! You can help build the decentralized future you want to see by shopping or selling in the app or contributing to the open source project. We have big things coming up in year 2 and we promise you won’t want to miss it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OpenBazaar 2 has had a powerful year since its launch in November 2017. We are proud of the growth and activity we have seen during this tumultuous time in crypto.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar Developer Call - November 8, 2018</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-November-8-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar Developer Call - November 8, 2018" /><published>2018-11-13T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-13T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-November-8-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-November-8-2018/">&lt;p&gt;This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on November 8, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to join the call in real time? Sign up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/developers&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our ongoing conversations on Slack at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse OpenBazaar now at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OlgcS_k_Oa0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chat log:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[09:59] mg: Hi kornilov. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:00] mg: Heard you learned how to feed chickens over the internet with magic internet money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:00] kornilov: Hi developers and Jenn. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:02] kornilov: Yes, I have learned to make ethereum testnet token - korncoin ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:02] mg: I was unaware of that! I was talking about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/redpepper261&quot;&gt;BCH chicken feeder/webcam&lt;/a&gt;. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:04] kornilov: Oh, that is supposed to be a secret project available only for NSA. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:04] mg: Haha… I’ll make sure to keep my lips sealed. :X&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:10] joshj: One minor clarification, ETH uses Infura, not Insight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:19] chris.troutner: 18!? That’s fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:20] Rod: Is there a general timeline/estimate for when 2.3 will be released?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:22] kornilov: How many fulltime employed developers OB has?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:22] kornilov: very nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:23] Rod: Have there been any updates for downloading offline messages quicker in the current client?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:23] Rod: I have done some prototypes for putting together OB features in the browser and the amount of time it takes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:26] chris.troutner: Sorry about that. My connection is sketchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:26] Rod: I did some testing with doing full IPNS crawl on a shorter interval and did not see any significant increase in resources used. Do you know if there is a specific reason the crawl speed is at the current speed it is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:26] Rod: I can follow up on slack later if needed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:27] chris.troutner: I just wanted to say congrats on the Hacktoberfest results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:28] Rod: Alright thank you Chris&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:28] chris.troutner: If OB wants to investigate BCH token integration (Wormhole or SLP), perhaps we could use it as an opportunity to incentivize community developers through swag and bounties, like gitcash.io or Gitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on November 8, 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Will The BCH Hard Fork Affect OpenBazaar?</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-will-the-bch-hard-fork-on-nov-15-affect-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Will The &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;BCH Hard Fork&lt;/span&gt; Affect OpenBazaar?" /><published>2018-11-12T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-12T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-will-the-bch-hard-fork-on-nov-15-affect-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-will-the-bch-hard-fork-on-nov-15-affect-openbazaar/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-happening-with-bitcoin-cash&quot;&gt;What’s Happening with Bitcoin Cash?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt; network upgrade beginning at 4:40PM UTC on November 15th, 2018. Depending on how the upgrade is accepted by the network, the Bitcoin Cash blockchain could fork into two or more incompatible chains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that transacting is dangerous during a hard fork like this unless it’s between addresses you entirely control. If you transact BCH to an address you don’t control you could lose access to your coins on other forks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to help OpenBazaar users prepare for the hard fork, here is some information about the OpenBazaar wallet that can help you decide how to handle any BCH you may have stored there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-will-the-bitcoin-cash-upgrade-affect-my-openbazaar-funds&quot;&gt;How Will The Bitcoin Cash Upgrade Affect My OpenBazaar Funds?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users of &lt;strong&gt;OpenBazaar 2.2.5 and prior&lt;/strong&gt; who have an active BCH wallet are using a local SPV-based wallet. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/en/glossary/simplified-payment-verification&quot;&gt;SPV wallets&lt;/a&gt; are designed to follow the chain that has the most cumulative proof-of-work according to the existing Bitcoin Cash difficulty rules. The SPV wallet in OpenBazaar will follow the longest chain served by the peers it’s able to connect to. We advise that you withdraw your BCH from your OpenBazaar wallet until the chains settle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;withdraw-your-bch-to-electron&quot;&gt;Withdraw Your BCH to Electron&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Users of an OpenBazaar wallet control their funds by having sole access to their keys. The wallet maintains its keys and seed locally on your computer which you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/115002892791-How-do-I-backup-my-OpenBazaar-wallet-&quot;&gt;backup to a safe location using these steps&lt;/a&gt;. Then, import your seed into a &lt;strong&gt;BIP39-compatible wallet&lt;/strong&gt; (such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://electroncash.org/&quot;&gt;Electron Cash&lt;/a&gt; ) to keep your funds safe through the fork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io&quot;&gt;OB1&lt;/a&gt; team will continue to observe the network upgrade and will take further actions as necessary to ensure the safety of our users’ funds at rest within the OpenBazaar wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-should-i-do-next&quot;&gt;What Should I Do Next?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next few weeks, make sure you have the keys to your OpenBazaar wallet stored somewhere safe as complications may arise. When things settle it is entirely your choice what you do with your coins, but we also recommend being cautious of a chain with hash power of 50% or more controlled by one entity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is a private, open-source marketplace powered by cryptocurrency that is making trade free for everyone, everywhere. The development team at OB1 is committed to building a secure and reliable transactional environment for users around the world. We do our best to ensure that you have the knowledge you need to make the best decisions for you and your coins. If you have questions please join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; to chat with our development team and active community.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What’s Happening with Bitcoin Cash?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Shop OpenBazaar - Pascal Boyart, DropShip IO and Boston Zcash Users Group</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/shop-openbazaar-pascal-boyart-dropship-io-boston-zcash-users-group/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shop OpenBazaar - &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Pascal Boyart, DropShip IO and Boston Zcash Users Group&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-11-11T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-11T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/shop-openbazaar-pascal-boyart-dropship-io-boston-zcash-users-group</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/shop-openbazaar-pascal-boyart-dropship-io-boston-zcash-users-group/">&lt;p&gt;Bring your cryptocoins and digital currency to OpenBazaar to shop, sell or trade with people from around the world. This is a bitcoin marketplace that expanded to become a &lt;em&gt;cryptocurrency&lt;/em&gt; marketplace where you can buy and sell what you want — &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; pay how you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out these stores featuring each of the different payment coins now available on OpenBazaar: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash/&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are 3 great stores for you to shop at today:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;pascal-boyart&quot;&gt;Pascal Boyart&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bitcoin (BTC)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Pascal_Boyart_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pascal Boyart on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Pascal Boyart on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmYTXDyMNjdUSvqNc88T2VeVF3KdG7PMefnGQKrp9NZ5Tp&quot;&gt;Pascal Boyart on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Pascal Boyart is an accomplished fine artist based in Paris. He began as a graffiti artist but now produces a wide range of art styles. Many of the pieces he has featured on OpenBazaar focus on cryptocurrency and crypto-culture. Read more of his amazing story on his &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/home/QmYTXDyMNjdUSvqNc88T2VeVF3KdG7PMefnGQKrp9NZ5Tp&quot;&gt;About page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BONUS:&lt;/strong&gt; For a limited time he’s offering &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/OpenBazaar/comments/9vm6ou/weekly_spotlight_share_your_openbazaar_stores/e9f00mz/&quot;&gt;a 10% reduction&lt;/a&gt; on the limited edition prints Crypto Anarchist Manifesto and WhitePaper French version. Use coupon code: BTCARTREVOLUTION
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dropship-io&quot;&gt;DropShip I/O&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bitcoin Cash (BCH)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;DropShip_IO_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;DropShip I/O on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;DropShip I/O on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmY1jBtr54t2T929RuDt24MLRFxjacQzHVmz5z8yxzVg3P&quot;&gt;DropShip I/O on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ever wish you could just buy things from Amazon using Bitcoin Cash? This OpenBazaar store makes that possible and even sweetens the deal with a discount to promote the use of cryptocurrencies worldwide. Learn more &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/home/QmY1jBtr54t2T929RuDt24MLRFxjacQzHVmz5z8yxzVg3P&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;boston-zcash-users-group&quot;&gt;Boston Zcash Users Group&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zcash (ZEC)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Boston_Zcash_Users_Group_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Boston Zcash Users Group on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Boston Zcash Users Group on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmYs2Hc2b2dMWPw1qbrYWS5zCRRjWzgUu3XAPWP239SNGp&quot;&gt;Boston Zcash Users Group on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Boston Zcash Users Group is putting their principles into action by giving Zcash fans and users a practical way to use their favorite coin. Check out the list of books, stickers and coins they have available for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;like-what-you-see&quot;&gt;Like what you see?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shop these stores and so many more on the brand new browsing website, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Bring your cryptocoins and digital currency to OpenBazaar to shop, sell or trade with people from around the world. This is a bitcoin marketplace that expanded to become a cryptocurrency marketplace where you can buy and sell what you want — and pay how you want.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Change, Hard Work and Strong Growth—OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/big-change-hard-work-and-strong-growth-openbazaar-2-turns-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Change, Hard Work and Strong Growth—&lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-11-07T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-07T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/big-change-hard-work-and-strong-growth-openbazaar-2-turns-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/big-change-hard-work-and-strong-growth-openbazaar-2-turns-1/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by Brian Hoffman, CEO, OB1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The years leading up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-20-is-live/&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar 2.0&lt;/a&gt; went by in a flash, it seems, culminating in our best and most capable software release ever this month last year. Since then it’s been a whirlwind of development milestones, bug fixes, crypto political drama, and flying all over the world to promote the benefits of private, free trade for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OpenBazaar_2_Turns_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Over 100,000 users have experienced the power of &lt;strong&gt;OpenBazaar 2.0&lt;/strong&gt; since it launched and it keeps growing bigger and stronger. All of our hard work continues to drive us collectively toward a better future for crypto users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-road-to-here&quot;&gt;The Road to Here&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We knew we were onto something great with version 1.0 of OpenBazaar. We used exciting, emerging technologies to build it but we discovered limits we wanted to push past to get the experience right for our users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development of OpenBazaar 2.0 started many months before its release late last year and took many hours of planning and designing from a large group of team members covering visual design, technical architecture, UX and UI development, community evangelism and marketing strategy.  Some critical decisions were made to improve the experience of OpenBazaar, like &lt;strong&gt;scrapping our fully decentralized search feature&lt;/strong&gt; in favor of using &lt;strong&gt;third party search engines&lt;/strong&gt; (much like how Bittorrent operates), and replacing our shoddy p2p protocol with Protocol Labs’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io/&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://libp2p.io/&quot;&gt;libp2p&lt;/a&gt;. This made our network connectivity improve greatly (though we still have a lot of work to do) and laid the groundwork for getting us to &lt;strong&gt;mobile&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;web&lt;/strong&gt; applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bitcoin-breakdown&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Breakdown&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These changes took a long time to implement and deliver, but the team did so fairly seamlessly &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-20-is-live/&quot;&gt;on November 1st, 2017&lt;/a&gt;. There wasn’t much time to celebrate though as a transaction fee crisis was happening in parallel with a massive uptick in interest in Bitcoin. This sent the team into disarray as we struggled to find users who wanted to pay $30 in fees just to buy something like a $20 t-shirt in the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some consternation we decided the only solution was to expand our payment options to include other currencies to ease the scalability pains felt by our users and so in &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2-1-released-bitcoin-cash-and-zcash-integrated/&quot;&gt;January&lt;/a&gt; we released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash&quot;&gt;ZCash (Beta)&lt;/a&gt; support for OpenBazaar. We are proud that we’ve been able to bring OpenBazaar to a broader community of crypto enthusiasts and are continuing that work today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wonder-whats-next&quot;&gt;Wonder What’s Next?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018 the breadth of crypto projects has increased exponentially through ERC-20 token issuances, completely new blockchains, layer two networks and more. We understand that there is a growing number of people interested in using all kinds of cryptocurrencies — not just Bitcoin — for e-commerce, coin trading, rewarding others for content creation and other use cases. OpenBazaar was always designed as a project for &lt;em&gt;the world&lt;/em&gt;, not just for Bitcoin, and we’re hard at work re-engineering it to support new coins and communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next release will center on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/Freedom-To-Trade-Means-Freedom-To-Choose-Currencies-The-OpenBazaar-Multiwallet/&quot;&gt;multiwallet&lt;/a&gt; which will allow users to send and receive payments from one wallet instance that can hold these five coins: Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, Zcash, Ethereum and Litecoin. We hope to introduce this new capability soon, followed by even more coins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;openbazaar-multiwallet-design.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar Multiwallet design&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar Multiwallet design for Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, Zcash, Ethereum and Litecoin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Want to see more? Click &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.invisionapp.com/share/5XMZC8DT8HM#/screens/308962050_Openbazaar-2-0-Wallet&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for an interactive demo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OB1 is also bringing OpenBazaar to mobile with &lt;strong&gt;our own iOS and Android apps&lt;/strong&gt;. We’re pioneering the technology to make a truly decentralized web version of OpenBazaar so that anyone can run it in their own standard browser. It’s an extremely bright future and every day thousands of new people are learning about the power of Bitcoin, Ethereum and other crypto projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are even more exciting developments on the horizon beyond these ambitious releases that I can’t wait to share with you. Please sign up for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/newsletter/&quot;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to learn about them as they are announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;openbazaar-2-turns-1&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month we are celebrating one year since the release of OpenBazaar 2.0 with promotions and events all month long. Connect with us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/openbazaarproject&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; to learn more and follow along on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; with the hashtag &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?src=typd&amp;amp;q=%23OB2Turns1&quot;&gt;#OB2Turns1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day we use technologies that make our lives easier, but at the expense of our &lt;strong&gt;privacy&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;security&lt;/strong&gt;. We’re working on this freedom-focused project to give individuals another choice for how they buy, sell and share their information online, one that respects these values we share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This movement is about taking control of the future we want to see for ourselves and our neighbors all around the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to keep working with you on this project and to help it grow together. We can only do it with your support so please spread the word and help us make OpenBazaar even better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Brian Hoffman, CEO, OB1</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why We Are Integrating Ethereum into OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/why-we-are-integrating-ethereum-into-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why We Are Integrating &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Ethereum&lt;/span&gt; into OpenBazaar" /><published>2018-10-31T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-31T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/why-we-are-integrating-ethereum-into-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/why-we-are-integrating-ethereum-into-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;In a previous article we explained &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/Escrow-Smart-Contract-Specification-in-OpenBazaar/&quot;&gt;how we’re integrating Ethereum into OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt; in addition to Bitcoin, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash/&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt;. In this article we want to talk about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; we’re integrating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ethereum.org/&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bitcoin-beginnings&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Beginnings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar began as a Bitcoin-only project, with the intent of creating an open, permissionless marketplace with no fees and no middlemen. From the beginning users wanted the ability to accept payments in cryptocurrencies other than bitcoin. While that was possible via our &lt;a href=&quot;https://shapeshift.io/&quot;&gt;Shapeshift&lt;/a&gt; integration, such payments weren’t really trustless. Non-bitcoin payments would just be Shapeshifted into bitcoin payments. Users effectively had to use Shapeshift as a middleman, had to trust them not to steal their funds, and had to pay them for the privilege. In that sense, non-bitcoin payments weren’t really &lt;em&gt;native&lt;/em&gt; to OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, in late 2017, bitcoin transaction fees began to rise. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitinfocharts.com/comparison/bitcoin-transactionfees.htm&quot;&gt;A lot&lt;/a&gt;. Using bitcoin for payments on OpenBazaar became impractical for months. Since payments in non-bitcoin currencies weren’t native on OpenBazaar (they were simply Shapefshifted into bitcoin payments) that meant &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; payments on OpenBazaar were impractical. Users wanted to use alternative currencies, but we were – effectively – forcing them to use bitcoin. Use of the platform ground to a halt. It was obvious something needed to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;becoming-crypto-inclusive&quot;&gt;Becoming Crypto-Inclusive&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want users to be able to trade using &lt;strong&gt;any cryptocurrency they desire&lt;/strong&gt;, without exposure to risks caused by other chains. In early 2018, in response to urgent demand from our users, we began integrating native altcoin payments into OpenBazaar. We’re refactoring our codebase to make it much easier to integrate new cryptocurrencies natively. The low hanging fruits are coins that are forks of Bitcoin, as their codebases are closest to what OpenBazaar was already supporting. Bitcoin Cash and Zcash were the first such integrations, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://litecoin.org/&quot;&gt;Litecoin&lt;/a&gt; integration is almost complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;enter-ethereum&quot;&gt;Enter Ethereum&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A natural continuation of that effort is to integrate Ethereum. Since Ethereum doesn’t share Bitcoin’s codebase, it has been more challenging to integrate than forks of Bitcoin. But we think it’s worth the effort because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ethereum has the largest community outside of Bitcoin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developer activity on Ethereum is huge and enthusiastic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The community has a special eagerness for its coin and tokens to be used for real-world commerce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrating &lt;strong&gt;ETH&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;ERC20 payments&lt;/strong&gt; is a natural next-step for OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond simple payments, &lt;strong&gt;smart contracts&lt;/strong&gt; built on Ethereum – with its rich Turing-complete scripting language – may allow us to support markets that would be extremely challenging to support with Bitcoin-like script-based cryptocurrencies. Trustless auctions, DAO-based stores, insurance contracts, and affiliate marketing are just a few of the ideas we are exploring. Integrating Ethereum has the potential to expand the types of products and services offered on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users won’t be required to use Ethereum to use OpenBazaar, and can still stick to paying and being paid in Bitcoin or other supported cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-summary&quot;&gt;In Summary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, the landscape isn’t what it was when OpenBazaar first started. There is a rich ecosystem we cannot afford to ignore, and Ethereum is a huge part of that. We’re excited about implementing ETH and ERC20 payments, and are looking forward to working with the Ethereum community as we explore how we can leverage smart contracts in OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In a previous article we explained how we’re integrating Ethereum into OpenBazaar in addition to Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash and Zcash. In this article we want to talk about why we’re integrating Ethereum.</summary></entry></feed>