<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://openbazaar.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://openbazaar.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-14T03:06:04+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">OpenBazaar</title><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar Developer Call - November 8, 2018</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-November-8-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar Developer Call - November 8, 2018" /><published>2018-11-13T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-13T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-November-8-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-November-8-2018/">&lt;p&gt;This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on November 8, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to join the call in real time? Sign up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/developers&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our ongoing conversations on Slack at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse OpenBazaar now at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OlgcS_k_Oa0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chat log:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[09:59] mg: Hi kornilov. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:00] mg: Heard you learned how to feed chickens over the internet with magic internet money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:00] kornilov: Hi developers and Jenn. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:02] kornilov: Yes, I have learned to make ethereum testnet token - korncoin ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:02] mg: I was unaware of that! I was talking about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/redpepper261&quot;&gt;BCH chicken feeder/webcam&lt;/a&gt;. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:04] kornilov: Oh, that is supposed to be a secret project available only for NSA. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:04] mg: Haha… I’ll make sure to keep my lips sealed. :X&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:10] joshj: One minor clarification, ETH uses Infura, not Insight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:19] chris.troutner: 18!? That’s fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:20] Rod: Is there a general timeline/estimate for when 2.3 will be released?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:22] kornilov: How many fulltime employed developers OB has?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:22] kornilov: very nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:23] Rod: Have there been any updates for downloading offline messages quicker in the current client?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:23] Rod: I have done some prototypes for putting together OB features in the browser and the amount of time it takes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:26] chris.troutner: Sorry about that. My connection is sketchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:26] Rod: I did some testing with doing full IPNS crawl on a shorter interval and did not see any significant increase in resources used. Do you know if there is a specific reason the crawl speed is at the current speed it is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:26] Rod: I can follow up on slack later if needed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:27] chris.troutner: I just wanted to say congrats on the Hacktoberfest results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:28] Rod: Alright thank you Chris&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:28] chris.troutner: If OB wants to investigate BCH token integration (Wormhole or SLP), perhaps we could use it as an opportunity to incentivize community developers through swag and bounties, like gitcash.io or Gitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on November 8, 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Will The BCH Hard Fork Affect OpenBazaar?</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-will-the-bch-hard-fork-on-nov-15-affect-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Will The &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;BCH Hard Fork&lt;/span&gt; Affect OpenBazaar?" /><published>2018-11-12T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-12T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-will-the-bch-hard-fork-on-nov-15-affect-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-will-the-bch-hard-fork-on-nov-15-affect-openbazaar/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-happening-with-bitcoin-cash&quot;&gt;What’s Happening with Bitcoin Cash?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt; network upgrade beginning at 4:40PM UTC on November 15th, 2018. Depending on how the upgrade is accepted by the network, the Bitcoin Cash blockchain could fork into two or more incompatible chains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that transacting is dangerous during a hard fork like this unless it’s between addresses you entirely control. If you transact BCH to an address you don’t control you could lose access to your coins on other forks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to help OpenBazaar users prepare for the hard fork, here is some information about the OpenBazaar wallet that can help you decide how to handle any BCH you may have stored there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-will-the-bitcoin-cash-upgrade-affect-my-openbazaar-funds&quot;&gt;How Will The Bitcoin Cash Upgrade Affect My OpenBazaar Funds?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users of &lt;strong&gt;OpenBazaar 2.2.5 and prior&lt;/strong&gt; who have an active BCH wallet are using a local SPV-based wallet. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/en/glossary/simplified-payment-verification&quot;&gt;SPV wallets&lt;/a&gt; are designed to follow the chain that has the most cumulative proof-of-work according to the existing Bitcoin Cash difficulty rules. The SPV wallet in OpenBazaar will follow the longest chain served by the peers it’s able to connect to. We advise that you withdraw your BCH from your OpenBazaar wallet until the chains settle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;withdraw-your-bch-to-electron&quot;&gt;Withdraw Your BCH to Electron&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Users of an OpenBazaar wallet control their funds by having sole access to their keys. The wallet maintains its keys and seed locally on your computer which you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/115002892791-How-do-I-backup-my-OpenBazaar-wallet-&quot;&gt;backup to a safe location using these steps&lt;/a&gt;. Then, import your seed into a &lt;strong&gt;BIP39-compatible wallet&lt;/strong&gt; (such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://electroncash.org/&quot;&gt;Electron Cash&lt;/a&gt; ) to keep your funds safe through the fork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io&quot;&gt;OB1&lt;/a&gt; team will continue to observe the network upgrade and will take further actions as necessary to ensure the safety of our users’ funds at rest within the OpenBazaar wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-should-i-do-next&quot;&gt;What Should I Do Next?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next few weeks, make sure you have the keys to your OpenBazaar wallet stored somewhere safe as complications may arise. When things settle it is entirely your choice what you do with your coins, but we also recommend being cautious of a chain with hash power of 50% or more controlled by one entity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is a private, open-source marketplace powered by cryptocurrency that is making trade free for everyone, everywhere. The development team at OB1 is committed to building a secure and reliable transactional environment for users around the world. We do our best to ensure that you have the knowledge you need to make the best decisions for you and your coins. If you have questions please join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; to chat with our development team and active community.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What’s Happening with Bitcoin Cash?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Shop OpenBazaar - Pascal Boyart, DropShip IO and Boston Zcash Users Group</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/shop-openbazaar-pascal-boyart-dropship-io-boston-zcash-users-group/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shop OpenBazaar - &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Pascal Boyart, DropShip IO and Boston Zcash Users Group&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-11-11T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-11T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/shop-openbazaar-pascal-boyart-dropship-io-boston-zcash-users-group</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/shop-openbazaar-pascal-boyart-dropship-io-boston-zcash-users-group/">&lt;p&gt;Bring your cryptocoins and digital currency to OpenBazaar to shop, sell or trade with people from around the world. This is a bitcoin marketplace that expanded to become a &lt;em&gt;cryptocurrency&lt;/em&gt; marketplace where you can buy and sell what you want — &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; pay how you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out these stores featuring each of the different payment coins now available on OpenBazaar: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash/&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are 3 great stores for you to shop at today:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;pascal-boyart&quot;&gt;Pascal Boyart&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bitcoin (BTC)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Pascal_Boyart_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pascal Boyart on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Pascal Boyart on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmYTXDyMNjdUSvqNc88T2VeVF3KdG7PMefnGQKrp9NZ5Tp&quot;&gt;Pascal Boyart on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Pascal Boyart is an accomplished fine artist based in Paris. He began as a graffiti artist but now produces a wide range of art styles. Many of the pieces he has featured on OpenBazaar focus on cryptocurrency and crypto-culture. Read more of his amazing story on his &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/home/QmYTXDyMNjdUSvqNc88T2VeVF3KdG7PMefnGQKrp9NZ5Tp&quot;&gt;About page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BONUS:&lt;/strong&gt; For a limited time he’s offering &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/OpenBazaar/comments/9vm6ou/weekly_spotlight_share_your_openbazaar_stores/e9f00mz/&quot;&gt;a 10% reduction&lt;/a&gt; on the limited edition prints Crypto Anarchist Manifesto and WhitePaper French version. Use coupon code: BTCARTREVOLUTION
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dropship-io&quot;&gt;DropShip I/O&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bitcoin Cash (BCH)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;DropShip_IO_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;DropShip I/O on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;DropShip I/O on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmY1jBtr54t2T929RuDt24MLRFxjacQzHVmz5z8yxzVg3P&quot;&gt;DropShip I/O on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ever wish you could just buy things from Amazon using Bitcoin Cash? This OpenBazaar store makes that possible and even sweetens the deal with a discount to promote the use of cryptocurrencies worldwide. Learn more &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/home/QmY1jBtr54t2T929RuDt24MLRFxjacQzHVmz5z8yxzVg3P&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;boston-zcash-users-group&quot;&gt;Boston Zcash Users Group&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zcash (ZEC)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Boston_Zcash_Users_Group_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Boston Zcash Users Group on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Boston Zcash Users Group on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmYs2Hc2b2dMWPw1qbrYWS5zCRRjWzgUu3XAPWP239SNGp&quot;&gt;Boston Zcash Users Group on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Boston Zcash Users Group is putting their principles into action by giving Zcash fans and users a practical way to use their favorite coin. Check out the list of books, stickers and coins they have available for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;like-what-you-see&quot;&gt;Like what you see?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shop these stores and so many more on the brand new browsing website, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Bring your cryptocoins and digital currency to OpenBazaar to shop, sell or trade with people from around the world. This is a bitcoin marketplace that expanded to become a cryptocurrency marketplace where you can buy and sell what you want — and pay how you want.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Change, Hard Work and Strong Growth—OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/big-change-hard-work-and-strong-growth-openbazaar-2-turns-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Change, Hard Work and Strong Growth—&lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-11-07T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-07T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/big-change-hard-work-and-strong-growth-openbazaar-2-turns-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/big-change-hard-work-and-strong-growth-openbazaar-2-turns-1/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by Brian Hoffman, CEO, OB1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The years leading up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-20-is-live/&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar 2.0&lt;/a&gt; went by in a flash, it seems, culminating in our best and most capable software release ever this month last year. Since then it’s been a whirlwind of development milestones, bug fixes, crypto political drama, and flying all over the world to promote the benefits of private, free trade for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;OpenBazaar_2_Turns_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Over 100,000 users have experienced the power of &lt;strong&gt;OpenBazaar 2.0&lt;/strong&gt; since it launched and it keeps growing bigger and stronger. All of our hard work continues to drive us collectively toward a better future for crypto users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-road-to-here&quot;&gt;The Road to Here&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We knew we were onto something great with version 1.0 of OpenBazaar. We used exciting, emerging technologies to build it but we discovered limits we wanted to push past to get the experience right for our users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development of OpenBazaar 2.0 started many months before its release late last year and took many hours of planning and designing from a large group of team members covering visual design, technical architecture, UX and UI development, community evangelism and marketing strategy.  Some critical decisions were made to improve the experience of OpenBazaar, like &lt;strong&gt;scrapping our fully decentralized search feature&lt;/strong&gt; in favor of using &lt;strong&gt;third party search engines&lt;/strong&gt; (much like how Bittorrent operates), and replacing our shoddy p2p protocol with Protocol Labs’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io/&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://libp2p.io/&quot;&gt;libp2p&lt;/a&gt;. This made our network connectivity improve greatly (though we still have a lot of work to do) and laid the groundwork for getting us to &lt;strong&gt;mobile&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;web&lt;/strong&gt; applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bitcoin-breakdown&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Breakdown&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These changes took a long time to implement and deliver, but the team did so fairly seamlessly &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-20-is-live/&quot;&gt;on November 1st, 2017&lt;/a&gt;. There wasn’t much time to celebrate though as a transaction fee crisis was happening in parallel with a massive uptick in interest in Bitcoin. This sent the team into disarray as we struggled to find users who wanted to pay $30 in fees just to buy something like a $20 t-shirt in the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some consternation we decided the only solution was to expand our payment options to include other currencies to ease the scalability pains felt by our users and so in &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/openbazaar-2-1-released-bitcoin-cash-and-zcash-integrated/&quot;&gt;January&lt;/a&gt; we released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash&quot;&gt;ZCash (Beta)&lt;/a&gt; support for OpenBazaar. We are proud that we’ve been able to bring OpenBazaar to a broader community of crypto enthusiasts and are continuing that work today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wonder-whats-next&quot;&gt;Wonder What’s Next?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018 the breadth of crypto projects has increased exponentially through ERC-20 token issuances, completely new blockchains, layer two networks and more. We understand that there is a growing number of people interested in using all kinds of cryptocurrencies — not just Bitcoin — for e-commerce, coin trading, rewarding others for content creation and other use cases. OpenBazaar was always designed as a project for &lt;em&gt;the world&lt;/em&gt;, not just for Bitcoin, and we’re hard at work re-engineering it to support new coins and communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next release will center on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/Freedom-To-Trade-Means-Freedom-To-Choose-Currencies-The-OpenBazaar-Multiwallet/&quot;&gt;multiwallet&lt;/a&gt; which will allow users to send and receive payments from one wallet instance that can hold these five coins: Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, Zcash, Ethereum and Litecoin. We hope to introduce this new capability soon, followed by even more coins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;openbazaar-multiwallet-design.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenBazaar Multiwallet design&quot; title=&quot;OpenBazaar Multiwallet design for Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, Zcash, Ethereum and Litecoin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Want to see more? Click &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.invisionapp.com/share/5XMZC8DT8HM#/screens/308962050_Openbazaar-2-0-Wallet&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for an interactive demo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OB1 is also bringing OpenBazaar to mobile with &lt;strong&gt;our own iOS and Android apps&lt;/strong&gt;. We’re pioneering the technology to make a truly decentralized web version of OpenBazaar so that anyone can run it in their own standard browser. It’s an extremely bright future and every day thousands of new people are learning about the power of Bitcoin, Ethereum and other crypto projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are even more exciting developments on the horizon beyond these ambitious releases that I can’t wait to share with you. Please sign up for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/newsletter/&quot;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to learn about them as they are announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;openbazaar-2-turns-1&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar 2 Turns 1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month we are celebrating one year since the release of OpenBazaar 2.0 with promotions and events all month long. Connect with us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/openbazaarproject&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; to learn more and follow along on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openbazaar&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; with the hashtag &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?src=typd&amp;amp;q=%23OB2Turns1&quot;&gt;#OB2Turns1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day we use technologies that make our lives easier, but at the expense of our &lt;strong&gt;privacy&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;security&lt;/strong&gt;. We’re working on this freedom-focused project to give individuals another choice for how they buy, sell and share their information online, one that respects these values we share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This movement is about taking control of the future we want to see for ourselves and our neighbors all around the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to keep working with you on this project and to help it grow together. We can only do it with your support so please spread the word and help us make OpenBazaar even better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">by Brian Hoffman, CEO, OB1</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why We Are Integrating Ethereum into OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/why-we-are-integrating-ethereum-into-openbazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why We Are Integrating &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Ethereum&lt;/span&gt; into OpenBazaar" /><published>2018-10-31T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-31T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/why-we-are-integrating-ethereum-into-openbazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/why-we-are-integrating-ethereum-into-openbazaar/">&lt;p&gt;In a previous article we explained &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/Escrow-Smart-Contract-Specification-in-OpenBazaar/&quot;&gt;how we’re integrating Ethereum into OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt; in addition to Bitcoin, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash/&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt;. In this article we want to talk about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; we’re integrating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ethereum.org/&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bitcoin-beginnings&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Beginnings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar began as a Bitcoin-only project, with the intent of creating an open, permissionless marketplace with no fees and no middlemen. From the beginning users wanted the ability to accept payments in cryptocurrencies other than bitcoin. While that was possible via our &lt;a href=&quot;https://shapeshift.io/&quot;&gt;Shapeshift&lt;/a&gt; integration, such payments weren’t really trustless. Non-bitcoin payments would just be Shapeshifted into bitcoin payments. Users effectively had to use Shapeshift as a middleman, had to trust them not to steal their funds, and had to pay them for the privilege. In that sense, non-bitcoin payments weren’t really &lt;em&gt;native&lt;/em&gt; to OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, in late 2017, bitcoin transaction fees began to rise. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitinfocharts.com/comparison/bitcoin-transactionfees.htm&quot;&gt;A lot&lt;/a&gt;. Using bitcoin for payments on OpenBazaar became impractical for months. Since payments in non-bitcoin currencies weren’t native on OpenBazaar (they were simply Shapefshifted into bitcoin payments) that meant &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; payments on OpenBazaar were impractical. Users wanted to use alternative currencies, but we were – effectively – forcing them to use bitcoin. Use of the platform ground to a halt. It was obvious something needed to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;becoming-crypto-inclusive&quot;&gt;Becoming Crypto-Inclusive&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want users to be able to trade using &lt;strong&gt;any cryptocurrency they desire&lt;/strong&gt;, without exposure to risks caused by other chains. In early 2018, in response to urgent demand from our users, we began integrating native altcoin payments into OpenBazaar. We’re refactoring our codebase to make it much easier to integrate new cryptocurrencies natively. The low hanging fruits are coins that are forks of Bitcoin, as their codebases are closest to what OpenBazaar was already supporting. Bitcoin Cash and Zcash were the first such integrations, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://litecoin.org/&quot;&gt;Litecoin&lt;/a&gt; integration is almost complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;enter-ethereum&quot;&gt;Enter Ethereum&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A natural continuation of that effort is to integrate Ethereum. Since Ethereum doesn’t share Bitcoin’s codebase, it has been more challenging to integrate than forks of Bitcoin. But we think it’s worth the effort because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ethereum has the largest community outside of Bitcoin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developer activity on Ethereum is huge and enthusiastic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The community has a special eagerness for its coin and tokens to be used for real-world commerce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrating &lt;strong&gt;ETH&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;ERC20 payments&lt;/strong&gt; is a natural next-step for OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond simple payments, &lt;strong&gt;smart contracts&lt;/strong&gt; built on Ethereum – with its rich Turing-complete scripting language – may allow us to support markets that would be extremely challenging to support with Bitcoin-like script-based cryptocurrencies. Trustless auctions, DAO-based stores, insurance contracts, and affiliate marketing are just a few of the ideas we are exploring. Integrating Ethereum has the potential to expand the types of products and services offered on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users won’t be required to use Ethereum to use OpenBazaar, and can still stick to paying and being paid in Bitcoin or other supported cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-summary&quot;&gt;In Summary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, the landscape isn’t what it was when OpenBazaar first started. There is a rich ecosystem we cannot afford to ignore, and Ethereum is a huge part of that. We’re excited about implementing ETH and ERC20 payments, and are looking forward to working with the Ethereum community as we explore how we can leverage smart contracts in OpenBazaar.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In a previous article we explained how we’re integrating Ethereum into OpenBazaar in addition to Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash and Zcash. In this article we want to talk about why we’re integrating Ethereum.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Shop OpenBazaar - Satoshi Doodles, CryptoCollectibles and Matthew Zipkin</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Shop-OpenBazaar-Satoshi-Doodles-CryptoCollectibles-and-Matthew-Zipkin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shop OpenBazaar - &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Satoshi Doodles, CryptoCollectibles and Matthew Zipkin&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-10-29T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-29T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/Shop-OpenBazaar-Satoshi-Doodles-CryptoCollectibles-and-Matthew-Zipkin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Shop-OpenBazaar-Satoshi-Doodles-CryptoCollectibles-and-Matthew-Zipkin/">&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar is the perfect place to put your &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash/&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt; to work. It’s like a bitcoin Ebay alternative for digital currency enthusiasts who are looking for a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can buy all &lt;em&gt;kinds&lt;/em&gt; of things with cryptocurrency on OpenBazaar! It’s an open source marketplace where you can buy (and/or sell!) what you want and &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; are in control—not some centralized network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are 3 great stores for you to shop at today:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;satoshi-doodles&quot;&gt;Satoshi Doodles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Satoshi_Doodles_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Satoshi Doodles on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Satoshi Doodles on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmXFvx9Hjw2EDcNECRQXpSybKVdZRLEHjC4CnJFr6bCCfh&quot;&gt;Satoshi Doodles on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Satoshi Doodles is a brand new store on OpenBazaar and we think it’s a perfect fit. Check out these cute and often hilarious art prints available for BCH.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;cryptocollectibles&quot;&gt;CryptoCollectibles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;CryptoCollectibles_comic_books_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;CryptoCollectibles Comic Books on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;CryptoCollectibles Comic Books on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmakxNv9Y5YFuAuvjvx4mEda3TmFBaHDtacd1KtEL56mP4&quot;&gt;CryptoCollectibles on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
CryptoCollectibles has been a constant and consistent presence on OpenBazaar since way back in version 1.0. We’re glad to have their &lt;em&gt;extensive&lt;/em&gt; selection of premium comic books available to purchase for BTC on OpenBazaar!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;matthew-zipkin&quot;&gt;Matthew Zipkin&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Matthew_Zipkin_Bitcoin_Clocks_and_CryptoCuddlies_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Matthew Zipkin Bitcoin Clocks and CryptoCuddlies on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Matthew Zipkin Bitcoin Clocks and CryptoCuddlies on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmeSyTRaNZMD8ajcfbhC8eYibWgnSZtSGUp3Vn59bCnPWC&quot;&gt;Matthew Zipkin on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Matthew Zipkin is another longtime friend to the OpenBazaar community and he has some neat, practical art pieces available in his store. Another fun fact, Matthew is also an &lt;a href=&quot;https://ob1.io/verified-moderators.html&quot;&gt;OB1 Verified Moderator&lt;/a&gt; who is available for you to add to your transactions and provide assistance in case of a dispute. Send him a message and say hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;like-what-you-see&quot;&gt;Like what you see?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shop these stores and so many more on the brand new browsing website, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OpenBazaar is the perfect place to put your Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, or Zcash to work. It’s like a bitcoin Ebay alternative for digital currency enthusiasts who are looking for a change.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Escrow Smart Contract Specification in OpenBazaar</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Escrow-Smart-Contract-Specification-in-OpenBazaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Escrow Smart Contract Specification&lt;/span&gt; in OpenBazaar" /><published>2018-10-24T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/Escrow-Smart-Contract-Specification-in-OpenBazaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Escrow-Smart-Contract-Specification-in-OpenBazaar/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Austin Williams, OpenBazaar Researcher&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integration of Ethereum into OpenBazaar represents one of the most challenging and rewarding tasks we’ve done for the project so far. We are so excited to bring our vision of seeing cryptocurrency and tokens used for real-world commerce to the Ethereum community!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Welcome to the family! Look forward to seeing what you and openbazaar come up with&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Vitalik Non-giver of Ether (@VitalikButerin) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/987001278764118018?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt; facilitates trades between arbitrary third parties on the internet. Currently, only UTXO-based cryptocurrencies can be used as a medium of exchange on OpenBazaar. The escrow contract is intended to be used as a way to shoehorn Ethereum functionality into OpenBazaar’s existing framework so that users can trade using ETH and ERC20 tokens as their medium of exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-openbazaar-trades-currently-work-in-utxo-land&quot;&gt;How OpenBazaar Trades Currently Work (in UTXO land)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;moderated-payments&quot;&gt;Moderated Payments&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a buyer and seller have agreed on a product and a price, the buyer sends their funds to an escrow address, which is a 2-of-3 multisig address with one key controlled by the buyer, one key controlled by the seller, and one key controlled by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/blog/how-to-choose-a-good-moderator-on-openbazaar&quot;&gt;moderator&lt;/a&gt; that has been agreed upon by both the buyer and the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the “happy path”, the seller delivers the goods, then the buyer releases the funds to the seller (with the buyer and seller signing the payout transaction from the escrow address).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the event that the seller does not deliver the goods as promised, the buyer pleads their case to the moderator, and the buyer &amp;amp; moderator can send the funds from escrow back to the buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the (very common) case where the buyer receives their goods but doesn’t release the funds to the seller, the seller presents their case to the moderator, and the seller &amp;amp; moderator sign the funds from escrow to the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seller can also unilaterally release funds from escrow after a previously agreed upon amount of time has passed. This allows the seller to release the funds from escrow without the moderator in the event that the buyer disappears. With UTXO-based coins, this is achieved by requiring that the buyer sign an nLockTime transaction releasing funds to the seller, and then passing that transaction to the seller (off-chain) before the seller delivers the product or service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;direct-payments&quot;&gt;Direct Payments&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers have the option of &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; using a moderator when making an OpenBazaar trade. While this isn’t recommended, it may be an acceptable risk for the buyer if the buyer trusts the seller. Direct or unmoderated payments come in two forms: online payments and offline payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online direct payments&lt;/strong&gt; occur when the buyer knows the seller is online. For online payments, the buyer simply sends the funds directly to the seller’s wallet after requesting an address to pay to. These are simple, classic transfers of value from one account to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offline payments&lt;/strong&gt; occur when the buyer sees that the seller is offline and is &lt;em&gt;uncertain&lt;/em&gt; whether the seller will ever come back online. In this case the buyer sends the funds to a 1-of-2 multisig address with one key held by the buyer and the other held by the seller. If the seller comes back online, they can accept the funds. If the seller doesn’t come back online, the buyer can reclaim the funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limitations Imposed by OpenBazaar’s Wallet Interface&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar interacts with all supported coins through its &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/wallet-interface/blob/master/wallet.go#L77&quot;&gt;wallet interface&lt;/a&gt;. This means that OpenBazaar’s Ethereum smart contracts must be designed in such a way as to be compatible with that interface. OpenBazaar is a live/launched product, so making big changes to the wallet interface in order to support Ethereum is non-trivial. Instead, we’ve decided to keep the wallet interface fixed (for now), and design the smart contract to be compatible with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;intended-use-of-the-escrow-contract&quot;&gt;Intended Use of the Escrow contract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Escrow contract will store the escrowed funds and state information for &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; OpenBazaar trade that is using Ethereum (or ERC20 tokens) as the medium of exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could have, instead, opted to deploy a new escrow contract for each Ethereum-based trade — thereby siloing escrowed funds from each trade in their own smart contract. However, we think the gas requirements for doing so are cost prohibitive, and we fear that would introduce too much friction into Ethereum-based trades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenBazaar trades that use ETH/ERC20 as the medium of exchange are intended to follow the same protocol as those that use a UTXO-based coin as the medium of exchange — and the escrow smart contract is intended to facilitate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;funding-the-trade&quot;&gt;Funding the Trade&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers initiate a trade by creating/storing a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Transaction&lt;/code&gt; struct in the Escrow contract and (simultaneously) funding the transaction by sending ETH (or ERC20 tokens) to the Escrow contract. At this point the transaction is in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FUNDED&lt;/code&gt; state. While in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FUNDED&lt;/code&gt; state, the buyer may add more ETH (or ERC20 tokens) to escrow if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;releasing-funds-from-escrow&quot;&gt;Releasing Funds from Escrow&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the transaction is in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FUNDED&lt;/code&gt; state, the escrowed funds can be released only if:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two of the three participants (buyer, seller, and moderator) agree on how the escrowed funds are to be distributed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An amount of time (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;timeoutHourse&lt;/code&gt;) has passed since the last time the buyer added funds to escrow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasoning behind (2) is that it is very common for buyers to not release funds after they’ve received their goods (this is due more to buyer laziness than malice). In that event, we want to make it easy for the seller to claim the escrowed funds without having to coordinate with a moderator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funds released from escrow can be split up and sent to various addresses. However, the receiving addresses &lt;em&gt;must be&lt;/em&gt; the addresses of the trade’s buyer, seller, or moderator. To reiterate, funds cannot be sent to an address that is not affiliated with the trade in question, but the escrowed funds can be divided up among the participants in any way — so long as 2-of-3 of the parties agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon release of funds from escrow, the trade is put into the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;RELEASED&lt;/code&gt; state. Once in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;RELEASED&lt;/code&gt; state, trades can no longer be altered. All participants who received some of the escrowed funds are noted in the trade’s Transaction struct (via the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;beneficiaries&lt;/code&gt; mapping).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;beneficiaries&lt;/code&gt; information will be used later, by other contracts, to determine whether or not a given trade was disputed, refunded, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;offline-direct-payments&quot;&gt;Offline Direct Payments&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The escrow contract can mirror the behavior of UTXO-based offline payments by calling &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;addTransaction&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;addTokenTransaction&lt;/code&gt; if it is an ERC20 transaction), setting the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;threshold&lt;/code&gt; value to 1, and setting the moderator address to a known, non-zero burn address. The effect is the equivalent of a 1-of-2 multisig address where the buyer holds one key and the seller holds the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;known-issues--misc&quot;&gt;Known Issues / Misc&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;moderator-selection&quot;&gt;Moderator selection&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is assumed that the moderator is &lt;em&gt;trusted&lt;/em&gt; by both the buyer and the seller before the trade begins. The obvious threat of collusion between a buyer and moderator — or seller and moderator — is beyond the scope of this contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;push-vs-pull&quot;&gt;Push vs pull&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;transferFunds&lt;/code&gt; function uses push payments (rather than the pull model) due to limitations imposed by OpenBazaar’s wallet interface. Hence any of the beneficiaries of a payout from escrow can cause the payout to fail (for example, by putting a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;revert()&lt;/code&gt; in their fallback function).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game theoretically speaking, such a DoS attack is irrational for any of the participants capable of causing such an issue, because the honest parties can always benefit by removing the offending party as a beneficiary and taking her share of the payout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, suppose the three parties agreed that the moderator would received 5% of the funds, and that the buyer and seller would split the remaining funds. The seller, being unhappy with the result, could cause the payout to fail until she could negotiate a more favorable agreement. However, the buyer &amp;amp; moderator — upon seeing the seller’s misbehavior — could simply agree to remove the seller as a beneficiary — thus removing the seller’s ability to DoS the payout.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason, we consider the DoS possibility caused by use of push payments in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;transferFunds&lt;/code&gt; function to be low risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;quality-assurance&quot;&gt;Quality assurance&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code for the escrow smart contract can be found in Github &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/smart-contracts/blob/master/contracts/escrow/Escrow_v1_0.sol&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We invite the community to examine the code and post issues or suggestions. Furthermore, we have written 37 tests for the contract to achieve &amp;gt;90% code coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;audit&quot;&gt;Audit&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://openzeppelin.org/&quot;&gt;OpenZeppelin&lt;/a&gt; to have the contracts audited and hope to have the audit process completed before the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special thanks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to extend a special thanks to the following folks who helped us get here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Andrey 🦃 Petrov&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ashwin Mangale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sameep Singhania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Austin Williams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chris Pacia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openzeppelin.org/&quot;&gt;OpenZeppelin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">By Austin Williams, OpenBazaar Researcher</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hacktoberfest with OpenBazaar: Help Make Trade Free, Get Rewards</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Hacktoberfest-with-OpenBazaar-Help-Make-Trade-Free-Get-Rewards/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/span&gt; with OpenBazaar: &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Help Make Trade Free,&lt;/span&gt; Get Rewards" /><published>2018-10-17T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-17T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/Hacktoberfest-with-OpenBazaar-Help-Make-Trade-Free-Get-Rewards</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Hacktoberfest-with-OpenBazaar-Help-Make-Trade-Free-Get-Rewards/">&lt;p&gt;We believe collaboration and individual empowerment are important which is why we love digital currencies like Bitcoin, and why we built OpenBazaar as an open source marketplace. We support events that bring together people from all around the world to encourage them to create and we’re excited about participating in &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/details&quot;&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/a&gt; this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Hacktoberfest_2018_poster1_1600x850.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hacktoberfest with OpenBazaar: Help Make Trade Free, Get Rewards&quot; title=&quot;Hacktoberfest with OpenBazaar: Help Make Trade Free, Get Rewards&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the month of October people around the world are working to motivate each other to contribute to open source projects. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/details&quot;&gt;register your Github account&lt;/a&gt; and commit at least five pull requests to any public project hosted on Github to earn your own limited edition tee commemorating your participation. &lt;strong&gt;Hacktoberfest ends October 31st&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OB1 has &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-go/issues?q=is%3Aopen+is%3Aissue+label%3Ahacktoberfest&quot;&gt;curated a few issues&lt;/a&gt; for OpenBazaar and will be adding more throughout the month. This is an ideal time for new developers to get involved in OpenBazaar and become familiar with the codebase. Don’t wait long! Some of these issues have been snatched up already, and we’re already more than halfway through October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are other ways to contribute to OpenBazaar, including:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offering &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.transifex.com/ob1/openbazaar/&quot;&gt;translations&lt;/a&gt; for one of our 63 supported languages or translate a new language&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assisting with code documentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/meet&quot;&gt;a brand ambassador at a local meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you may not get a Hacktoberfest tee for activities outside of Github, OB1 will hook you up with other sweet OpenBazaar gear including an &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmcUDmZK8PsPYWw5FRHKNZFjszm2K6e68BQSTpnJYUsML7/openbazaar-t-shirt&quot;&gt;OpenBazaar tshirt&lt;/a&gt; for completed work. To find out more, follow the above links to join the project you are interested in and mention &lt;strong&gt;Hacktoberfest swag&lt;/strong&gt; when you contact us. The easiest way to connect is to join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; and let us know who you are and what you’re up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to meet you. Let’s get started!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We believe collaboration and individual empowerment are important which is why we love digital currencies like Bitcoin, and why we built OpenBazaar as an open source marketplace. We support events that bring together people from all around the world to encourage them to create and we’re excited about participating in Hacktoberfest this year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OpenBazaar Developer Call - October 11, 2018</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-October-11-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenBazaar Developer Call - October 11, 2018" /><published>2018-10-15T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-15T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-October-11-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/OpenBazaar-Developer-Call-October-11-2018/">&lt;p&gt;This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on October 11, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to join the call in real time? Sign up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/developers&quot;&gt;openbazaar.org/developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our ongoing conversations on &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.org/slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse OpenBazaar now at &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9 mb-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MOMeiER0Deg&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chat log:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:04] chris.troutner: Hey everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:04] Sam - OB1: Welcome Chris&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:10] chris.troutner: I’ve been doing some work on Insight servers for Bitcoin Cash. I Dockerized Bitpays insight server: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/christroutner/insight-docker&quot;&gt;https://github.com/christroutner/insight-docker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:12] szollo: That’s awesome, I’ll take a look - thanks Chris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:12] 🌪 mg (ob1): +1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:15] 🌪 mg (ob1): Hacktoberfest issues: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-go/issues?g=is%3Aissue_is%3Aopen+label%3Ahacktoberfest&quot;&gt;https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-go/issues?g=is%3Aissue_is%3Aopen+label%3Ahacktoberfest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10:16] 🌪 mg (ob1): Program details: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com&quot;&gt;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a video recording of the OpenBazaar Developer call on October 11, 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Shop OpenBazaar - Casa Store, Crypto Greeting Cards, and Crypto Republic</title><link href="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Shop-OpenBazaar-Casa-Store-Crypto-Greeting-Cards-and-Crypto-Republic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shop OpenBazaar - &lt;span class='post-title-extra'&gt;Casa Store, Crypto Greeting Cards, and Crypto Republic&lt;/span&gt;" /><published>2018-10-12T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-12T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://openbazaar.org/blog/Shop-OpenBazaar-Casa%20Store-Crypto-Greeting-Cards-and-Crypto-Republic</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://openbazaar.org/blog/Shop-OpenBazaar-Casa-Store-Crypto-Greeting-Cards-and-Crypto-Republic/">&lt;p&gt;Want to know what you can buy with Bitcoin? (Or Bitcoin Cash, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://z.cash/&quot;&gt;Zcash&lt;/a&gt;?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All &lt;em&gt;kinds&lt;/em&gt; of things on OpenBazaar! It is a marketplace where you can buy and sell what you want and connect to people all around the world who are using cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are 3 great stores for you to shop at today:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;casa-store&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/Qmd9hFFuueFrSR7YwUuAfirXXJ7ANZAMc5sx4HFxn7mPkc&quot;&gt;Casa Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Casa_Store_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Casa Store on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Casa Store on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/Qmd9hFFuueFrSR7YwUuAfirXXJ7ANZAMc5sx4HFxn7mPkc&quot;&gt;Casa Store on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Casa began as a personal key management system then expanded to help their customers with hardware solutions as well. They are an Authorized Reseller for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ledger.com/&quot;&gt;Ledger&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://trezor.io/&quot;&gt;Trezor&lt;/a&gt; and in September this year they expanded again. They began pre-releases for their brand new &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/Qmd9hFFuueFrSR7YwUuAfirXXJ7ANZAMc5sx4HFxn7mPkc/casa-lightning-node&quot;&gt;Lightning Nodes&lt;/a&gt; and sold out the first two shipment waves in the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;em&gt;lucky you&lt;/em&gt;, it does seem that December shipments are still available on OpenBazaar…
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;crypto-greeting-cards&quot;&gt;Crypto Greeting Cards&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Crypto_Greeting_Cards_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Crypto Greeting Cards on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Crypto Greeting Cards on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmbmytVomWgsBW74QgyPdh17adoPBJeo2g7scihNPAjMmy&quot;&gt;Crypto Greeting Cards on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you are seeking high-quality, cryptocurrency-themed greeting cards for your fellow crypto-enthusiasts, they’ve got you covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want greeting cards that allow you to easily give the gift of cryptocurrency along with practical educational materials, they’ve &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; got you covered!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s what they say about their store:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“After being tired of the stacks of mundane, generic store-brand greeting cards, we set out to pair our passion in cryptocurrency with designs inspired by the community. Each card features a pre-generated cryptocurrency wallet that can be transferred to the recipient. Like cash in an envelope, only better. The goal is to inspire new participants to join the financial revolution!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crypto Greeting Cards are an affordable way to introduce friends, family, and loved ones to cryptocurrency. After redeeming the card, the recipient will learn:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to set up a wallet app&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The difference between public address and private key&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;An introduction to transactions (sweeping funds)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is there any better way to spread cryptocurrency than kind words and a small gift?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think not.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;crypto-republic---bch&quot;&gt;Crypto Republic - BCH&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;Crypto_Republic_BCH_Store_on_OpenBazaar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Crypto Republic BCH Store on OpenBazaar&quot; title=&quot;Crypto Republic BCH Store on OpenBazaar&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/QmU5ZSKVz2GhsqE6EmBGVCtrui4YhUXny6rbvsSf5h2xvH&quot;&gt;Crypto Republic - BCH on OpenBazaar&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Spend your Bitcoin Cash on some great items from apparel to video games at Crypto Republic. They have a lot of great information about who they are and what they stand for and how to get around OpenBazaar on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com/store/home/QmU5ZSKVz2GhsqE6EmBGVCtrui4YhUXny6rbvsSf5h2xvH&quot;&gt;About page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like what you see?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out these stores and so many more on the brand new browsing website, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbazaar.com&quot;&gt;openbazaar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Want to know what you can buy with Bitcoin? (Or Bitcoin Cash, or Zcash?)</summary></entry></feed>